<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Career>
  <Key>CLONE</Key>
  <Name>Clone Soldier</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Clone Soldier[h4]
Clone Soldiers' initial training is narrowly focused to deliver the tools they need as soldiers in the Grand Army of the Republic. Due to their accelerated, synthetic growth cycle and rapid training program, they begin with the career skills [B]Athletics, Brawl, Cool, Discipline, Medicine, Ranged (Heavy), Ranged (Light),[b] and [B]Vigilance.[b] A Clone Soldier automatically gains a rank in four of these skills without spending experience. They receive a discount when spending experience points for advancement on any of the eight career skills.

[H4]A CLONE SOLDIER'S ROLE[h4]

Clone Soldiers form the backbone of the Grand Army of the Republic. They serve in practically every battlefield role, fighting as infantry, leading as officers, and flying as pilots, in addition to fulfilling both mundane and esoteric responsibilities. These soldiers share their genetic identity, their origins, and their core training. However, they all have distinct experiences and personal responsibilities. These slight variations are enough to make them recognizable individuals who manage to secure their own niches within the vast army.
[P]The clones' shared traits are a powerful asset to the individual soldiers and the army as a whole. They are universally competent in those areas required for them to be effective soldiers. They have a baseline level of training that is extremely consistent, so that the clones' commanders-including Jedi, career military officers, and other clones-can reliably expect them to perform as planned in the field. Further, the flexibility inherent to their organic makeup grants a significant advantage against their most common opponents: the droids of the Separatist army.
</Description>
  <Source Page="18">Rise of the Separatists</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>ATHL</Key>
    <Key>BRAWL</Key>
    <Key>COOL</Key>
    <Key>DISC</Key>
    <Key>MED</Key>
    <Key>RANGLT</Key>
    <Key>RANGHVY</Key>
    <Key>VIGIL</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <Specializations>
    <Key>CLONEOFF</Key>
    <Key>CLONEPIL</Key>
    <Key>CLONETRO</Key>
  </Specializations>
</Career>