<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Career>
  <Key>COMMANDER</Key>
  <Name>Commander</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Commander [h4]

A Commander's eight career skills are [B]Coercion, Cool, Discipline, Knowledge (Warfare), Leadership, Perception, Ranged (Light),[b] and [B]Vigilance[b]. He automatically gains a rank in four of these skills without spending experience, and gains a discount on increasing them with future experience points.

[P][H4]A COMMANDER'S ROLE[h4]

[P]Individual warriors can act bravely and with resolute determination, accomplishing great things. They can also cause untold havoc without any real achievement, save property damage and loss of life, including their own. A motley mob of people capable of violence is only a threat until a more disciplined force arrives to put it down.

[P]The role of a Commander is to organize, manage, and lead the fighters and other people who serve in a military force so they accomplish truly great things together. He must see the bigger picture, make the hard decisions, and motivate his people to charge into the jaws of death for a greater cause, all while never wasting personnel or resources. Without good Commanders, true victory is impossible for any military.

[P]Whether on the bridge of a capital ship, flying in formation with a squad of starfighters, or standing on a hill shouting encouragement to his troops, the Commander is the true heart and soul of the Alliance military. In his hands lies the key to victory or defeat.</Description>
  <Source Page="70">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  <Custom>CustomItem</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>COERC</Key>
    <Key>COOL</Key>
    <Key>DISC</Key>
    <Key>LEAD</Key>
    <Key>PERC</Key>
    <Key>RANGLT</Key>
    <Key>VIGIL</Key>
    <Key>WARF</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <Specializations>
    <Key>COMMODORE</Key>
    <Key>FIGUREHEAD</Key>
    <Key>FORCEADHERENT</Key>
    <Key>IMPERIALACADEMYCADET</Key>
    <Key>INSTRUCTOR</Key>
    <Key>PADAWANSURVIVOR</Key>
    <Key>PIRATE</Key>
    <Key>RETIREDCLONETROOPER</Key>
    <Key>SHIPCAPTAIN</Key>
    <Key>SQUADLEADER</Key>
    <Key>STRATEGIST</Key>
    <Key>TACTICIAN</Key>
  </Specializations>
</Career>