<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Career>
  <Key>SOLDIER</Key>
  <Name>Soldier</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Soldier[h4]

A Soldier's eight career skills are [B]Athletics, Brawl,  Knowledge (Warfare), Medicine, Melee, Ranged (Light), Ranged (Heavy),[b] and [B]Survival[b]. The Soldier automatically gains a rank in four of these skills without spending experience, and gains a discount on increasing them with future experience points.

[P][H4]A SOLDIER'S ROLE[h4]

[P]Soldiers are the ones who take up arms and face death for a cause, for pay, or sometimes for lack of anything better to do. Fighting is what they know and what they do, and the ones who do it best survive long enough to pass on that knowledge to the green recruits who follow in their bloody footsteps. There is glory and honor to be found serving as a Soldier, yet there is also terror, pain, blood, and brutality. For a Soldier, a boring day is often one of his best days.

[P]Administrators and politicians craft policy, commanders dictate how policy is to be implemented, and Soldiers are the tools of that implementation. Most care little for what the actual policy is: for them, the job is to take out the enemy and stay alive (not necessarily in that order). Some Soldiers are more invested in the causes they are fighting for, motivated by the knowledge that they fight for something worthy.

[P]On the battlefront, behind enemy lines, and across the galaxy, the true heart and soul of the Rebellion is found in the Soldiers who serve beneath its banner. The causes they fight for are justice and freedom from tyranny. The cost of failure is almost certainly death, not only for themselves, but for everyone and everything they love.</Description>
  <Source Page="88">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  <Custom>CustomItem</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>ATHL</Key>
    <Key>BRAWL</Key>
    <Key>MED</Key>
    <Key>MELEE</Key>
    <Key>RANGHVY</Key>
    <Key>RANGLT</Key>
    <Key>SURV</Key>
    <Key>WARF</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <Specializations>
    <Key>COMMANDO</Key>
    <Key>FORCEADHERENT</Key>
    <Key>HEAVY</Key>
    <Key>IMPERIALACADEMYCADET</Key>
    <Key>MEDIC</Key>
    <Key>PADAWANSURVIVOR</Key>
    <Key>PIRATE</Key>
    <Key>RETIREDCLONETROOPER</Key>
    <Key>SHARPSHOOTER</Key>
    <Key>SHIPCAPTAIN</Key>
    <Key>TRAILBLAZER</Key>
    <Key>VANGUARD</Key>
  </Specializations>
</Career>