<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Career>
  <Key>TECHNICIAN</Key>
  <Name>Technician</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Technician[h4]

[P]Technicians are both knowledgeable and handy, and their skills show it: [B]Astrogation, Computers, Coordination, Discipline, Knowledge (Outer Rim), Mechanics, Perception,[b] and [B]Piloting (Planetary)[b]. He automatically gains one rank in four of these skills (of his choosing) without spending experience, and he receives a discount when he spends experience to purchase ranks in any of these skills.

[P][H4]The Technician's Role[h4]

[P]Pretty much anything to do with technology or mechanical devices lies within the Technician's purview. He knows how to operate, maintain, repair, and upgrade just about anything with power or gears. Most Technicians would rather deal with machines and droids than people; the latter are just too unpredictable.
[P]Technicians can be found almost anywhere, at any tier of society or in any location where there's even a few machines. Formality—even cleanliness—tends to fall far outside their daily concerns. They usually smell of some kind of grease, solvent, or other substance that's used on machines, and even their cleanest clothes are seldom free from stains. Even those Technicians that move among the higher echelons come off as rumpled and slouching; it's just not in their nature to put on a professional front. They let their work speak for itself.

[P]Note that Technicians do have a sense of pride, and it resides in the work they perform. If a Technician brings someone a piece of tech that he's not only repaired but upgraded with some very useful modifications, the reaction of the recipient can make or break his entire day.

[P]This is why Technicians tend to gravitate to one another socially, or bond with someone who has an appreciation for machinery. Gadgeteer-oriented Bounty Hunters and Smugglers are most likely to befriend a Technician in a group. This can be a mutually beneficial relationship, considering all of the wonderful things a technically proficient individual can do for someone's gear.

[P]Like Pilots and Doctors, Technicians of almost any specialization will have a relatively easy time finding work in the Outer Rim. Every operation, from small farmsteads to large space stations, has need of those who can keep the tech running. Criminal overlords particularly enjoy having a Technician on their payroll, not only to take care of their many assets, but also to craft the occasional "toy" for them with which to surprise their enemies.</Description>
  <Source Page="86">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
  <Custom>CustomItem</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>ASTRO</Key>
    <Key>COMP</Key>
    <Key>COORD</Key>
    <Key>DISC</Key>
    <Key>MECH</Key>
    <Key>OUT</Key>
    <Key>PERC</Key>
    <Key>PILOTPL</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <Specializations>
    <Key>CYBERTECH</Key>
    <Key>DROIDTECH</Key>
    <Key>FORCEADHERENT</Key>
    <Key>IMPERIALACADEMYCADET</Key>
    <Key>MECHANIC</Key>
    <Key>MODDER</Key>
    <Key>OUTLAW</Key>
    <Key>PADAWANSURVIVOR</Key>
    <Key>PIRATE</Key>
    <Key>RETIREDCLONETROOPER</Key>
    <Key>SHIPCAPTAIN</Key>
    <Key>SLICER</Key>
  </Specializations>
</Career>