<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Hooks xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Hook>
    <Key>HIGH</Key>
    <Name>A Higher Calling</Name>
    <Description>[H4]A Higher Calling[h4]
Even in the rough-and-tumble world of [B]Edge of the Empire[b], there are those who strive to change the galaxy - often for the better, but sometimes for the worse. Perhaps the character has made a vow to help others, which works nicely into the Oath Obligation. A character may receive some sort of sign that tells him to leave behind his former life and make his way to the fringes of the galaxy to serve this higher calling.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source>Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>FLAW</Key>
    <Name>A Failure of Character</Name>
    <Description>[H4]A Failure of Character[h4]
Some inherent flaw in the character causes him to leave behind the life he knew for the unknown. This background hook ties in well with some Obligations such as Addiction, Obsession, or Betrayal. Regardless of the cause, the character finds himself shut out from his former society, left to deal with his own problems. However, the character may view this in a positive light, seeing himself freed from the pressures of scrutiny or keeping on the move to leave trouble behind.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source>Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>NEWREC</Key>
    <Name>The New Recruit</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The New Recruit[h4]

Under the guidance of such wise administrators as Mon Mothma, the Alliance began recruiting efforts very early in its inception. Those skilled in the ways of intelligence, oration, and sheer talent scouting were employed from the start to build growing networks dedicated to finding those who had cause to oppose the Empire as well as the capability and the will to take action against it. As the conflict grows, so, too, does this network dedicated to finding bodies to fill the ranks and serve the needs of the Alliance. 

[P]A Player Character may well be a part of the Rebellion because he was discovered by someone in this network—someone who saw his potential and recognized his willingness to fight against the current regime imposed by Emperor Palpatine. It might not even have been someone normally tasked with recruitment who found the PC; chance encounters by those connected to the Alliance with those who might be able to help occur all the time, and risks are frequently taken if it means an opportunity to gain the services of a capable and savvy ally. 

[P]The cellular nature of most Alliance operations minimizes the risk of betrayal fairly well. Such recruits are tested considerably before they are ever given access to sensitive material or plans, and their awareness of the extent of the network they are connected to is kept to a minimum until they have truly earned the trust of their superiors.</Description>
    <Source>Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SEARCHINS</Key>
    <Name>The Searching Insurgent</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Searching Insurgent[h4]

Once they make the decision to oppose the terror and atrocities of the Empire, many individuals go looking for a way to contact and join up with the Rebellion. As badly as the Alliance needs people, though, it's not necessarily easy to find Alliance members to talk to about signing on. The vastly superior forces and assets of the Empire make it very dangerous for anyone to openly support the Alliance, as many planets and people discovered in the immediate aftermath of the Declaration of Rebellion. Imperial Intelligence and related agencies—not to mention countless bounty hunters—are constantly searching for any and all beings connected to the Rebellion, so secrecy is paramount to survival. 

[p]As such, finding a way to join the Alliance's efforts against the Empire can be a quest all its own. It could even be the basis for the start of an [B]Age of Rebellion[b] campaign. Hopefuls need to do a lot of research, investigation, and sneaking around to discover clues about the Rebellion and to avoid the attention of Imperial agents. At the same time, they must prove themselves capable and trustworthy to anyone with whom they might make contact. Such an endeavor is a very tense, very delicate game of cat and mouse at first; the searchers might even fall under Alliance observation for a time, not knowing they are being observed and judged while they continue to try to find a way in. 

[P]Many who want to join the Rebellion do so in rather dramatic fashion, taking it upon themselves to simply start striking against Imperial forces and assets. Such acts can be foolhardy and stupid, but they can also be brave and daring. If the would-be Rebels manage to succeed without getting themselves killed in the process, they may well draw the attention of Alliance operatives who are willing to talk to them about joining.</Description>
    <Source>Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ACCREB</Key>
    <Name>The Accidental Rebel</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Accidental Rebel[h4]

The vast majority of the sentient beings of the galaxy have no desire to join the Alliance or serve in the Rebellion. They may not be ardent supporters of the Empire, but this doesn't mean they are willing to drop everything in their lives to go blasting away at hordes of stormtroopers or weaving a dilapidated starship through swarms of TIE fighters. They would rather go about their business and live their lives, hopefully out of the way of any battles or other trouble. 
[P]Unfortunately for some hapless individuals, the galaxy has other plans. Cases of mistaken identity can result in innocents becoming wanted for crimes they never even considered. Receiving goods marked for Alliance use may find one or more PCs fleeing for their lives from Imperial agents or hired mercenaries. A friend's—or even casual acquaintance's—involvement with the Rebellion can saddle a character with unintended guilt by association. Of course, there are times when people simply find themselves in the wrong place at the wrong time and have no choice but to become heroes. 

[P]Alternately, unexpected situations may cause an epiphany for someone who was previously not interested in getting involved. While it may be easy to ignore tales of injustice and atrocity when they happen far away from an individual's daily life, many individuals have altogether different reactions when they come face-to-face with the horror of the Empire's policies. Apathy is difficult to maintain when someone watches another sentient executed for speaking out, a family enslaved because of their species, or an entire population wiped out for political expediency. 

[P]In such situations, a person's apathy can quickly turn to anger. That anger, in turn, often turns to action, usually with violent and irrevocable consequences. Once steps are taken toward open and direct opposition, such a character has joined the Rebellion in spirit, even if not yet in fact.</Description>
    <Source>Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>DISSART</Key>
    <Name>Dissident Artist</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Dissident Artist[h4]

Some people have a creative drive that cannot be stilled, and craft works that not only give expression to their thoughts and emotions but also push others to question their own positions. The PC has always been an uncompromising artist, and his controversial works eventually drew the ire of the Empire. In the face of pressure to tone down his creations, the PC refused to compromise his art and redoubled his efforts, challenging the establishment and inspiring the resistance. He became wanted as a political dissident of the Empire, but is now a welcome asset to the Alliance. 

[P]The value of an artist should not be underestimated. The character might possess an uncanny insight into how people of all species think, or he might have honed his skills and ingenuity through countless crafts and creations. Further, many artists have a level of celebrity that gives them unique access to people and places across the galaxy.</Description>
    <Source>Desperate Allies</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>IMPOUT</Key>
    <Name>Imperial Outcast</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Imperial Outcast[h4]

For obedient citizens of the Empire, success is said to come from joining the forces of law and order. Whether through Officer School, or as a bureaucrat in one of many local puppet governments, or merely as a low-level desk jockey, people from all worlds are encouraged to contribute to their government and reap the rewards of status and power. The PC started down this road, but events conspired to change his path. Perhaps the character became disillusioned with the chain of authority after being given an unsavory order, or he became a victim of the corruption and discrimination rampant within the Empire. 

[P]Forgetting the mindset that comes from years of training in the Empire is no simple task, and the character is likely to feel isolated, like a traitor who abandoned everything he had. However, he is likely to find, amid the ranks of the Rebel Alliance, others who began as the Empire's brightest and eventually realized that they, too, had to leave. </Description>
    <Source>Desperate Allies</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>MINVOICE</Key>
    <Name>Minority Voice</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Minority Voice[h4]

The Empire has built much of its power by taking advantage of conflict, ostracizing and exploiting smaller populations for its own gain. Some species, such as the Wookiees, are enslaved on their own worlds. Others are merely denied the privileges of the common citizen. Rather than choose to accept this injustice silently, the PC spoke up for a group victimized by the Empire's abuses. As a champion who fights for fairness for these outcasts, the PC highlights the injustices brought upon them. The Empire does not tolerate dissent, but the Rebel Alliance welcomes such voices. 

[P]The minority voice is likely to be an outspoken member of the Alliance. With a specific cause to champion, the character has good reason to push the group to do more to help those in need.</Description>
    <Source>Desperate Allies</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>INDUST</Key>
    <Name>Industrialist</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Industrialist[h4]

The galaxy is home to a dazzling array of shipyards, factories, and industrial complexes manufacturing all manner of equipment, such as weapons, droids, capital ships, mundane tools, and luxury items. The PC comes from a life of work in such operations, perhaps employed as a labor captain, shift supervisor, bureaucrat, or possibly even as the partial or sole owner of such a corporation. Running an operation that makes and distributes complicated equipment is no easy task, but the PC has made a career of making sure everyone in the business operates in unison to get things built. An astute knowledge of resource management can prove a boon to the beleaguered Alliance. 

[P]Unfortunately, many of the challenges facing the Alliance come to rest at the industrialist's doorstep. The Rebel forces are disparate, poorly funded, and frequently constrained to operating in secret. In sec-tors where the Empire's control is tight and regulations are strict, the character must reach into the depths of his experience to make ends meet.</Description>
    <Source>Desperate Allies</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SOTPROTOTYPE</Key>
    <Name>Prototype Tester</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Prototype Tester[h4]

The tester's job is to stress new, experimental vehicles until they break. He pushes the limits until all the various ceilings and tolerances are defined, refined, and improved. Then, he tries to break the vehicle all over again so corporations can put out a reliable, thoroughly tested vehicle. When an Ace comes from a prototype testing background, he brings nerves of durasteel and more than a little luck with him. Of all the Ace backgrounds, the tester is the most experienced at dealing with a malfunctioning vehicle and making emergency landings.</Description>
    <Source>Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SOTENTERTAINER</Key>
    <Name>Entertainer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Entertainer[h4]

Among civilians, there are few events more popular than a day at the racetrack. Spectators gather from across the planet to witness some of the bravest beings in the galaxy compete to find out who is the fastest. Between races, competitors often participate in exhibitions to hone their skills, test their vehicles, and dazzle spectators with heart-stopping maneuvers. 

[P]Most competition pilots are peaceful, living only for the thrill of victory, and for feeling that unique bond with their vehicle that only comes from pushing it to the limit with daredevil stunts and holo finishes. However, if pushed into choosing a side in the Galactic Civil War, entertainers possess the precise control over their vehicles required to make them lethal combatants. </Description>
    <Source>Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SOTCLONEWARS</Key>
    <Name>Clone Wars Veteran</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Clone Wars Veteran[h4]

While many think of the Clone Wars as a conflict between Jedi-led clone armies and Separatist droids, the truth of the matter is that most combatants were part of local defense forces and resistance movements. Veterans of the Clone Wars are valued as instructors first, who pass on their valuable combat experience to bush pilots and freighter captains joining the fight. Still, when called upon to suit up, veterans are able to shake any rust quickly, and become lethal presences in any skirmish. 

[p]The Clone Wars gave many Aces the chance to establish heroic legacies, which thrust them into prominent military or political roles in the subsequent Galactic Empire. Others quietly retired, any lust for combat they might have once possessed satisfied ten-fold. On the other hand, most Separatist veterans languished in exile on the Outer Rim or rotted in Imperial prisons. When the Rebellion against the Empire took shape, a number of veteran Aces defected from the Empire, came out of retirement, or were freed by the Rebels to assist in their struggle. 

[P]The list of Clone Wars veterans among Rebel ranks is extensive, including Garven Dreis, immortalized for his sacrifice at the Battle of Yavin under the call sign Red Leader. During the Clone Wars, Dreis was a local defense force pilot at Virujansi, and flew alongside Anakin Skywalker.</Description>
    <Source>Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SOTIMPDEF</Key>
    <Name>Imperial Defector</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Imperial Defector[h4]

Imperial academies at Carida, Raithal, Corulag, and Prefsbelt turn out a never-ending stream of officers, stormtroopers, and pilots for the Empire. The academy teaches standard Imperial tactics and maneuvers, so that graduates can assimilate into military units throughout Imperial space. The program weans out undesirables by design, and a fair percentage of each class of trainees washes out. 
[P]While the curriculum emphasizes loyalty to the Empire, many cadets find themselves unable to execute what they see as unjust orders. These graduates often desert or defect to the Rebellion. A famous example is the mutiny of the Rand Ecliptic, which was led by recent academy graduates Biggs Darklighter and Derek "Hobbie" Klivian. Once in command of the vessel, Biggs, Hobbie, and a number of other sympathetic TIE pilots joined up with the Rebellion.</Description>
    <Source>Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SOTBUSH</Key>
    <Name>Bush Pilot</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Bush Pilot[h4]

Most agriworlds in the galaxy are the same: vast fields used to grow crops or graze herds, with long distances between neighbors. The farmers and ranchers of the galaxy typically use airspeeders as utility vehicles for crop dusting, herding, and transport into town. The bored youth of most quiet agriworlds almost universally chase adventure by buzzing the fields and threading the canyons of their homeworlds, imagining they are anywhere else in the galaxy. These young bush pilots often meet up and race through dangerous terrain unsupervised, and are among the most underrated pilots in the galaxy thanks to their extremely informal training. 

[P]Perhaps the most famous bush pilot in the galaxy is Luke Skywalker, who honed his skills flying a T-16 Skyhopper across Tatooine's Beggar's Canyon and moisture farms with his friends. Skywalker went on to become the hero of the Battle of Yavin and a key leader in the elite Rogue Squadron. Countless pilots of the Rebellion come From similar, humble origins, and sometimes their lack of formal training enables them to surprise opponents trained in traditional combat tactics. </Description>
    <Source>Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>FLEEEMP</Key>
    <Name>Fleeing the Empire</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Fleeing the Empire[h4]

The Empire hunts down Force users diligently and enthusiastically. The character may have betrayed his affinity to the Force in some way, perhaps by anticipating someone's thoughts or saving someone's life by stopping a crashing speeder with his mind. Whatever the cause, the character is now hunted by Imperial agents and must flee his former life or be destroyed.</Description>
    <Source>Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>GREATPOW</Key>
    <Name>With Great Power...</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]With Great Power...[h4]

Some individuals cannot stand idly by while watching the evils the Empire inflicts on the galaxy. The character knows he's been given a gift that few others have. To squander it while innocents suffer would be the height of irresponsibility.</Description>
    <Source>Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ULTAB</Key>
    <Name>Ultimate Abilities</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Ultimate Abilities[h4]

Some characters see their strange abilities as a sign that they are destined for greatness. They can do things that others around them cannot. Clearly, this means they are a cut above the general population. To leave their life behind is merely the first step in a journey that may see them rise to become the ultimate power in the universe. Whether or not they use that power for good—or for evil—remains to be seen.</Description>
    <Source>Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ANCIENTORDER</Key>
    <Name>Ancient Order</Name>
    <Description>
    [H4]Ancient Order[h4]
[P]Some characters become Guardians because they are chosen to follow an order with a long history, which naturally prepares them for their eventual role. Such characters have likely known their intended destiny for a long time, many trained from birth. Their teachers may have also been Force-sensitive, or they might have been completely unaware of the mystical powers their students possessed. No matter how an individual Guardian reached this place, The PC's skills are a natural fit for this specific role that years of training entail. 
[P]Guardians of this sort tend to be guided by a concrete code passed down by their ancestors or predecessors, though invariably, some rebel against even the most ironclad of laws and codes of honor.</Description>
    <Source>Keeping the Peace</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>OUTAGENT</Key>
    <Name>Outlaw Agent</Name>
    <Description>
    [H4]Outlaw Agent[h4]
[P]Not all heroes are able to work exclusively for the forces of good. Sometimes, the only choice is between perpetuating the Empire's oppression and joining a criminal group in opposing it. Some beings are even conscripted forcefully into illegal operations. 
[P]Still, working under the umbrella of a criminal empire does not mean that a character cannot help others. This sort of Guardian excels at making the best of a bad situation. Guardians such as these might have codes of personal honor adopted from the organizations they served, or they might see the idea of honor among criminals as a mere pretense that killers such as themselves use to play at being civilized.</Description>
    <Source>Keeping the Peace</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>BATTLEADER</Key>
    <Name>Battlefield Leader</Name>
    <Description>
    [H4]Battlefield Leader[h4]
[P]Being the first to battle necessarily means putting oneself in harm's way. A Guardian who jumps into the fray first and leads every charge has likely taken a lifetime's worth of hits. Guardians of this sort often leap before they look, and consider risks to themselves to be acceptable as long as they can protect the ones they lead in battle. 
[P]Characters of this sort also tend to make moral judgments on the fly, doing what they see as right in the moment rather than binding themselves to any specific code. Still, some - especially those who go on to command - develop a concrete philosophy of right or wrong over time, based on their own past experiences rather than ancient texts.</Description>
    <Source>Keeping the Peace</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>WAYFARER</Key>
    <Name>Wayfarer</Name>
    <Description>
    [H4]Wayfarer[h4]
[P]Some who follow the path of the Guardian are not content, or able to stay in one place. The galaxy is a big place, with countless planets, all sorts of strange creatures and civilizations, and naturally, innumerable beings who need protection. Guardians who follow the winds - or the call of the Force - often find others counting on them.  A wayfaring Guardian rises to the occasion, but neither allies nor accolades can keep this character rooted. After all, hyperspace is calling just as surely as the voices of the weak, the powerless, and the oppressed.
[P]Indeed, perhaps the need to protect others keeps this Guardian traveling - lingering too long in one place risks drawing the wrath of the Empire upon the very people the Guardian sought to safeguard. Guardians of this sort often follow only the call of their own conscience, unbound by structured regulations or explicit codes. Still, there are always exceptions; some who wander do so to fulfill oaths, uphold obligations, or pursue more esoteric ends.[P][H4]
  </Description>
    <Source>Keeping the Peace</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>UNDTECH</Key>
    <Name>Underworld Tech Expert</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Underworld Tech Expert[h4]
In the [B]Edge of The Empire[b], it can be hard to avoid occasionally interacting with criminal enterprises and underworld culture. Many Technicians support and are supported by shady characters, if not by outright criminals. Specialised underwolrd techs can be highly prized when they fulfull a critical role in a larger organisation, bu the average Mechanic or Droid Tech is sometimes regarded as more expendable than a reliable enforcer. The character might be trying to escape difficult decisions from the past or seeking to advance within a particular criminal organisation.
[P]For crime lords, being able to have people put back together is almost as important as being able to take tehm apart in the first place. A [B]Cyber Tech[b] might have once been kept on retainer by a criminal organisation, patching up enforcers and bosses or maintaining their temperamental cybertechnology. Such an individual is often indispensable, which makes leaving in one piece very difficult. Of course, the ability to rebuild oneself completely makes crafting a new identity after escaping much easier.
[P]A [B]Droid Tech[b] can keep a syndicate's security droids operational, repairing these mechanical servants after they are damaged in turf wars (or by a wrathful boss who dislikes recieving bad news from droid messengers). However, seeing the droid damaged and abused again and again might drive a compassionate Droid Tech to flee, taking these mechanical charges with along for the ride. Running away from a crim syndicate is never easy, but having a loyal army of customised droids to help does improve such a fugitive's chances of survival dramatically.
[P][B]Mechanics[b] serve a multitude of roles in the criminal underworld, and one of the most notorious jobs is as a laborer in a starship chop shop. These illegal operations, ofter disguised as legitimate garages, dismantle stolen starships so that their parts can be sold without an obvious trail. A Mechanic who got started in such an environment would likely be very skilled at assessing and dismantling vehicles, but might well dream of of putting them together instead. The chance to do so might be enough to lure such a character away from steady (if ethically dubious) work, though the criminal syndicates that own such operations often take a dim view of anyone who wishes to leave.
[P][B]Modders[b] are needed to customised starships and vehicles for smuggling operations. A real master of modification can get the most out of a starship's engine to help it escape Imperial patrols, find every spare centimeter of hill that could contain hidden compartments and generally turn even an inauspicious vehicle into one of the fastest, stealthiest, most efficient smuggling machines in the galaxy. Any outfit of smugglers would do well to have a Modder as a contact, or better yet, as a member or the crew.
[P]Outlaw [B]Slicers[b] are common enough, serving in criminal syndicates to thwart law enforcement and competitors alike through clever use of computers. However, some of the best Slicers who act as Underworld Tech Experts are strictly freelance. These individuals can crack any computer, foil any droid's programming, and stalk through the HoloNet like a ghost, acquiring information without anyone else ever knowing. These masterful Slicers are more than mere inforchants, for not only can they intercept information, but they can also change it, distribute it, and fabricate it wholesale. The best of the best sometimes consider themselves artists as much as Technicians and demand exorbitant fees for their efforts, taking on only the jobs that catch their interest. Such Slicers are vanishingly rare, but their impact can be felt across the galaxy - of they want anyone to know that they exist at all, that is.
[P]The obvious specialisation for characters deep in the underworld is the [B]Outlaw Tech[b]. Many Outlaw Techs openly embrace the criminal lifestyle and the inherent difficulties and danger, usually for the credits. An Outlaw Tech might once have been muscle for a criminal organisation, using a deadly array of custom-built weapons and wargear to eliminate threats, assinate witnesses and terrorise anyone who stood in the syndicate's way. Whether an Outlaw Tech wields a disruptor, a personal stealth field, a deflector shield or a highly customised rifle, nobody else is as well-suited to maintaining and optimising such a deadly arsenal. The Outlaw Tech might custom-build weapons to take out specific targets, honing blades to pierce the skind of particularly tough creatures, brewing toxins that affect only certain species or tailoiring environment-specific camoflage. Usually, leaving a criminal organisation is a risky proposition, but in the case of a brillian, tech-enhanced killer with a resumé of executions to match, even the most jaded crime boss might have seen the wisdom in letting the Outlaw Tech walk away unscathed.</Description>
    <Source Page="16">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>BORNENG</Key>
    <Name>Born Engineer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Born Engineer[h4]
Some characters take to tinkering as children or as adolescents, displaying a prodigious skill with technology at a young age. A Born Engineer's precocious skill might have been learned from an influential mentor while growing up. The mentor could be a parent, an older sibling, a neighborhood mechanic, or a formal instructor. Alternatively, such a character could be a loner or misfit in a family or community that is focused on other aspects of life. Whether the character is carrying on the legacy of a mentor or fighting against tradition will have a substantial impact on the way the PC views technology. A character who honors a beloved teacher by continuing that person's craft will take considerable pride in technical prowess, while a PC who was scorned for early success might still be ashamed of these skills on some level.
[P]A uniquely skilled [B]Cyber Tech[b] might have discovered this particular speciality when the character suddenly lost a limb or crucial organ. Whether the injury was due to an industrial accident, a violent altercation, or a disease, the character might have first become familiart with cybernetics through maintenance of personal devices and this uncovered an innate talent for crafting and implanting these mechanical prosthetics. The character's expertise might be largely self-taught combining an intuitive understanding with practical know-how picked up during years of using cybernetics.
[P]People born with exceptional skills sometimes find themselves isolated from others in spite of their abilities, or even because of them. An up-and-coming [B]Droid Tech[b] might have decided to tackle the problem of making fiends in a literal fashion, crafting a droid companion to understand the character as others did not. Whether or not these efforts were successful, such a Born Engineer might feel considerable respect and empathy for droids in memory of that early companion.
[P]A [B]Mechanic[b] might be the heir to a line of machinists, innovating upon designs drawn up by parents or more distant ancestors. Such a character could hail from a family corporation that manufactures starships and might use innate aptitude and education to pursue the company's interests by creating increasingly refined designs. Growing up around starships would have given the character an unmatched fluency in this craft. Tith this innate understanding of machines, a Born Engineer with strong corporate ties would be well-positioned to create that company's greatest technological achievements yet.
[P]The path that a Born Engineer takes can vary a great deal based on teh resources available in the environment where the character grew up. A [B]Modder[b] might have developed an incredible knack for making due with scraps and hald-broken machines because the character grew up aboard a tramp freighter that traveled the fringes of the galaxy. At the edges of civilized space, one has to learn to repurpose machines as needed to survive. Such a character might obsessively hoard anything that could even possibly be useful later,, for who can really say that the servos and wires in a droid's severed arm won't someday be useful for a cobbled-together machine that sustains failing air filters or realigns the hyperdrive?
[P]A character whjo grew up aboard a space station or other mechanized living facility likely knows a great deal about computers. A Born Engineer can thrive in such an environment, and might have quickly taekn to creating and modifying code, becoming a [B]Slicerb[b]. Because everything on a space station is generally wired in to a central computer network, a Slicer can be an incredible asset to the pwople in charge - or an even more infuriating thorn in their side. Such a Slicer might have been a sort of law enforcer, helping maintain order on the station, or might have become a local renegade. using a mastery of computers to steal credits, evade the authorities, or pursue some other goal frowned upon by those in power.
[P]Someone raised on the fringes of the galaxy could have a natural disdain for regulations and instruction manuals, sliding into the role of [B]Outlaw Tech[b]. After all, far from the Core Worlds, warranties are meaningless, and user safety instructions seem like suggestions at best. Someone with a genius for constructing devices could easily turn it to the production of arms perhaps first from retrofitted machine tools and later for custom-crafted parts made to the finest specifications. A weaponsmith fromt he Outer Rim might not see arms dealership as a dirty trade - people need weapons to defend themselves from creatures and marauders alike in the lawlwss wastes, and to suggest otherwise is naive, as the weaponsmith sees it. Hoever, if such a character was confronted with the harm those weapons dealt after a lifetime of crafting them, it might force even the most innately skilled Outlaw Tech to regret pursuing the perfection in arms that felt so natural at the time.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>TECHDES</Key>
    <Name>Tech Designer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Tech Designer[h4]
Some Technicians believe that no matter what problem a being faces, the answer always lies in building a better solution, If a starship engine is powerful, it can be made more compact. If a cybernetic amr is as precise as an organic one, it can be made even more exact. Technology transforms the galazy, and those at the cutting edge of design have the power to create a future in their own image.
[P]Cybernetic prosthetics are already almost unbelievably advanced, capable of not only mimicking the function of a lost limb, but even transmitting sensations to the user just like a flesh and blood equivalent. However some [B]Cyber Techs[b] are hardly content to rest on these laurels. For these individuals, cybernetics are not merely a means to restore lost functionality, but an oppurtunity to pursue abilities a fully organic being could never attain. These Tech Designers frequently do not confine their ideas to  the traditional form of a species, instead designing cybernetics that fulfill their functions best. These "optiimizations" might be as small as additional limbs for added utility or as vast as completly replacing the body with a frame of wire and steel. While many cringe at such a thought these innovators hold with certainty that, as always, progress is inevitable.
[P]To most organic beings, droids represent a strange sidestep in evolution - most see them as simulacra of intelligent beings rather than as entities in their own right. However, some organic [B]Droid Techs[b] (and more than a few droids) believe these machanical beings to be the logical successors to the concept of "life". After all, droids are theoretically immortal, their intelligences can be untethered from their bodies, and they cn adapt both their bodies and minds dramicatlly to new circumstances with incredible speed; few organic species can boast such qualities. And, while droids have rarely occupied places of galactic prestige, evolution can be a slow process followed by explosive change. A few eccentric droid designers even believe that in pushing the development of droids forwar, life grows ever closer to perfection.
[P]ON the finges of galactic society, [B]Mechanics[b] frequently can't purchase every device their crews need. If ofter falls to ships' Mechanics to build something from scrathc to solve problems that nobody doresaw. However, while some Mechanics are content to simple cobble together an inefficient solution, Tech Designer believe that if they're going to do something they should do it right. While breaking out a drafting board might be impractical in the midst of a crisis, doing so when the Mechanic has time to carefully design and construct a device that not only solves the problem in the short term, but also minimizes waste and unforessn consequences int he future.
[P]While most [B]Modders[b] are not usually designers in the traditional snese of being who draft devices from scratch, they do have a place on any development team, be it with a major corporation or at a small technology firm. After all, while the original designer comes up with a device's intended purpose, someone has to figure out what the machine is actually good for. For this task of product testing, few can match a Modder's willingness to take things apart, slap things  together, igore recommended settings and make unorthodox use of anything froma  blaster to a starthips engine to a computer.
[P][B]Outlaw Techs[b] at the cutting edge of their field usually on the front lines, testing their technology first-hand. There is not crucible for development like actual combat, and most Oulaw Techs who work to advance combat technology to the brink want to be there to observe the results. The character might work as a mercenary or even a bounty hunter ot find oppurtunites to push new gear to its breaking point. Such a character might see combat as part experiment, part technology demo. An Outlaw Tech of this persuation is always on the lookout for clients to impress with new armaments.
[P]Computer systems are always imporving, changing and evolving and so too must [B]Slicers[b]. Slicers who want to stay current ar always learning new tricks, developing new workarounds to common security and finding ways to subvert security. However, some of the most dangerous slicers are those who design their own rigs and programs, and they can be very difficult for even the most skilled administrators to predict or defend against.

    </Description>
    <Source Page="15">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ANTIQ</Key>
    <Name>Antiquarian</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Antiquarian[h4]
Technology often seems an inherently progressive idea, and to many people it represents only efforts ot buld and improve upon the things of th past. However, some Technicians are actually deeply engaged in the past. The galaxy is unfathomably ancient, and over countless millenia, thousands of species have lived and discovered new ways to transform their environments to their needs. At first glance, manufacturing techniques used only in a single community on a backwater world might seem less advanced than those used in a vast starship constuction facility. However, these unique methods may produce results that are not directly comparable, or may even perform certain tasks better than their "modern" counterparts. The metallurgy of some societies whose members have never left their homeworlds have been found to surpass the industrial standards used to fabricate starship hulls due to the specialized techniques used by these enclaves. Other cultures have found inventive solutions to problems the wider galaxy never even thought to address, from creative energy solusions in absence of traditional fuels, to esoteric weapons that function on principles that still evade even the sharpest researchers and academics.
[P]Life is perhas the strangest phenomenon in a galaxy filled with nigh-unfathomable wonders ranging from black holes to gravity itself. In the face of hardship, life leverages its encironment to its advantage. For intelligent forms of life, this frequently includes the development of mechanical prosthetics by [B]Cyber Techs[b]. However, sentient beings are as varied as they are adaptable and cybernetic technologies are not a one-size-fits-all proposition. NOt all species have nervous systems that function in the same way - and some do not have them at all, at least in the traditional sense. By seeking out the myriad ways in which different intelligent species across space and time have enhanced their bodies, a Cyber Tech can uncover increible innovations in mechanical science and medicine alike.
[P]Like starships and many other commone technologies, droids have existed since time immemorial. However, unlike most other advanced constructs, droids are capable of self-modification. A [B]Droid Tech[b] with an interest in antiquity might seek out unique droids that pushed their own evolution in strange and innovative ways. Finding even a fragment of such a being might provide months of work for the character in dissecting the surviving hardware and code to understand the being's ideas, motives, and other thoughts. An organic being might pursue this path, but so too might a droid, especially one who wishes to understand the complexities of its own existence as a being of artifice.
[P]Not everyone can hail from a technological hot spot like Corellia or even from a fringe world such as Tatooine. However, individual who grow up in truly low-tech communites are just as innovative as their more technologicall experienced counterparts. A [B]Mechanic[b] from a world without advanced technology might have experience with metallurgy, chemistry and machines that do not rely on electricity. Such an individual might be a specialist at producing a particular thing, like a blacksmith, architect or weaver, but might also be a generalist who serves a community's wider needs. Unleashed upon the galaxy, such an Antiquarian would likely acclimate rapidly, using the same logical modes of thinking and practical knowhow to master new technologies.
[P]The galaxy is filled with examples of innovation and a [B]Modder[b] would be remiss not to take at least a passing interest in such ventures from history and the forgotten edges of galactic society. Some Modders dive headlong into this world of rediscovery, seeking out ancient or overlooked cultures and intergrating their unique innovations into existing pieces of  technology for personal use. Unlike some other Technicians, most Modders hold little to be sacret, least of all the instruction manual. Thus, these mechanical mavericks are often willing to draw upon any useful knowledge, regardless of whether its source is published and accredited within the lofty academies of the Core Worlds.
[P]Sentient species have been fighting each other for thousands upon thousands of years - and most have been fighting among themselves since they arose from the primordial muck of their various homeworlds - and [B]Outlaw Techs[b] know it. The winners have usually been those who have wielded the best weapons. Over countless eons of war, the sentient beings of the galaxy have created an incredible variety of weapons, and some Outlaw Techs pride themselves on collecting rare pieces from anient civilizations and far-flung worlds. Such character might not only appreciate the efficacy of such weaponry, but also get a substanital thrill out of adding rare works to their arsenals.
[P]Most species have possessed computers for even longer than they have had starships or droids. While many [B]Slicers[b] look down on ancient computer interfaces, the wise know that the past is the foudation of the future. A Slicer who understands computer code from a historical perspective cna often find vulnerabilities and back doors buried deep in laryers of digital sediment and use these to gain an advantage over the competition. From ancient starship computers still in use after centuries to HoloNet relays established in ancient days, an Atiquarian Slicer has no shortage of oppurtunities to put the secrets  fo the past to work.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>FAILLEAD</Key>
    <Name>The Failed Leader</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Failed Leader[h4]
Not everyone is born to lead. Many individuals are
thrust into positions of power against their will, or discover
their shortcomings as leaders when it’s too late.
These characters are such souls, who, through lack of
skill or blatant misfortune, have failed in their attempts
to command their people. Whether they have learned
from their mistakes, or even recognize the mistakes for
what they are, can be a pivotal decision when creating
such Commanders. What remains to be seen is how
they use the lessons they’ve learned, if they’ve learned
them at all, and whether they can earn back the respect
they’ve lost—that of their peers, as well as their own.
[P][B]Commodores[b] who fail to lead often lose their vessels
to the enemy. Their ships are either captured,
perhaps by pirates, or destroyed in military action
due to poor decisions or tactical blunders. Each such
loss is a disgrace that must somehow be atoned for,
whether the failure was the Commander’s fault or
the result of an unfortunate series of events. While
failure to lead on the ground might lead to a handful
of deaths, the loss of a starship results in hundreds,
sometimes thousands, of casualties. The weight of
such a burden is difficult to bear, but one must learn
to live with it if one is to strive for better days ahead.
[P]Losing a starfighter to enemy fire is bad enough, especially
given the difficulty of acquiring new ships to replace
those that have been lost. Losing pilots, however, is all
the more serious, as talented fighter pilots don’t grow on
trees. Each one lost is irreplaceable, and failed [B]Squadron
Leaders[b] have lost most, if not all, of their pilots and
starfighters in combat. The guilt and shame surrounding
this loss haunts them at every moment, and replacing
their pilots and ships is likely a top priority
[P]Every [B]Tactician[b] makes mistakes, but it’s the size
of those mistakes and the cost they inflict in lives
that they fear the most. Whether a Tactician planned
a failed raid on an enemy facility, or chose to hit a
flank the Empire had secretly reinforced, he’s lost a
significant number of troops due to his own miscalculations.
His own self-confidence is shaken, and he
feels—rightly or wrongly—that the trust his troops
and his commanding officer have placed in him has
been weakened too.
[P]Failed [B]Figureheads[b] can come from two different
backgrounds. In the first, they once experienced a monumental
climb in popularity and power, only to lose it all
due to the Empire’s policies or their own overreach or
corruption. In the second background, they never really
succeeded as a politician at all, and instead eked out a
living as a cog in some larger political machine. In these
cases, they must attempt to either regain what they’ve
lost, or gain what they never had, and the Rebel Alliance
is the perfect opportunity to do just that.
[P]When a [B]Strategist[b] fails, the outcome of an entire
conflict can be placed in jeopardy. This defeat can
be the result of a single bad decision, or the product
of a number of smaller mistakes that snowball into
an overwhelming catastrophe. Though Strategists
rarely work alone, especially in the higher echelons
of Alliance Command, their expertise and opinions
are well respected and always considered when plans
are made. To fail at this level is a rebuke that few can
bounce back from, but learning from one’s mistakes
may very well make one a better Strategist in the end.
[P]It is popularly said that “Those who can, do. Those
who can’t, teach.” Such a dubious proverb seems to have
been devised with these particular [B]Instructors[b] in mind.
Despite their best efforts to attain a fleet appointment,
a battlefield commission, or a political appointment,
they were never able to do so. Instead of achieving what
they felt was their calling in life, they have instead been
relegated to an Instructor’s position, training troops to
do the job they once aspired to do themselves. Such
individuals may be bitter and resentful, but that doesn’t
mean they won’t rise to the occasion in time.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Lead by Example</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>DEFECTOR</Key>
    <Name>Defector</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Defector[h4]
Prior to joining the Rebel Alliance, defector characters
were among the ranks of an enemy. Their former
master was most likely the Empire, but even
criminal organizations or regional governments that
have crossed swords with the Alliance are possible.
[P]For whatever reason—a moral quandary, disillusionment,
or disgrace—such characters have
defected from their original organization and offered
their loyalty to the Alliance. Though accepted by the
Rebels, defectors have yet to earn their complete
trust. To make matters worse, defectors are fugitives
who face certain death should they be captured by
their former masters.
[P]Many [B]Commodores[b] defected from the Imperial
Navy following the dissolution of the Imperial Senate.
Fearing the ambitions of Emperor Palpatine
more than the justice they might face if caught, they
now lead the Rebellion’s fledgling navy. They helm
ships great and small, contributing what they can
to the fight ahead. A good number of the Alliance’s
most recognized Commodore heroes learned all they
know in the Imperial Navy and cut their teeth at the
Imperial Academy.
[P]To survive more than a handful of missions, TIE
pilots have to be the best they can be. Many [B]Squadron
Leaders[b] developed a taste for adrenaline at the
controls of an Imperial fighter, battling pirates in the
Outer Rim or chasing smugglers closer to the Core.
For whatever reason, they’ve taken their skills over to
the other side, trading in the Empire’s flimsy TIEs for
durable X-wings and maneuverable A-wings.
[P]Serving with ground forces isn’t exactly the most
prestigious occupation in the Imperial war machine.
Nevertheless, the Imperial Army is a powerful organization
with limitless personnel and excellent equipment.
Former Imperial [B]Tacticians[b] get acquainted with
the brutality of combat early on, and many of them
question the ethics of terror tactics. Taking ground is
one thing, but murdering innocents serves no tangible
purpose. It isn’t unusual for such individuals to defect
to the Rebel Alliance, and some view their decision as
the only thing that can save their soul.
[P]Palpatine’s grand strategy hasn’t always been clear,
for the Empire is a dark and secretive institution.
Many of the most effective military [B]Strategists[b] in the
Empire found themselves marginalized once the Galactic
Civil War was in full swing. Others decided that
the war they were fighting wasn't the right one and
chose to take their abilities elsewhere. Whatever their
reasons, they may very well have an inside view of the
Empire’s motivations and future plans that could be
of great value to the Rebel Alliance.
[P]Whether they served as teachers at the Imperial
Academy or as drill sergeants in any one of a thousand
Imperial boot camps across the galaxy, [B]Instructors[b]
play a pivotal role in ensuring that troops are
well trained and fit for action. Sending citizens off to
die in an immoral conflict can leave a bad taste in
anyone’s mouth, and a handful of the Empire’s brightest
teachers have decided to instill their lessons in
fledgling Rebels, instead.
[P]Many Republic loyalists were displaced when Palpatine
came to power. These [B]Figureheads[b] soon
found themselves left out in the cold, their opinions
and politics openly ignored or violently prosecuted
by their former master. Some come from the Senate,
having formerly represented a system or locality,
while others held more mundane positions within
the Republic or Imperial political machines. Whatever
their reasons, they see a promise of power in the
Rebel Alliance—if it can win the war, of course.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Lead by Example</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>CITSOLD</Key>
    <Name>Citizen Soldier</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Citizen Soldier[h4]
Citzen soldiers are commoners from across the galaxy who fight to protect their families, their planets and their people. Though many such individuals serve in teh ranks of the Rebel Alliance only a handful reveal themselves to be exemplary leaders, especially in times of freat strife. For these people, the Rebel Alliance is a temporary but absolute obligation; the only things that might end their service are victory or death.
[P]Civilian ship commanders and free traders are plentiful the galaxy over, especially in areas of commerce and intersystem trade. Though their experience in space battles may be lacking or limited to skirmishes against pirates here and there, some discover they possess latent talents in leadership and ship-to-ship tactics. A great many Rebel [B]Commodores[b] are drawn from this large pool of individuals , perhaps even using their own ships and crews to help forge victory for the Rebel Alliance.
[P]Not all [B]Squadron Leaders[b] are trained for military
action. Some act as test pilots for corporate or planetary
ship manufacturers, while the majority ply their
trade as couriers, escorts, or transport captains. Hoping
to make a difference in securing the galaxy for
freedom, they have offered their skills and reflexes to
the Rebel Alliance and found themselves no worse off
for their lack of academy training. Those who can lead
oftentimes find themselves placed in command of a
fighter element, a squadron, or an entire attack wing.
If only their parents could see them now!
[P]Civilians trained in tactics are a rarity, and those
who are usually come from law enforcement backgrounds.
Other [B]Tacticians[b] were once war scholars
and historians, familiar with small and large unit
tactics due to their chosen area of study. Still, there
are those who participate in mock combats, either
on holographic tabletops or in skirmishes on civilian
“stun ranges,” where fun and safety are the rule rather
than the exception. Though they may be derided by
the trained soldiers they serve with, many find their
experiences a boon on the battlefield.
[P]Though politics may be a realm of power and ambition,
a great many politicos get involved in the affairs
of state to better serve their communities. Though
some of these officeholders may have been successful
in local politics, or even risen to occupy a Senator’s
seat, the Empire has effectively stripped their
people of freedom, and nothing they can do through
official channels can change that. With the trust and
admiration of their constituents behind them, these
[B]Figureheads[b] take their talents to the Rebel Alliance,
motivating citizens the galaxy over to support the
fight against Imperial tyranny.
[P]War in politics and business isn’t all that different
from combat. Though the methods used to achieve
victory may be different, the ultimate goal remains
chillingly similar in all three mediums. [B]Strategists[b]
from the civilian sector often have their roots in
economic, corporate, or political endeavors. Those
employed by the Rebel Alliance are likely to find
themselves working to destroy the Empire not militarily,
but economically. They also work to provide the
Alliance with its own income streams, especially those
that cannot be drastically affected by the Empire’s
efforts to bankrupt the Rebellion.
[P][B]Instructors[b] who qualify as citizen soldiers have
their roots in a number of civilian professions, such
as law enforcement, education, and (strangely
enough) health and fitness. Instructors with experience
in law enforcement training are capable of
teaching small unit tactics, weapons use, and selfdefense,
while health and fitness professionals specialize
in enhancing individual fitness through calisthenics,
martial arts, and other methods. Scholars
and educators are just as valuable, allowing potential
Rebels to learn the theories behind warfare on
a number of levels, and can help individuals to learn
critical lessons from history.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Lead by Example</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>MERC</Key>
    <Name>Mercenary</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Mercenary[h4]
Not every Soldier of the Rebellion fights for the high
and mighty ideals of the cause; some take up arms
for purely financial incentives. Hired guns might have
signed a contract with the rebels with the expectation of high risk, high reward jobs. While Alliance High
Command has few credits to spend on mercenaries,
some jobs are just too specialized to assign to Alliance
Regulars. On occasion, the Alliance finds an alternative to Imperial credits for payment.
[P]However, most mercenaries find that once they
begin working with the Alliance, it has a way of sweeping them up in their cause. Those whose hearts cannot be melted by Alliance idealism and morality might
find themselves reported to the Empire as a rebel
sympathizer and blacklisted from working for clients
in the corporate world.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Forged in Battle</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>IDEALREC</Key>
    <Name>Idealistic Recruit</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Idealistic Recruit[h4]
While those victimized by the Empire make up a significant portion of rebel forces, as do Imperial defectors, their numbers aren’t enough to threaten a single
Imperial fortress world, let alone engage in conventional warfare with the Empire on multiple fronts. The
Alliance Army is dependent on a steady stream of
young, wide-eyed recruits willing to give their all in
an attempt to restore peace and justice to the galaxy. Fresh faces drawn from every corner of the galaxy travel to secret rebel bases to undergo the basic
training the Alliance can provide before deployment.
[P]Recruits come from all social and economic backgrounds, but those from the Outer Rim are most eager
to join, having only heard about Imperial atrocities
secondhand. Brave recruiters carefully spread propaganda vids across backwater planets and arrange
meetings to discuss how the Empire impacts the galaxy, eventually swaying local youth to join the Alliance.
Most rimfolk already possess most of the skills the rebels want in their recruits. Life on the Rim often teaches
them resilience in the face of adversity, familiarity with
ranged weaponry, basic equipment repair skills, and an
eagerness for any life that gets them offworld.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Forged in Battle</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>LABOR</Key>
    <Name>Laborer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Laborer[h4]
Laborers start off in menial occupations essential but less-valued skills and often involve repetitive, physical work. They often suffer economic injustices on the lower rung of the socioeconomic ladder. Labor leaders fit the Activist background better, so this background often reflects those who grew up in humbler circumstances. a laborer's strugg;es can be about moral corruption but can also include fighting against despair and drudgery.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>REFUGEE</Key>
    <Name>Refugee</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Refugee[h4]
Refugees have escaped violence, starvation, and persecution only to face similar problems in their new home. In some cases, cities are unprepared to handle an influx of refugees and have no social services set up to accommodate them. In extreme instances, governments seperate refugees from the rest of the population and cut them off from economic opportunities. On other worlds, differences in culture create tenrions among the populations, and refugees face violence from the citizenry rahter than the government.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>OFFICIAL</Key>
    <Name>Official</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Official[h4]
Officials once worked in the system, either in the local bureaucracy, law enforcement, a religious organization, or the Empire itself. From their chairs and desks, they had access to those in power, but ironically, they had  little power themselves, being cogs in a machine built of procedures, red tape, and calcified culture. In an organization hostile to Force users, the official's title became a collar, and the positon a leash, forcing the official to abandon this rigid life if the pursuit of something more meaningful is desired.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ARISTO</Key>
    <Name>Aristocrat</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Aristocrat[h4]
Aristocrats have (or had) money and perhaps a title. They may belong to an actual aristocracy, come from moneyed families or bear historic names that grant them privileges, even if only token privileges. Somtimes these privileges oppress another group. Like elected or appointed officials, aristocrats are bolstered by their position and hampered by the conservatism of the system it is part of. In this case, cultural pressures rather than bureaucratic ones maintain the status quo. Sentinels with this background may still have family and friend who search for them, providing a resource, a source of conflict, and an emotional tie that enemies might exploit.</Description>
    <Source Page="11">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>GANGL</Key>
    <Name>Gang Leader</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Gang Leader[h4]
Gang leaders don't always organize their groups purely for violence. Some toughs gather together to protect themselves and support each other. Other gangs mobilize to become the unofficial police of a neighborhood, espeically in places where law enforcement refuses to patrol. Gangs are sometimes a symptom of a city suffering from the disease of an injustice, be it poverty or local persecution. They are only as violent and corrupt as their leaders, though, and those led by Sentinels might be the best forces of good in a city.</Description>
    <Source Page="12">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>RECLUSE</Key>
    <Name>Recluse</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Recluse[h4]
Not all Seekers avoid the centres of galactic activity because they are pursuing particular goals or need to be on the run. For some, dwelling on the fringes of the galaxy is all they have ever known. Their paths may eventually lead them into contact with wider society but they bear the indelible imprint of their origins as outsiders. These Seekers may have come from a society largely undiscovered by other species, or they may have simply been born into a remote area that recieves few visitors. In rare cases, they might possibly be the descendants of other Force users, who fled the Imperial purge or even earlier calamities, and have grown up deliberately cut off from the outside world.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Savage Spirits</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>EXILE</Key>
    <Name>Exile</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Exile[h4]
While many Seekers choose their paths, some are set upon them by events beyond their control. Whether they are cast adrift by the will of the Force or just cruel chance is difficult to say, but these new circumstances demeand that Seekers adapt quickly. They might be constantly on the run from the past they left behind, dodging bounty hunters, Imperials, or even their own family and fromer friends. Alternatively, these characters might simply be cut off from what was once their home, unable to return becasue of the events that precipitated their departure.
[P]Although most exiles long for their past life to some degree. This longing is rarely more than bittersweet. By leaving the past behind, they have freed themselves from what once was and have plunged into a crucible of new adventures that call with an intesity their old life rarely offered. Any one might have to reluctantly leave their home, but the best Seekers are those who leave and never look back.</Description>
    <Source Page="12">Savage Spirits</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SURVIVOR</Key>
    <Name>Survivor</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Survivor[h4]
The lives of Seekers can be about more than just establishing their own path. Some Seekers find themselves directly in the paths of others, whether caight up in galactic turmoil, hunted by deadly predators, or always being in the wrong place at the wrong time. For these intrepid soulds their path is about taking everything the galaxy can throw their way and moving onward in spite of it.
[P]These natural survivors might view themselves as unlucky, or they might be too stubborn to admit any alternative route. A rare few even seek out increasingly difficult challenges through whcih to prove themselves. Whatever the reason for their trials their journey forward forges them into some of the toughest and most determined individuals in the galaxy.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Savage Spirits</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ACTIV</Key>
    <Name>Activist</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Activist[h4]
Many Sentinels start off as activists in some form of another. Even unawaked to the Force, activists find themselves fighting injustice through social and legal pressure. They spread awareness, organize bodies of experts, and push for new laws. on planets that have (or claim to have) progressive rights and equalities, activistswork out in the open—or at least not in hiding. On more oppressive planets, activists work queitly in the shadows but are no less effective. Those who fall to the dark side give in to their rage and desperation, their activism turning destructive for desctruction's sake or even becoming murderous in the name of justice.</Description>
    <Source Page="10">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>QUESTER</Key>
    <Name>Quester</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Quester[h4]
Sometimes, Seekers are not content to bide their time in the fringes of society or to follow the guidence of the Force to hidden wisdom. They might do those things out of necessity, but more often than not, Seekers set their own goals establishing new trails for thei own reasons. Such Seekers, find a reason to go out into the galaxy, whether to wilderness, cityscape, or deep space areas, and track down a new secret, treasure, or target. Then, having found what they were looking for, they set their sights on a new goal. Questing Seekers are always in motion, pushing the boundaries of their lives and the galaxy alike. These Seeker aren't easily defined by their pasts, but rather by the missions they seek out new challenges and the methods by which they pursue them.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Savage Spirits</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>THRILLHUNT</Key>
    <Name>Thrill of the Hunt</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Thrill of the Hunt[h4]
The hunting of sentient beings is said by some to be the most thrilling and treacherous challenge in the galaxy. Though some beasts are more powerful, faster, or more savage than any sentient creature, few kinds of prey are more cunning. For most bounty hunters, the pursuit of targets from world to world and sector to secotr is simply a means to an end. For some, however the hunt is an end unto intself, and the payout for collecting the bounty is simply an added bonus.</Description>
    <Source Page="16">No Disintegrations</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>INITMONEY</Key>
    <Name>In It for the Money</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]In It for the Money[h4]
Bounty hunters are, at their core, exceedingly mercenary. While many bounty hunters may claim to adhere to some higher order or serve a greater good, at the end of the day, they all serve one master—money. Those individuals in the business who have embraced their love of credits may seem crass and avaricious to others, but they are, perhaps, the most honest about their trade.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">No Disintegrations</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>LAWBRINGER</Key>
    <Name>Lawbringer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Lawbringer[h4]
Law and order is not typically the first thing that comes to mind when considering the bounty hunting trade. Most galactic citzens, when they consider bounty hunters at all, imagine freewheeling loose cannons who skirt the edge of the law, useful only in desperate situations to capture difficult fugitives. While this is largely the case, there are some among the profession for whom  the rule of law is sacrosanct. These hunters consider themselves extensions of legitimate law enforcement or, in some cases. agents of justice in an unjust galaxy.</Description>
    <Source Page="16">No Disintegrations</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>DESUND</Key>
    <Name>Desire for Understanding</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Desire for Understanding[h4]

Having realized he has some untapped power at his disposal, the character now wishes to know what this power is. Simple research on his home planet or via the HoloNet has yielded nothing, so he must set out into the wider galaxy to see what he can learn about his odd abilities..
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ACADEMIC</Key>
    <Name>Academic</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Academic[h4]
      For the student who seeks history, science, and other knowledge beyond the halls of academia, the stars can be an undeniable siren's song. First-hand experience can mean the difference between theoretical knowledge and true understanding, and the academic who understands the importance of the latter is the true master of his field.

[P]True exploration requires an appreciation for all that is already known, as well as a desire to add to that knowledge. An Explorer with a strong foundation in academia is armed with the knowledge to see himself and his team safely through many situations in which ignorance is a lethal failing. Big guns, fast ships, and all the credits in the galaxy cannot overcome a problem if there isn't sufficient understanding of what the problem is.

[P]Most academics learn quickly that life out in the Rim requires adaptation and versatility. One learns how to fight, how to survive, and many other skills as necessary if he doesn't want to end up a footnote in someone's journal. One also learns to make the right kinds of friends, trading knowledge for protection and expertise for mutual benefit.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Enter the Unknown</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>BORNNBRED</Key>
    <Name>Born and Bred</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Born and Bred[h4]
  Some Smugglers have never been anything else. They may come from a long line of Smugglers. They may not know where they came from, but were forced into the life of a Smuggler before they were old enough to make a decision for themselves. Either way, smuggling is all this Smuggler knows, and he does it well.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>CRIMINAL</Key>
    <Name>Criminal</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Criminal[h4]
The reasons for pursuing a life of crime are as varied as the types of crime one can commit. Some are born into it. Some find it the only way to survive. Some are anxious to grab the "quick score" rather than work for a living. Some pursue crime as a way of life, understanding that it is a profession like any other and indeed one that requires immense skill and a little luck.

[P]Naturally, the farther one travels from the center of Imperial power, the easier a life of criminal activity can be. Criminals may well become Explorers due to sheer necessity, mastering the skills and talents required to find places to hide, ways to pursue their agendas, and means to survive and thrive.

[P]Additionally, the life of a criminal is not often one that is consciously chosen; instead, it is thrust upon a person because he has a horrible streak of bad luck, winding up in the wrong place at the wrong time. Grasping at any means of survival is the natural response, yet it can be nearly impossible to escape the life of a criminal once that path is chosen.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="13">Stay on Target</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>CYNIC</Key>
    <Name>Cynical</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Cynical[h4]
   Some of the most prized possessions of a Smuggler are the stories he can tell, both tales of his exploits and rumors he has heard on his travels. The cynical Smuggler has one definitive story: the moment that not only changed the course of his life but his whole view of the galaxy. Due to a traumatic even, this Smuggler carries a big chip on his shoulder. He's lost faith in law, order, or people in general. In a galaxy of infinite possibilities, this event could be anything from the destruction of his homeworld to a personal betrayal.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>DISADV</Key>
    <Name>Disadvantaged</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Disadvantaged[h4]
      For most beings in the galaxy, life is a constant battle for survival. Whether on a planet under strict Imperial rule or some backwater moon far from any trade route, the career of a Smuggler becomes an attractive prospect, a way of exchanging the familiar daily struggle for a life full of potential. Work as a Smuggler is not easy, but the dream of one great score to set him up forever keeps him running the hyperlanes.

[P]The Smuggler with a disadvantage background is tough and a little rough around the edges. He may have lived in poverty, been a slave, worked for an oppressive employer, or otherwise had it hard growing up.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ENEMIES</Key>
    <Name>Enemies and Antagonists</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Enemies and Antagonists[h4]
Simply put, the character rubbed someone the wrong way and found himself fleeing his former life. Even if the player decides that the enemy may not be the source of an Obligation, or may not be around any more to cause the character grief, this could be used as a hook to reintroduce the enemy later on in a campaign.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="38">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="38">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ENTREPRENEUR</Key>
    <Name>Entrepreneur</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Entrepreneur[h4]
The galaxy is overflowing with opportunities for those willing to search for them. The best of those opportunities - especially for someone with more imagination than money - can be found far from the galactic center, where societies and technology are still developing.

[P]A successful Entrepreneur in the outer reaches will surround himself with a team possessed of various skills. He may have a business plan, or he may simply seize upon whatever jumps out at him as he explores his environment. Regardless, Entrepreneurs who leave the safety and security of the Core Worlds are true pioneers, and they have to be adaptable and quick on their feet to survive, much less to thrive.

[P]The old saying about larger risks being necessary for larger rewards holds especially true for the Entrepreneur who explores opportunities in the far corners of the galaxy. Of course, without a great deal of luck and a few allies, the penalty for failure can be quite lethal.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Enter the Unknown</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>EXIMP</Key>
    <Name>Ex-Imperial Operator</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Ex-Imperial Operator[h4]
The Empire's bureaucracy and its military employ billions of beings. The vast majority are happy with their lot in life, even under the harsh rule of the Emperor.

[P]Yet there are plenty who, for one reason or another, find themselves departed from their service. Some are simply fired. Others leave Imperial service hoping for something more. More than a few find reasons to escape serving the Empire because their freedom, or even their very lives, depend on it.

[P]The safety of such a move depends a great deal upon what kind of role the character played within the Empire before his departure. A minor functionary with little access to important information will probably be able to simply quit or resign, moving on to private pursuits. Someone who knows where bodies are buried and who did what to whom as the Empire rose to power, however, may find his way out very difficult indeed.</Description>
    <Source Page="16">Enter the Unknown</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>EXMILITARY</Key>
    <Name>Ex-Military</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Ex-Military[h4]
The galaxy is full of armies, from numerous planetary defense forces to the awesome might of the Imperial Military. Countless millions of sentients fight in the ranks of these forces, but countless more have served their time and left the military. While some manage the transition back to civilian life, many former soldiers find that their most marketable skill is their fighting ability. For them, mercenary work or even criminal enterprise is a lucrative (if dangerous) career choice.
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="13">Fly Casual</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>FALLENNOBLE</Key>
    <Name>Fallen Noble</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Fallen Noble[h4]
There are millions - perhaps billions - of noble families throughout the galaxy, and quite a few of them have black sheep. An aristocrat with a poor reputation finds life in the Core Worlds difficult, perhaps even impossible. The outer reaches offer opportunities for redemption, or at least a chance to start over, for the noble who needs to escape scandal or worse.

[P]Nobles rarely have to pursue any kind of profession. Many, however, enjoy various hobbies and intellectual pursuits, which they invariably learn how to parley into an actual occupation once forced out of their comfortable lifestyles. Naturally, a noble may have to engage in a great deal of on-the-job training to really understand his pursuits. Necessity can be a wonderful motivator in such circumstances.

[P]Whether others even know if one is a noble has a lot to do with the measures he takes to maintain that secret. He may decide that being open about it will somehow give him advantages when dealing with others. If he's smart, however, he will likely go out of his way to suppress that part of his background, preferring to avoid attention on his troubled past.</Description>
    <Source Page="16">Enter the Unknown</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>OPP</Key>
    <Name>Opportunity Knocks</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Opportunity Knocks[h4]
The simplest reason for a character to live on the fringes of society is the basic desire to grasp some opportunity or challenge oneself. A character from a hard, poor background may strive to better himself and jumps at the first chance to improve his lot. A well-off character may be bored with the steady rhythms of high society or realizes that his chances for advancement must come from his own hard work rather than waiting for things to occur. Lastly, this could be as simple as making a spur of the moment decision to board a starship bound for some far-flung part of the galaxy.</Description>
    <Source Page="37">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="37">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>PEACETURNEDTOWAR</Key>
    <Name>Peace Turned To War</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Peace Turned To War[h4]
While many Hired Guns get their start in some sort of violent enterprise, not all mercenaries or marauders begin their lives as warriors. Some spent a great deal of their lives in an honest career or some other peaceful labor, before some pivotal event set them on the path to become the hardened veteran they are today. Whatever that event was, the character's personality is still defined by the work he did beforehand.

    </Description>
    <Source Page="15">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>PRIV</Key>
    <Name>Privileged</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Privileged[h4]
     Whether wealth is won, earned or inherited some people just have a lot more credits than anyone else. However, bad luck, poor choices in trade, or extravagant lifestyle can quickly turn a rich person into a poor one. Some Smugglers have lived the good life but lost everything. Some may have even purposefully left wealth behind, tired of the strings attached or dreaming of a life of adventure and glory.

[P]The Smuggler who has known wealth, whether he frittered it away or had it forcibly taken, is not likely to have lost his privileged attitude.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>RESPECT</Key>
    <Name>Respectable</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Respectable[h4]
It's entirely possible for a merchant to spend his whole career transporting and selling legal goods while keeping on the right side of the law, but sometimes laws change and he cannot or will not change with them. Or he might lose legitimate business and need to expand his client base to stay afloat. Either way, it is easy for a respectable trader to turn to smuggling.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SCIONOFALEGACY</Key>
    <Name>Scion of a Legacy</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Scion of a Legacy[h4]
One of the most powerful motivations in a character's life can be his parents or other mentors. Many children follow in the footsteps of their fathers or mothers, even if they do so because that is what is expected of them. However, living up to the reputation of an elder can be difficult even when that is what the character desires most. At some point the character's own life, personality, and morality might come in conflict with the reputation of his forebears, and he must change himself or break with the past.

    </Description>
    <Source Page="15">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>AVENGER</Key>
    <Name>The Avenger</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Avenger[h4]
Some say a man who seeks vengeance should dig two graves: one for his target, and one for himself. However, these words never seem to reach the beings who need to hear it most. Following the one that wronged him, this character is in pursuit of righteous vengeance, leaving everything else he knew and loved behind. He lives a life of quiet desperation, planning his revenge and stalking his prey. The character does what he has to do to survive until he delivers retribution. He is proud to wield a blaster for any employer, especially if that gets him closer to his goal.

[P]Characters with this backstory should consider choosing their Obligation (with GM approval) instead of rolling randomly, so that it aligns with their background. Alternately, they can tie their Motivation into their background instead.

    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="14">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
      <Source Page="12">Forged in Battle</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>FUGITIVE</Key>
    <Name>The Fugitive</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Fugitive[h4]
The galaxy is full of those on the run from something or someone. Some people may be pursued by bounty hunters, while others may be fleeing local governments, corporations, or even the Empire. Many of these people are guilty of their accused crimes, while others are innocent victims of a miscarriage of justice. In either case, colonies provide a safe haven where a person can hide, reinvent themselves, and start over in life.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>GRIZZ</Key>
    <Name>The Grizzled Settler</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Grizzled Settler[h4]
     This character usually began as a young idealist, perhaps newly married. He decided the best opportunity for his family were in starting over somewhere new, where the sweat off his back could build something lasting. Unfortunately, life on the frontier is hard, and what starts as a dream for the future can quickly turn sour as children succumb to exotic diseases or local wildlife, leaving some settlers stranded with nothing to live for. The grizzled settler has lived through the worst the planet has to offer, and if asked, takes a pessimistic view of any enterprise— if he does more than spit in response.
</Description>
    <Source Page="12">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>IDEALIST</Key>
    <Name>The Idealist</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Idealist[h4]
      Many Colonists are exiles from more populous worlds, fleeing armed foes or haunting memories. Other Colonists, though, leave the Core Worlds not out of necessity or fear, but with more selfless intentions. The Outer Rim is home to countless settlements of sentients, and many of them are plagued by political instability, impoverished, or oppressed by local powers. From mining colonies threatened by pirates to worlds wracked by plagues brought by careless travelers, the point of light in the vast darkness of untamed space are threatened by many problems unknown in the Core.

[P] Most natives of the Core Worlds would not consider anything as radical as leaving the comfort of their everyday routines to aid individuals they have never laid eyes on before. Apart from the discomfort of leaving familiar surroundings, the Outer Rim can be extremely dangerous. Still, some individuals feel the inexorable pull of empathy urging them to leave their homes and routines to help their fellow sentients, while others see rendering such aid as a matter of duty, a personal debt to society that must be repaid to those less fortunate than themselves. Each individual has unique motives, but it is certain that there are many idealists to be found amongst those who strike out beyond the Core.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>LOCLEAD</Key>
    <Name>The Local Leader</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Local Leader[h4]
     Many colonies, especially the smaller ones, contain a core cadre of prominent individuals. These business-people, ranchers, professionals, and other citizens in good standing have a strong influence on a local community. A small colony might lack an established political system or authoritative central government. Instead, these local leaders step in to fill the void, doing what they can to keep their community running smoothly.
</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>OPPOR</Key>
    <Name>The Opportunist</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Opportunist[h4]
     Founding a colony is hard work, but a generation or two later, when the hardest work is done but opportunity still abounds, the opportunist moves in with fresh resources. These characters are often looked down upon by already established families, especially those opportunists seeking a leadership position before the landing ramp is even fully extended. There are also colonies with corporate or Imperial interests, where a bureaucrat offworld might send in new leadership that has minimal experience. Opportunists are, at their core, enthusiastic and willing to take any risk, but often lack a key understanding of the beings they intend to influence. In truth, this understanding can only come with time.</Description>
    <Source Page="11">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>WANDERER</Key>
    <Name>Wanderer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Wanderer[h4]
Curiosity? Boredom? Tragic circumstances? A desire for something more? Whatever it is that drives someone to wander away from his home and set out among the stars, it must be a powerful force to overcome the fear of the unknown. Most beings are simply overwhelmed by the sheer vastness of the galaxy, much less the uncountable dangers they must face each day as they ramble across the hyperlanes from planet to planet. The hardy soul who does so merely because he is drawn to is either exceptionally brave or a touch mad. Perhaps he is both.
</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="18">Enter the Unknown</Source>
      <Source Page="15">Savage Spirits</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>WRONG</Key>
    <Name>Wrong Place, Wrong Time</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Wrong Place, Wrong Time[h4]
The character finds himself embroiled in a life of adventure through no fault of his own. He could have been captured by pirates, the sole survivor of a deadly plague, or even something as mundane as being unemployed and forced to find some new way to bring in the credits. Regardless of the method for the character's push from society, he finds it nearly impossible to return to the way that things used to be. The character must quickly adapt to his new and dangerous situation.
</Description>
    <Source Page="38">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="38">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>YESTERDAYSHERO</Key>
    <Name>Yesterday's Hero</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Yesterday's Hero[h4]
 Once this character was the man of the hour, toasted in every shadowport from Kothlis to Nar Shaddaa. However, everything in this life passes in time, and whether through the machinations of a political enemy, the natural ebb and flow of popularity, or a legitimate mistake or miscalculation, the character has now fallen from grace. Where he once commanded legions, now he only commands the blaster at his hip. Where once he had limitless resources, now he scrounges for credits, his days of glory a distant and probably bitter memory. Regaining his former success might be his overriding goal, but it is just as possible that the character has given up on himself and simply wishes to avoid any reminders of his past.
</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
</Hooks>