<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<VehActions>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>ACCDEC</Key>
    <Name>Accelerate/Decelerate</Name>
    <Description>The pilot may increase or decrease the ship or vehicle's current speed by one, to a minimum of zero or a maximum of the ship's maximum speed rating.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="232">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="245">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="238">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>true</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>FLYDRIVE</Key>
    <Name>Fly/Drive</Name>
    <Description>This starship maneuver reflects the simple act of moving the ship or vehicle closer or further away from something at its current speed. The number of starship maneuvers required for a ship or vehicle to move through a given number of range bands is dependent on its speed. It is important to remember that range is based on the moving ship's perspective, and is not a measure of actual physical distance. Moving between one range band and the next always takes two maneuvers regardless of speed, with the following exceptions detailed below:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[B]Speed 0:[b] The ship or vehicle is not moving and cannot use this starship maneuver until it accelerates. 
&lt;li&gt;[B]Speed 1:[b] One starship maneuver to move within close range of a target or object, or two starship maneuvers to move from close to short range or from short range to close range. 
&lt;li&gt;[B]Speed 2-4:[b] One starship maneuver to move within close range of a target or object, to move from close to short range, or from short to close range. Two starship maneuvers to move from close to medium, or medium to close range. 
&lt;li&gt;[B]Speed 5-6:[b] One starship maneuver to move within close range of a target or object, to move from close to medium range, or from medium to close range. Two starship maneuvers to move from close to long, or long to close range.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="232">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="245">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="238">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>true</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>EVASMAN</Key>
    <Name>Evasive Maneuvers</Name>
    <Description>Evasive Maneuvers reflects a pilot's efforts to avoid incoming fire, collision, or other calamity. Executing Evasive Maneuvers upgrades the difficulty of the dice pool once for all attacks made against the ship until the end of the pilot's next turn. While this makes the ship executing the starship maneuver harder to hit, it also makes it harder for the ship executing the starship maneuver to hit anything else. Executing Evasive Maneuvers likewise upgrades the difficulty of the dice pool once for all attacks made by the ship until the end of the pilot's next turn. Evasive Maneuvers can only be undertaken by ships or vehicles of silhouette 4 or lower. Anything larger is typically too slow or awkward to perform Evasive Maneuvers.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="232">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="245">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="238">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>true</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>4</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>3</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Active>true</Active>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>STAY</Key>
    <Name>Stay on Target</Name>
    <Description>This reflects a pilot's concentration and his ability to shut out combat-related stresses and distractions to make sure a target is hit or an adversary destroyed. Until the end of the pilot's next turn, all combat checks from the vehicle or vessel executing this maneuver upgrade the Ability dice in their pool once. Unfortunately, while he is concentrating so hard on his target, the pilot blocks out all other threats and is an easier target for opponents. Any combat checks made targeting a ship executing this starship maneuver upgrades the Ability dice in their pool once until the end of the pilot's next round. This starship maneuver is restricted to small vessels like starfighters and patrol boats, and only ships or vehicles of silhouette 4 or lower can Stay on Target.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="233">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="245">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="239">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>true</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>4</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>3</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Active>true</Active>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>PUNCH</Key>
    <Name>Punch It</Name>
    <Description>This maneuver allows a ship or vehicle to go immediately to its maximum speed rating from any other speed, mostly by throwing the throttles to maximum and overloading the ship or vehicle's drives. While expeditious, it also puts undue strain on a ship or vehicle. When executing this starship maneuver, the ship or vehicle suffers one point of system strain for every point of speed between the ship's current speed and its maximum speed. 

[P]For example, the pilot of a YT-1300 light freighter is hiding from an Imperial navy patrol at speed 0 in the lee of a large asteroid. Suddenly he is set upon by a pair of TIE Fighters, decides that discretion is the better part of valor, and Punches It. He immediately throws his throttles to their maximum setting and the ship jumps to life. While he escapes unharmed and is able to jump to hyperspace, the sudden acceleration causes three points of strain to his ship. 

[P]This starship maneuver is restricted to ships of silhouette 4 or lower, as larger vessels have too much mass to accelerate so quickly.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="233">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="246">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="239">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>true</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>4</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>ANGLEDEF</Key>
    <Name>Angle Deflector Shields</Name>
    <Description>Using this maneuver, a crewmember with access to the shield controls can reassign up to one point of Defense from one defense zone to another. For example, a player could shore up a vessel's forward defense zone with a point from its aft defense zone. This maneuver only works if the ship or vehicle had defense that can be reassigned, as with deflector shield.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="233">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="246">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="239">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>MECHINCPOW</Key>
    <Name>Increase Power</Name>
    <Description>Normally, the engines on a starfighter are optimized for speed and maneuverability. As a maneuver, an astromech can reconfigure this balance for a short period of time, routing additional power to the engines from other systems. This is useful when straight-line speed over maneuverability is needed, especially when trying to escape the Empire's fastest ships, or when the engines have suffered damage and the extra speed is needed simply to keep up. While risky, and hard on the ship, this extra boost of speed can make the difference between life and death. When an astromech performs Increase Power, the ship takes 2 system strain, and increases the ship's top speed by 1 for a number of turns equal the astromech's Intellect. The drawback is that this move reduces the craft's handling by 2, and the astromech may not perform a [B]Boot Shields[b] action in the same turn. Pilots should note that this maneuver can be combined with the Full Throttle talent, allowing an X-wing to briefly match the speed of an A-Wing!

[P]Multiple uses of Increase Power on the same ship do not stack.</Description>
    <Source Page="72">Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>3</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Active>true</Active>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>BLANKBARR</Key>
    <Name>Blanket Barrage</Name>
    <Description>The gunner uses the ship's weapons to raise a curtain of fire around the ship, protecting it from starfighters. Any smaller vessel attempting an attack run will have to brave a hurricane of heavy weaponry. 

[P]When performing the Blanket Barrage action, the character makes an [B]Average ([DI][DI]) Gunnery check[b] and selects all weapons of a single type (heavy turbolasers, medium ion cannons, etc.) within one or more of his ship's firing arcs. Those weapons count as firing that round. Until the end of the character's next turn, all vehicles with silhouette 4 or smaller upgrade the difficulty of any combat checks made against the ship once, plus one additional time per [AD][AD] scored on the Blanket Barrage Gunnery check. If their combat check generates [TH][TH], they suffer one automatic hit, which deals half the base damage (rounding up) of the type of weapon used in the Blanket Barrage action. If their combat check generates [DE], they suffer one automatic hit dealing the base damage of the type of weapon used in the Blanket Barrage action. 

[P]At the GM's discretion, the Blanket Barrage might not cover all arcs of the ship (if the ship has no aft weaponry, for example, it may leave an opening aft), and some ships might be able to approach from this direction and avoid suffering the penalties from Blanket Barrage.</Description>
    <Source Page="246">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>5</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>3</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>GUNN</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>CONCBARR</Key>
    <Name>Concentrated Barrage</Name>
    <Description>The gunner directs the vehicle's fire to focus on a precise point on the opponent's hull. Focusing fire in this way has the potential to deal significant damage. 

[P]When performing the Concentrated Barrage action, the character fires all weapons of a single type (heavy turbolasers, medium ion cannons, etc.) within a single firing arc. This action requires at least two weapons to use, and it cannot be used if there are not two weapons of a single type in the chosen firing arc. Although he is firing multiple weapons, he makes a single combat check, as per the rules for the Performing a Combat Check with Vehicle Weapons action. If the attack succeeds, the character may spend [AD] once to add damage equal to the number of weapons involved in the attack to one hit of the attack.

[P]The Concentrated Barrage action can only be used to target ships with a silhouette 5 or higher.</Description>
    <Source Page="246">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>5</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>3</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>GUNN</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>OVERBARR</Key>
    <Name>Overwhelming Barrage</Name>
    <Description>The gunner disperses the vehicles fire to overwhelm the target with a multitude of shots, hitting it and every adjoining vehicle. This tactic is often used to overwhelm formations of enemy ships and vehicles. 
[P]When performing the Overwhelming Barrage action, the character fires all weapons of a single type (heavy turbolasers, medium ion cannons, etc.) within a single firing arc. This action requires at least two weapons to use, and cannot be used if there are not two weapons of a single type in the chosen firing arc. Although he is firing multiple weapons, he makes a single combat check, as per the rules for the [B]Performing a Combat Check with Vehicle Weapons action[b]. If the attack succeeds, the character may spend [AD] to deal one additional hit to one vehicle that is at short range from the original target, plus one additional vehicle for every 10 weapons involved in the attack. Vehicles hit in this way must have a silhouette equal to or higher than that of the original target. For example, firing 10 weapons allows the attacker to hit two additional targets with [AD], firing 20 weapons allows him to hit three additional targets, and so on. The extra hit can be triggered multiple times, but cannot target any ships that have already been hit during this action.

[P]These hits deal the weapon's base damage, + 1 damage per [SU] on the check.</Description>
    <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>5</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>3</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>GUNN</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>DAMCONT</Key>
    <Name>Damage Control</Name>
    <Description>This action is an attempt to mitigate some of the stress caused to a vehicles systems through combat or accident. In general, PCs can only attempt one Damage Control check to reduce hull trauma (one 
per success) per encounter. The difficulty of the Mechanics check is determined by the strain the ship is currently suffering. Damage Control can be attempted as many times as needed to reduce a ship's system strain to zero (with the caveat that a single character can still only perform one action per turn, of course).

[P]Likewise, a skilled mechanic can even repair some of the damage dealt to a vehicle during an ongoing fight, although this is much trickier. In general, PCs can only attempt one Damage Control check to reduce hull trauma per encounter (there are only so many repairs that can be accomplished without the facilities of a proper shipyard). In addition, the GM is the final arbitrator as to whether a Player Character can attempt repairs of hull trauma at all (a snubfighter pilot could not climb out of his cockpit during a dogfight to patch his wing, nor could a speeder biker re-attach one of his control surfaces while driving through a forest). 

[P]Characters can also use this action to repair Critical Hits the ship is suffering from. The difficulty of repairing a Critical Hit is listed on [B]Table 7-9 : Critical Hit Result.[b] Checks to repair Critical Hits can be attempted multiple times, until the Critical Hit is repaired.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="233">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="247">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="240">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Skills>
      <Key>MECH</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>GAINADV</Key>
    <Name>Gain the Advantage</Name>
    <Description>This action reflects the constant, frantic give-and-take of a dogfight between small craft like star-fighters and patrol boats or high-speed vehicles such as airspeeders. It allows a pilot to gain the upper hand on a single opponent so that he positions himself for a better attack during the following round. To execute this starship action, the pilot makes a [B]Piloting check[b], the difficulty of which is determined by the relative speeds of the ships or vehicles involved in the attack. These difficulties are outlined in [B]Table 7-3 : Speed Advantage Difficulty.[b] If the check succeeds, the pilot ignores all penalties imposed by his own and his opponent's use of the Evasive Maneuvers starship maneuver until the end of the following round. In addition, the pilot also chooses which defense zone he hits with his attack. If he fails his check, he fails to gain the advantage from the attempt and still suffers the effects of any Evasive Maneuvers. 

[P]Once the advantage has been gained, on the following turn, the opponent may attempt to cancel out the advantage by using Gain the Advantage as well. This works as described earlier, but his check is one step more difficult for each time he or his opponent has successfully Gained the Advantage against the other.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="234">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="247">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="240">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>true</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>4</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>4</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Active>true</Active>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <Skills>
      <Key>PILOTPL</Key>
      <Key>PILOTSP</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>COMBAT</Key>
    <Name>Combat Check with Weapon</Name>
    <Description>This is similar to the Perform a Combat Check action on page 204, with some minor differences as to how it is implemented because of the differences between vehicles and individuals. For this reason, the steps to perform a combat check are repeated, with the differences written in each step; instead of the differences being listed without context. 

[P]Each weapon on a starship or vehicle may only be fired a maximum of once per round unless a rule specifically allows otherwise.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="234">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="249">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>PLOTCOURSE</Key>
    <Name>Plot Course</Name>
    <Description>The crewmember studies the terrain ahead and plots a course that should take the vehicle safely through it. On a successful check, each success reduces the [SE] suffered for difficult terrain by 1.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>ASTRO</Key>
      <Key>PERC</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>COPILOT</Key>
    <Name>Copilot</Name>
    <Description>The crewmember serves as the vehicle's copilot, managing systems and auxiliary equipment to allow the pilot to focus on flying or driving. On a successful check, each success downgrades the difficulty of the pilot's next piloting check by 1.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>PILOTPL</Key>
      <Key>PILOTSP</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>JAM</Key>
    <Name>Jamming</Name>
    <Description>The crewmember uses the vehicle's systems to jam the communications of enemy vehicles. On a successful check, the enemy most make a [B]Average ([DI][DI]) Computers check[b] to use their communication systems. The difficulty increases by one for each additional [SU][SU], and the jamming affects an additional target for each [AD] spent.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>COMP</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>BOOSTSHIELD</Key>
    <Name>Boost Shields</Name>
    <Description>The crewmember re-routes power from other systems to boost the defensive systems a vehicle. This only works if a vehicle already has a defense rating. On a successful check, the vehicle suffers 1 system strain, and increases the defense of one defense zone by one until the beginning of his next turn. Additional [SU] increase the duration by one round per [SU].</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>MECH</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>MANREP</Key>
    <Name>Manual Repairs</Name>
    <Description>In some cases, repairs can be as simple as a sturdy metal plate welded over a damaged system. If the GM allows and the crewmember has the proper tools for the job, they can attempt to use the Damage Control action with Athletics rather than Mechanics. If successful, they may remove one point of hull trauma from the ship, plus one additional point for each additional [SU][SU]. Remember, this follows the limitations to Damage Control, and thus may only be attempted once per encounter.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>ATHL</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>FIREDISC</Key>
    <Name>Fire Discipline</Name>
    <Description>The crewmember forgoes fighting to analyze the opponents' tactics and direct his fellows to greater accuracy with their weapons fire. If successful, the next crewmember firing a weapon aboard the ship can add [BO] his check. Each additional [SU][SU] grants this to an additional crewmember. In addition. the crewmember may spend [AD][AD][AD] to allow every hit from shipboard weapons to inflict 1 system strain on their target as well as regular damage until the beginning of his next turn as the carefully timed shots pummel shields and overload systems.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>DISC</Key>
      <Key>LEAD</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>SCANENEMY</Key>
    <Name>Scan the Enemy</Name>
    <Description>The crewmember uses the ship's scanners to study the enemy. If successful, he learns what weapons the ship has, any modifications, and their system strain and hull trauma thresholds. If he spends [AD][AD] he can also learn their current system strain and hull trauma levels.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>PERC</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>SLICE</Key>
    <Name>Slice Enemy's Systems</Name>
    <Description>The crewmember uses powerful shipboard computers to attempt to disrupt the systems of an enemy vehicle. If successful, he reduces the defense of one zone on the target vehicle for one round per [SU]. A [TR] may be spent to disable a weapon system for one round, and [AD][AD] may be spent to inflict one system strain on the target vehicle.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>COMP</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>SPOOFMISS</Key>
    <Name>Spoof Missiles</Name>
    <Description>The crewmember tracks incoming attacks and uses vehicle systems to disrupt their tracking systems, or even times incoming missiles and drops flares and chaff at the opportune moment. If successful, any attacks against the crewmember's ship or vehicle using weapons with the Guided quality upgrade their difficulty by one (plus an additional upgrade for every additional [AD][AD]) until the start of the crewmember's next turn.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>COMP</Key>
      <Key>VIGIL</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>MECHWATCHBACK</Key>
    <Name>Watch Your Back!</Name>
    <Description>A socketed astromech has direct access to the fighter's scanners and targeting systems, and as such is able to quickly identify threats the pilot may not see. Unlike the pilot, the droid is capable of looking in all directions at once and can warn the pilot of an immediate threat. The astromech performs an [B]Average ([DI][DI]) Computers check[b] to identify and prioritize incoming threats. Each [SU] provides the craft with +1 defense to a single defense zone until the astromech's next turn. One or more [SE] may be added to the check depending on the size and chaos of the dogfight. A single fighter-on-fighter engagement would not add any, while the sheer number of potential threats available in a fleet engagement could add as much as [SE][SE][SE]. </Description>
    <Source Page="73">Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Active>true</Active>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>COMP</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>MECHTARGETLOCK</Key>
    <Name>Target Lock</Name>
    <Description>Beyond defense, an astromech may also use the fighter's scanners and targeting systems to perform a target lock. This is especially useful when a shot absolutely matters, with pilots most often reserving the droid's capabilities for missiles or proton torpedoes. To perform this action, the astromech declares a target, making a Computers check with a difficulty determined by comparing the silhouettes of the astromech's ship and the target ship (use [B]Table 7-5: Silhouette Comparison[b] on page 249 of the [B]Age of Rebellion[b] Core Rulebook). As with [B]Watch Your Back![b] above, add [SE] appropriate to the situation, representing the difficulty of prioritizing multiple targets. 

[P]A successful Target Lock action provides [BO] on the pilot's Gunnery checks against the declared target as well as one additional [BO] for each [SU][SU] beyond the first. The Target Lock remains in place for one round, plus one additional round per [AD][AD] generated on the check. Any [TH] generated indicates the number of turns an astromech must wait before another attempt at Target Lock may be made.</Description>
    <Source Page="73">Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Active>true</Active>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>COMP</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
</VehActions>