<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>ALPHA3VWING</Key>
  <Name>Alpha-3 Nimbus "V-Wing" Interceptor</Name>
  <Description>[H3]Alpha-3 Nimbus "V-Wing" Interceptor[h3]

The antiquated A3-Nimbus short-range interceptor was once the premier interceptor of the Republic Navy. Built in great numbers by Kuat Systems Engineering, the Alpha-3 Nimbus, also known as the V-wing, entered service with the Republic Navy late in the Clone Wars to replace the aging Delta-series interceptors. Faster and lighter than the heavy ARC-170 fighters, Republic Navy V-wings were not only incredibly fast and agile but also remarkably sturdy for such small, lightweight fighters. Similar in appearance and performance to KSE's Delta-7 Aethersprite interceptor, the V-wing has a broad, wedge-shaped hull with a single-position cockpit located far aft on the ship's dorsal side. Blade-shaped, variable geometry wings are mounted on rotating port and starboard hubs just aft of the cockpit, and provides the fighter, along with its advanced vectored thrust system with its impressive maneuverability. While the V-wing has no native hyperspace capabilities, it does feature an astromech droid, the unique Q7 series, to monitor systems and perform light maintenance during flight. 

[P]Although very lightly armored, V-wing interceptors are remarkably sturdy fighters with strong hulls and well-designed power systems that can take inordinate amounts of abuse. Powered by a pair of early model KSE high-output ion engines in an over/under configuration, V-wings are nearly as fast and agile as a modern TIE-series fighter. V-wings served with the Republic Navy until the end of the Clone Wars, and then with the infant Imperial Navy at the beginning of the Empire's rise to power. Soon, however, the first TIE-series fighters were introduced and the entire fleet of V-wings was either scrapped or sold out of the service as surplus.</Description>
  <Source Page="57">Stay on Target</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Starfighter</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <Encumbrance>0</Encumbrance>
  <HP>2</HP>
  <Price>70000</Price>
  <Rarity>7</Rarity>
  <Restricted>false</Restricted>
  <BaseMods />
  <MaxAltitude />
  <HyperdrivePrimary>0</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>0</HyperdriveBackup>
  <StarFighters />
  <NaviComputer>false</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srClose</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one astromech droid</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>5</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>0</Passengers>
  <Consumables>One day</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>4</Speed>
  <Handling>2</Handling>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <DefAft>0</DefAft>
  <DefPort>0</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>0</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>2</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>10</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>8</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <Massive>0</Massive>
  <SinglePilot>true</SinglePilot>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>false</Turret>
      <Location>Wingtip</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>3</Count>
          <Index>0</Index>
          <MiscDesc />
          <DefZone />
          <QualReplace>false</QualReplace>
          <SkillIsCareer>false</SkillIsCareer>
          <SkillIsRanked>false</SkillIsRanked>
          <VehicleWeaponUpgrades />
          <SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>-1</SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>
          <DieModifiers />
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERLT</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>false</Turret>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LIMITEDAMMO</Key>
          <Count>4</Count>
          <Index>0</Index>
          <MiscDesc />
          <DefZone />
          <QualReplace>false</QualReplace>
          <SkillIsCareer>false</SkillIsCareer>
          <SkillIsRanked>false</SkillIsRanked>
          <VehicleWeaponUpgrades />
          <SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>-1</SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>
          <DieModifiers />
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>CML</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
</Vehicle>