<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>ARMDROPSUIT</Key>
  <Name>Armored Drop Suit</Name>
  <Description>[H3]Armored Drop Suit[h3]
Mobility is often a decisive element in any engagement. Combatants from common killers-for-hire to Imperial storrmroopers know that taking a good position and controlling the flow of combat can be better protection than a durasteel blast door. Most armor designs factor this in to some degree, foregoing absolutely maximized plating or coverage to allow normal mobility, but a few suits go above and beyond the concept of allowing “normal mobility.”
[P]Armored drop suits are a type of light laminate body armor constructed around a powerful repulsorift unit,
allowing the wearer to fly between firing positions or
spots of cover, or to rain down attacks from above.
The arrangement of fabric and composite plating of
the armor in such suits minimizes air resistance and
improves maneuverabiIity, while still offering respectable protection against incoming fire.
[P]As a maneuver, the wearer of an armored drop suit
can engage his flight systems to function as a Silhouette 0, Speed 2, Handling + 2, System Strain Threshold 5 vehicle that; requires Piloting [Planetary] to
operate. Further, while the flight systems are engaged
and the wearer is conscious to guide himself down, he
does not suffer damage from falling.
[P][I]Note:  This is the vehicle version of the Armored Drop Suit armor.[i]</Description>
  <Source Page="49">No Disintegrations</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Drop Suit</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Air Vehicle</Category>
  </Categories>
  <Price>7500</Price>
  <Rarity>7</Rarity>
  <BaseMods>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>While conscious and flight systems are engaged, wearer cannot suffer falling damage.</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
  </BaseMods>
  <MaxAltitude>From orbit</MaxAltitude>
  <SensorRangeValue>srNone</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>Armor's wearer</Crew>
  <Silhouette>1</Silhouette>
  <Speed>2</Speed>
  <Handling>2</Handling>
  <SystemStrain>3</SystemStrain>
  <SinglePilot>true</SinglePilot>
  <SensorRange>No Sensors</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>