<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>BTSA2</Key>
  <Name>BTS-A2 "H-Wing" Long-Range Strike Starfighter</Name>
  <Description>[H3]BTS-A2 "H-Wing" Long-Range Strike Starfighter[h3]

A follow-up to Koensayr's wildly successful Y-wing starfighter, the BTS-A2 H-wing is a heavily armed and armored, three-man fighter designed for long-range strike and interdiction missions. Essentially an up-armored and up-gunned Y-wing equipped with modern avionics and fire control systems, the H-wing is a steady, reliable fighter that can punch well above its weight thanks to a broad collection of ordnance and energy weapons. Taking the lessons learned from the production and long life of the venerable Y-wing, the H-wing's hull is a broad, lifting body design with a unique tandem-style cockpit. The port cockpit houses the ship's pilot, while the starboard cockpit houses the two weapon systems operators responsible for the fighter's onboard weap-ons. In addition, a tiny. cramped compartment with a bunk, chemical refresher, and soundproof divider is located aft of the cockpits for use by the crew on long-distance hyperspace jumps. Powered by a pair of Koensayr's relatively new R440 Ion Jet Engines fitted with the company's iconic thrust vectral vanes, the H-wing is remarkably fast for such a heavy fighter. Other systems familiar to V-wing pilots and technicians are used in the H-wing, such as an upgraded version of Fabritech's ANx-Y sensor package and the successor to SubPro's NH-7 comprehensive avionics package. 

[P]The H-wing is very well-suited to its role as a strike/attack starfighter with its diverse array of armaments. The ship's primary weapon is a dorsal turret-mounted Taim &amp; Bak KY12 medium laser cannon which gives the H-wing excellent anti-ship and anti-armor capabilities. Secondary weapon systems include a linked pair of forward-mounted ArMek light ion cannons and two Arakyd flex tube proton torpedo launchers. This versatile loadout, combined with its powerful shields, reliable systems, sturdy construction, and long-range capabilities, make the H-wing perfect for far-ranging patrols, commerce raiding, and solo cruises. 

[P]Although envisioned by Koensayr as a replacement for the aging V-wings in the Rebel arsenal and a heavy-strike counterpart to the new B-wings, widespread use of the H-wing has yet to catch on among the members of the Alliance. While there are a number of reasons to explain the halting adoption of this new fighter, the primary reason is that the H-wing is a large, expensive, and complex new fighter trying to force its way into a niche already filled by two capable and well-liked fighters with established support infrastructure. In addition, very few Rebel installations have the facilities or manpower required to maintain a single H-wing, let alone an entire squadron. As it stands, those few H-wings in Alliance service are used as escorts for freighter-tonvoys and system patrol craft in Rebel-held star systems.</Description>
  <Source Page="55">Stay on Target</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Starfighter</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <Encumbrance>0</Encumbrance>
  <HP>1</HP>
  <Price>225000</Price>
  <Rarity>6</Rarity>
  <Restricted>false</Restricted>
  <BaseMods />
  <MaxAltitude />
  <HyperdrivePrimary>1</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>0</HyperdriveBackup>
  <StarFighters />
  <NaviComputer>true</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srShort</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, two weapon systems operators</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>15</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>1</Passengers>
  <Consumables>One month</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>3</Speed>
  <Handling>-2</Handling>
  <DefFore>2</DefFore>
  <DefAft>1</DefAft>
  <DefPort>0</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>0</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>4</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>15</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>12</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <Massive>0</Massive>
  <SinglePilot>true</SinglePilot>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Port>true</Port>
        <Starboard>true</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>true</Turret>
      <Location>Unspecified</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities />
      <Key>LASERMED</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>false</Turret>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
          <Index>0</Index>
          <MiscDesc />
          <DefZone />
          <QualReplace>false</QualReplace>
          <SkillIsCareer>false</SkillIsCareer>
          <SkillIsRanked>false</SkillIsRanked>
          <VehicleWeaponUpgrades />
          <SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>-1</SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>
          <DieModifiers />
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>IONLT</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>false</Turret>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LIMITEDAMMO</Key>
          <Count>12</Count>
          <Index>0</Index>
          <MiscDesc />
          <DefZone />
          <QualReplace>false</QualReplace>
          <SkillIsCareer>false</SkillIsCareer>
          <SkillIsRanked>false</SkillIsRanked>
          <VehicleWeaponUpgrades />
          <SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>-1</SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>
          <DieModifiers />
        </Quality>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
          <Index>0</Index>
          <MiscDesc />
          <DefZone />
          <QualReplace>false</QualReplace>
          <SkillIsCareer>false</SkillIsCareer>
          <SkillIsRanked>false</SkillIsRanked>
          <VehicleWeaponUpgrades />
          <SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>-1</SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>
          <DieModifiers />
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>PTL</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
</Vehicle>