<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>ETASHUTTLE</Key>
  <Name>Eta-Class Shuttle</Name>
  <Description>[H3]Cygnus Spaceworks [I]Eta[i]-Class Shuttle[h3]
Cygnus Spaceworks' [I]Eta[i]-class shuttles are an excellent combination of utility and performance. The precursors to the Imperial Navy's [I]Lambda[i]-class armed shuttles, [I]Eta[i]-class shuttles were operational decades before the outbreak of the Clone Wars. Similar in constuction to the [I]Lambda[i]-class ships, [I]Eta[i]-class shuttles have cut a striking figure through the spacelanes. They have a narrow, rectangular hull that is surprisingly spacious within, with enough space for six passengers, their baggage, ship's stores, and even a pair of small, stowable emergency speeder bikes.
[P]The small, spherical flight deck is nearly all transparisteel, giving the pilot and co-pilot excellent visibility aroudn the ship. A tall vertical stabilizer is mounted to the hull's dorasl side, and two matching, variable-pitch S-foils similar to the [I]Lambda[i]'s are mounted port and starboard. Propulstion is provided by four CSW Mk .VIII Shrike Major ion engines tuned for long-range efficiencey, and the hsips carry respectable shields and defensive armament.
[P]Throughout the decades, these small utility vessels saw service primarily with the Galactic Senate and the Republic Ambassadorial Corps  shuttling VIPs about on importan business. Throughout their service they gained a reputation as solid, reliable little ships that, while not particularly large or well-appointed, were comfortable and perfectly suited for their mission. During the Clone Wars, the Jedi Order used many of these ships to shuttle Jedi operatives on both public and clandestine missions throughout the galaxy.
[P][I]Eta[i]-class shuttle have been increasing in rarity, with their numbers dwindling each year. Production shut down long ago, and the tooling and assembly lines were converted to class vessels as well as Xg-1 Star Wing fighters. Many were lost through attrition, hard usage, accident, or abandonment on Outer Rim planets by their Jedi Users. Those that are left, are typically used by small transport companies or budget minded private survey teams.
[P][B]Undicurs Aboard:[b] [I]Eta[i]-class shuttles can carry up to four Undicur jumpspeeders in addition to its listed encumbrance and passenger capacities. Thow of these speeder bikes are included as part of the ship's standard purchase price.</Description>
  <Sources>
    <Source Page="61">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Source Page="72">Rise of the Separatists</Source>
  </Sources>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Shuttle</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Non-Fighter Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>2</HP>
  <Price>100000</Price>
  <Rarity>6</Rarity>
  <BaseMods>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>[B]Undicurs Aboard[b]: Two Undicur Jumpspeeders are included with purchase.  [I]Eta[i]-class shuttles can carry up to four.</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
  </BaseMods>
  <HyperdrivePrimary>2</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>12</HyperdriveBackup>
  <NaviComputer>true</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srShort</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one co-pilot</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>100</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>10</Passengers>
  <Consumables>Two months</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>4</Silhouette>
  <Speed>3</Speed>
  <DefFore>2</DefFore>
  <DefAft>1</DefAft>
  <Armor>3</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>17</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>12</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>2</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERLT</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <SensorRange>Short</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>