<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>JADTHULAND</Key>
  <Name>Jadthu-Class Landing Ship</Name>
  <Description>[H3][I]Jadthu[i]-class Landing Ship[h3]
Possibly one of the most heavily armored troop carriers ever developed, the [I]Jadthu[i]-class landing ship was once the premier lander of the Grand Army of the Republic. Developed by Republic Sienar Systems from a licensed Incom design, [I]Jadthu[i]-class landers were first acquired by the GAR in the years leading up to the Clone Wars. They were initially classed as short-range heavy strategic lift vessels. The first Jadthus delivered to the GAR were equipped with modular cargo holds and various freight-handling systems. Lacking hyperdrives and navicomputers, they were relegated to in-system hauling and occasional transatmospheric freight delivery. As the Republic geared up for its war against the  Separatists, however, GAR brass ordered a number of modifications to turn the big, sturdy vessels into orbital dropships for the newly deployed clone army.
[P]In their new role as combat dropships, the [I]Jadthu[i]-class landers underwent a massive combat retrofit. Their blocky, trapezoidal hulls were reinforced to better withstand transatmospheric operations and then covered in thick starship armor that could shrug off even the heaviest weapons. Freight-handling systems were removed, and the Jadthu's cargo holds were modified to carry a mix of troops, equipment, and light vehicles. Power plants and engines were upgraded to military spec, which gave the heavy ships a blistering straight-line speed, and they were equipped wilh defensive laser turrets and physical countermeasure systems, such as the Arakyd Industries Caltrop-5 Chaff Gun, to protect them from enemy fighters and gunboats. All these modifications made for a ship that could enter the hottest landing zones, deploy its troops, and retreat safely to orbit while under heavy fire.
[P]After serving for years during the Clone Wars, the [I]Jadthu[i]-class was mothballed by the nascent Imperial Navy in favor of more  modern Sienar Fleet Systems designs. Before they could all be  scrapped, many of these vessels found their way into unauthorized hands as they were stolen from breaking yards or storage docks. Today, the [I]Jadthu[i]-class has found a new home delivering troops for the Rebel Alliance as well as for certain mercenary and criminal organizations.</Description>
  <Source Page="60">Knights of Fate</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Landing Ship</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>2</HP>
  <Price>200000</Price>
  <Rarity>5</Rarity>
  <BaseMods>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>[B]Caltrop-5 Chaff Gun[b]: Upgrades difficulty of Gunnery checks and checks triggered by Guided quality made using missiles, rockets, or torpedoes targetting  starship once.  Upgrades difficulty of Piloting for other ships within close range once. [DE] on Piloting checks can inflict a Critical Hit on the pilot's ship.</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
  </BaseMods>
  <SensorRangeValue>srShort</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one co-pilot, one loadmaster, one loadmaster's assistant, one engineer</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>800</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>60</Passengers>
  <Consumables>Two days</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>5</Silhouette>
  <Speed>3</Speed>
  <Handling>-3</Handling>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <DefPort>1</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>1</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>5</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>30</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>15</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Port>true</Port>
        <Starboard>true</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>true</Dorsal>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Dorsal</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERHVY</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Port>true</Port>
        <Starboard>true</Starboard>
        <Ventral>true</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Ventral</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERHVY</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <SensorRange>Short</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>