<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>LAVRQH7</Key>
  <Name>LAVR QH-7 Chariot Command Speeder</Name>
  <Description>[H3]LAVR QH-7 Chariot Command Speeder[h3]

The LAVr QH-7 is a combination staff car, VIP transport,
and command, comms, and control speeder
used by the Imperial armed forces. Designed and
built by Uulshos Manufacturing, the Chariot, as it’s
colloquially known, provides an officer and staff with
a fast, agile, relatively well-armed and armored vehicle
from which to observe and guide events on the
battlefield. Within its wedge-shaped hull, the Chariot
mounts a powerful sensor and comms array, a continuous
orbital data uplink, and numerous electronic
counter-measure and counter-countermeasure systems.
The hull is heavily shielded against electronic
attack and disruption caused by ion weapons, and it
features a number of redundant systems that make
the vehicle exceptionally difficult to neutralize, short of completely destroying it.
[P]For non-electronic defense, the vehicle carries respectable
anti-splinter and anti-small arms armor, and it
mounts a light laser cannon in a retractable ventral turret.
The armor, combined with the vehicle’s sloping,
angular hull and low profile, make the Chariot a remarkably
tricky target to hit. Despite their respectable
defenses, Chariots are rarely seen on the front lines.
Instead, they are typically used to move quickly about a
battlefield, appearing wherever and whenever they are
needed at strategically important points to provide assistance,
or to whisk officers away from dangerous areas.</Description>
  <Source Page="51">Lead by Example</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Landspeeder</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Land Vehicle</Category>
  </Categories>
  <Encumbrance>0</Encumbrance>
  <HP>2</HP>
  <Price>40000</Price>
  <Rarity>5</Rarity>
  <Restricted>true</Restricted>
  <BaseMods />
  <WeaponModifiers />
  <MaxAltitude />
  <HyperdrivePrimary>0</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>0</HyperdriveBackup>
  <StarFighters />
  <NaviComputer>false</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srLong</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One vehicle commander, one driver, one guard/gunner, four coms/electronic warfare droids</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>20</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>3</Passengers>
  <Consumables />
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>4</Speed>
  <Handling>1</Handling>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <DefAft>0</DefAft>
  <DefPort>0</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>0</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>2</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>10</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>10</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>false</Starship>
  <Massive>0</Massive>
  <SinglePilot>false</SinglePilot>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>false</Turret>
      <Location>Ventral</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities />
      <Key>LASERLT</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <BuiltInAttachments />
</Vehicle>