<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>PTOWER</Key>
  <Name>P-Tower Light Anti-Vehicle Battery</Name>
  <Description>[H3]1.4 FD P-Tower Light Anti-Vehicle Battery[h3]

The 1.4 FD is a light anti-vehicle and anti-armor laser
cannon battery first introduced during the opening
years of the Clone Wars. Initially designed to counter
medium and heavy armored repulsortanks, the 1.4 FD
is turret-mounted, single barrel, and roughly twice as
tall as an average human. Operated by a single gunner
and maintained by three engineers or technicians,
this weapon features a seriously outdated and notoriously
inaccurate targeting computer and fire control
system linked to a boxy, handheld remote firing unit.
It has its own integral power generator and low-yield
ray shield system, and it features a unique series of
micropower capacitor-routers that store energy in a
broad dish at the back of the weapon. It is typically
operated remotely by the gunner while the gunner and
the weapon’s technicians take cover behind a nearby
fortification, as the weapon has a tendency to overload
and burn or electrocute its users.
[P]Due to its advanced age and a number of design
peculiarities, the 1.4 FD suffers from a number of
drawbacks that make it difficult to use effectively. It is
relatively fragile and inaccurate, has a slow rate of fire,
requires more than it’s fair share of maintenance and
repair, and is generally unpleasant and often dangerous
to operate. In addition, the weapon’s broad dish
and tendency to glow brightly when fired make it an
excellent target for enemy anti-battery fire. Despite
these drawbacks, the 1.4 FD continues to be popular
among Alliance leadership and quartermasters due
to its low purchase price and ubiquity, and the fact
that purchasing these obsolete weapons, even in bulk,
draws very little attention from the Empire.</Description>
  <Source Page="46">Lead by Example</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Field Equipment</Type>
  <Categories />
  <Encumbrance>0</Encumbrance>
  <HP>0</HP>
  <Price>4000</Price>
  <Rarity>2</Rarity>
  <Restricted>false</Restricted>
  <BaseMods />
  <WeaponModifiers>
    <WeaponModifier>
      <Unarmed>false</Unarmed>
      <UnarmedName>1.4 FD Anti-Vehicle Battery</UnarmedName>
      <SkillKey>GUNN</SkillKey>
      <AllSkillKey />
      <Damage>4</Damage>
      <DamageAdd>0</DamageAdd>
      <Crit>4</Crit>
      <CritSub>0</CritSub>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>BREACH</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
        <Quality>
          <Key>INACCURATE</Key>
          <Count>2</Count>
        </Quality>
        <Quality>
          <Key>SLOWFIRING</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <BaseMods />
      <VehicleWeaponProperties>
        <Location>Unspecified</Location>
        <Turret>false</Turret>
        <Retractable>false</Retractable>
        <FiringArcs>
          <Fore>true</Fore>
          <Aft>true</Aft>
          <Port>true</Port>
          <Starboard>true</Starboard>
          <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
          <Ventral>false</Ventral>
        </FiringArcs>
        <Qualities />
      </VehicleWeaponProperties>
      <VehicleWeaponCount>1</VehicleWeaponCount>
      <RangeValue>wrClose</RangeValue>
    </WeaponModifier>
  </WeaponModifiers>
  <MaxAltitude />
  <HyperdrivePrimary>0</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>0</HyperdriveBackup>
  <StarFighters />
  <NaviComputer>false</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srNone</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One remote gunner</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>0</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>0</Passengers>
  <Consumables />
  <Silhouette>1</Silhouette>
  <Speed>0</Speed>
  <Handling>0</Handling>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <DefAft>0</DefAft>
  <DefPort>0</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>0</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>0</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>3</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>5</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>false</Starship>
  <Massive>0</Massive>
  <SinglePilot>false</SinglePilot>
  <VehicleWeapons />
  <BuiltInAttachments />
</Vehicle>