<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>R41STAR</Key>
  <Name>R-41 Starchaser</Name>
  <Description>[H3]R-41 Starchaser[h3]

Built by Hoersch-Kessel Drive at the beginning of the Clone Wars as a competitor to Incom/SubPro's popular Z-95 Headhunter, the R-41 Starchaser is an old, solidly built, and reliable multi-role starfighter. The single-seat Starchaser has a flat, lifting body fuselage with a broad diamond-shaped nose and short, straight s-foils mounted well aft on port and starboard wing roots. Four H-K Model 4Yb ion fusion engines provide enormous amounts of thrust but little in the way of maneuverability, and the fighters are equipped from the factory with class 2 hyperdrives and relatively sophisticated navicomputers. Standard R-41 armament consists of a pair of wingtip-mounted light laser cannons, forward-mounted light ion cannons, and a single forward-mounted concussion missile launcher whin gives the little fighter good anti-ship and anti-armor capabilities. Although the Starchaser showed great promise and performed well against its Z-95 competitor, a number of real or perceived problems with the series limited its broader appeal. 

[P]Unfortunately, in an effort to wring every ounce of thrust out of the 4Yb ion engines, Starchasers were lightly armored and had exceptionally fragile hulls with a tendency to disintegrate under moderately heavy fire. Combined with their average maneuverability and low-powered shields, Starchasers were considered deathtraps by most who flew them. In addition, production delays caused them to come to market much later than the Headhunter, providing that fighter with a head start in sales and good first impressions. Combined with the violence of the Clone Wars and the turmoil surrounding the fall of the Galactic Republic, the Starchaser never caught on as a mass market fighter. Already woefully outdated by the time the Empire came to power, H-K discontinued the ill-fated R-41 and relegated it to history. Today, occasional Starchaser squadrons operate within the Rebel Alliance, especially with cash-strapped cells that can't afford to operate Y-wings or X-wings.</Description>
  <Source Page="55">Stay on Target</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Starfighter</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <Encumbrance>0</Encumbrance>
  <HP>2</HP>
  <Price>55000</Price>
  <Rarity>7</Rarity>
  <Restricted>false</Restricted>
  <BaseMods />
  <MaxAltitude />
  <HyperdrivePrimary>2</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>0</HyperdriveBackup>
  <StarFighters />
  <NaviComputer>true</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srClose</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>6</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>0</Passengers>
  <Consumables>One week</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>4</Speed>
  <Handling>0</Handling>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <DefAft>0</DefAft>
  <DefPort>0</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>0</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>2</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>6</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>8</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <Massive>0</Massive>
  <SinglePilot>true</SinglePilot>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>false</Turret>
      <Location>Wingtip</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
          <Index>0</Index>
          <MiscDesc />
          <DefZone />
          <QualReplace>false</QualReplace>
          <SkillIsCareer>false</SkillIsCareer>
          <SkillIsRanked>false</SkillIsRanked>
          <VehicleWeaponUpgrades />
          <SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>-1</SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>
          <DieModifiers />
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERLT</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>false</Turret>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities />
      <Key>IONLT</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>false</Turret>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LIMITEDAMMO</Key>
          <Count>8</Count>
          <Index>0</Index>
          <MiscDesc />
          <DefZone />
          <QualReplace>false</QualReplace>
          <SkillIsCareer>false</SkillIsCareer>
          <SkillIsRanked>false</SkillIsRanked>
          <VehicleWeaponUpgrades />
          <SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>-1</SelectedVehicleWeaponIndex>
          <DieModifiers />
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>CML</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
</Vehicle>