<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>SS54GUN</Key>
  <Name>SS-54 Light Assault Gunship</Name>
  <Description>[H3]SS-54 Light Assault Gunship[h3]
Botajef Shipyards is a small shipbuilding concern located on the Outer Rim world of Botajef. A relative newcomer to the galactic shipbuilding industry, its most famous product is the hulking AA-9 Coruscant-class freighter, which brought the company to prominence during the Clone Wars. Recently, the company has branched out and entered the military starship market with the release of the SS-54.
[P]Designed to compete with the likes of the GAT-12 Skipray and the [I]Firespray-31[i]-class patrol craft, the SS-54 is a small, relatively fast vessel built for short-range patrols and ground attack. Vaguely insect-like in profile. SS-54s have a bulbous, well-armored command deck and a hull that tapers from the large prow to a high, squared-off stern similar to that of a LAAT/c heavy vehicle carrier. The ship's engines-a pair of powerful Incom HA-980a H/O ion engines-are mounted on the ends of short, adjustable spars that extend from the ship's sides. The interior of the SS-54 is largely open, with room enough for a squad of troops or a handful of passengers to ride in relative comfort. Standard armament consists of four fire-linked laser cannons mounted forward in the prow and a twin light laser turret mounted dorsally just aft of the engine spars.
[P]Since its introduction, the SS-54 has gained a small but loyal following among mercenaries and bounty hunters.Among its users, this ship has a reputation as a simple, reliable, and versatile vessel that can fill a number of roles remarkably well.</Description>
  <Source Page="58">Knights of Fate</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Gunship</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
    <Category>Non-Fighter Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>2</HP>
  <Price>110000</Price>
  <Rarity>6</Rarity>
  <HyperdrivePrimary>2</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>12</HyperdriveBackup>
  <NaviComputer>true</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srShort</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one co-pilot</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>30</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>10</Passengers>
  <Consumables>Two weeks</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>3</Speed>
  <Handling>1</Handling>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <Armor>2</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>18</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>14</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>3</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERMED</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Dorsal>true</Dorsal>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>true</Turret>
      <Location>Dorsal</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERLT</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <SensorRange>Short</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>