<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>VERATHWALK</Key>
  <Name>Versatile-Athletic Walker</Name>
  <Description>[H3]Baktoid Versatile-Athletic "Zalaaca" Walker[h3]
When Baktoid Combat Autom ata was absorbed by the Empire, a number of its executives and leading engineers quit to form a new company: Baktoid Industrial Systems. One of the early projects of the newly reformed company was this experimental product, an incredibly fast four-legged walker meant to compete more with speeder bikes than other walkers. The result was an eye-catching vehicle, partly inspired by the zalaaca species from Naboo. It has four reversejointed legs, a lithe multi-jointed body, and a long tail that serves as a counterbalance and rudder, as well as antennae for the sensor array housed in the rear of the body. The front console is styled to be vaguely reminiscent of a predatory animal face, with a menacing auto-blaster slung beneath. It seats a single pilot, with up to one passenger riding tandem.
[P]While the unique design of the zalaaca walker provides impressive acceleration and agility, the experience of riding one is best described as violent, startling, and challenging. Perhaps due to the Baktoid engineers' expertise in drone production, the zalaaca
walker has a reputation for inflicting motion sickness on riders who attempt sharp maneuvers. Still, the zalaaca walker is im pressively durable, fast, and adapts well to a wide variety o f com plex terrains in the hands of a skilled pilot.
[P]Very few zalaaca walkers were produced, but rumor has it that nearly all of them were donated to the Alliance to Restore the Republic as thanks for granting asylum to the fleeing Baktoid employees when the corporation was overtaken by the Empire.</Description>
  <Source Page="58">Forged in Battle</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Personal Scout Walker</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Land Vehicle</Category>
    <Category>Walker</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>1</HP>
  <Price>14500</Price>
  <Rarity>8</Rarity>
  <SensorRangeValue>srShort</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>9</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>1</Passengers>
  <Silhouette>2</Silhouette>
  <Speed>3</Speed>
  <Handling>-2</Handling>
  <HullTrauma>5</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>5</SystemStrain>
  <SinglePilot>true</SinglePilot>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Key>AUTOBLAST</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
</Vehicle>