<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>XL3CSPEED</Key>
  <Name>XL-3C Guardsman Patrol Airspeeder</Name>
  <Description>[H3]XL-3C Guardsman Patrol Airspeeder[h3]
The XL-3C Guardsman, produced by Tion Mil/Sci Industries, is the civilian version of TMSI's XL-5 Guardian force reconnaissance ship used by the Imperial Army and the ISB. A blocky, ungainlu ship, the Guardsman bears a striking resemblance to Mobquet's MB-C1 Medium Cargo hauler. A horizontal, cylindrical flight deck similar to that of the CR90 holds a crew of three in a tight but well laid-out cockpit, along with the ship's primary weapons and flight controls. The rectangular fuselage that holds the ship's drives and the bulk of its sensor suite. A secure, air locked passage allows the crew to move between the flight deck and the main fuselage.
[P]Designed for police and search-and-rescue work, the Guardsman is a slow, lumbering vessel optimized for high altitude observation and patrol. Like its milspec cousin, the Guardsman is packed to the gunwales with a number of powerful automated sensor systems—life form detectors, chemical and radiation sniffers, motion sensors, multi-optic sensor suites, high-powered cameras, encrypted, long-range comms, and more—that allow it to assemble a high-resolution view of a broad swath of ground.
[P]For patrol and law enforcement use, TMSI provides a prisoner-handling suite that can be equipped at the factory or by an aftermarket specialist. This provides the Guardsman with six secure, environmentally sealed holding cells, each capable of holding two human-sized beings—or one Wookiee-sized individual—for transport, along with various security and restraint systems to help keep prisoners in line. The cells and associated systems makes the Guardsman attractive to both planetary police forces and to bounty hunters, and the ships are in high demand among both groups.</Description>
  <Source Page="56">No Disintegrations</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Airspeeder</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Air Vehicle</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>1</HP>
  <Price>39000</Price>
  <Rarity>7</Rarity>
  <MaxAltitude>150 kilometers</MaxAltitude>
  <SensorRangeValue>srLong</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one co-pilot, one sensor/commms, one security tech</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>30</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>12</Passengers>
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>2</Speed>
  <Handling>-1</Handling>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <Armor>2</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>5</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>8</SystemStrain>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>BLASTCANHVY</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <SensorRange>Long</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>