<Vehicle>
  <Key>YT2400</Key>
  <Name>YT-2400 Light Freighter</Name>
  <Description>
    [H3]YT-2400 Light Freighter[h3]

Corellian Engineering's YT-2400 class light freighters are an update of the aging, reliable YT-1300 class. Using the lessons learned over the decades since the YT-1300's initial launch, CEC's engineers packed as much power and as many sophisticated flight and cargo handling systems into the YT-2400 as it could possibly hold. The YT-2400 has a saucer-shaped hull with a central circular core surrounded by cargo and passenger modules. Like all YT series freighters, it has a starboard-mounted cockpit connected to the main hull by a pair of reinforced pylons. The cockpit section contains its own access hatch and crew escape pod. Overall, these ships are slightly smaller than the YT-1300, thus they make better, more efficient use of the space available to them. The bow of the ship and forward cockpit pylon contain the ship's main cargo hold and the crew quarters. Opposite the cockpit are the common galley and refresher, and abaft the central core are a number of private cabins, the engineering bay, and the passenger escape pod. 

[P]While officially built as a civilian freighter to be used for legitimate business, Corellian Engineering's marketing and development departments are fully aware that the majority of their customers are, perhaps, on the far side of the law. The ship is touted as being "Double Plated," which is essentially advertising-speak for military grade armor. YT-2400s also feature heavy shields, room for larger reactors and ion drives, and a number of dedicated weapon hard points that come out of the shipyard unused.</Description>
  <Source Page="265">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <HyperdrivePrimary>2</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>12</HyperdriveBackup>
  <NaviComputer>true</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srShort</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One Pilot, One Co-Pilot/Engineer</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>140</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>6</Passengers>
  <Consumables>Two Months</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>4</Silhouette>
  <Speed>3</Speed>
  <Handling>0</Handling>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <DefAft>1</DefAft>
  <DefPort>0</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>0</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>4</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>25</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>18</SystemStrain>
  <HP>5</HP>
  <Price>130000</Price>
  <Rarity>5</Rarity>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
    <Category>Non-Fighter Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <Type>Freighter</Type>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <Key>LASERMED</Key>
      <Location>Dorsal</Location>
      <Turret>true</Turret>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Port>true</Port>
        <Starboard>true</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>true</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <Key>LASERMED</Key>
      <Location>Ventral</Location>
      <Turret>true</Turret>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Port>true</Port>
        <Starboard>true</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>true</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
</Vehicle>