<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Species>
  <Key>HUMAN</Key>
  <Name>Human</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Humans[h4]

Humans are the most populous and gregarious of the galaxy's sapient species. They seem to be present on almost every open planet that harbors life while traveling the spacelanes looking for more. 

[P][B]Physiology:[b] Humans are mammalian bipeds with mostly hairless skin. Their skin tones encompass a gamut of colors, from peachy tones to dark brown and black. Males average 1.8 meters tall, while females stand shorter and are generally not as stocky. They process oxygen for respiration and can digest a variety of animal and vegetable matter. Their biology is well-suited to many environments in the galaxy, which perhaps explains their dominance and ubiquity.

[P][B]Society:[b] Human ambition and competition have split their species into many different societies. Across the galaxy, humans live under every political system ever devised, from feudalism and theocracy to democracy and autocracy, with human technology encompassing a similarly wide variation. 

[P][B]Homeworld:[b] Humans are thought to have arisen somewhere in the Core Worlds, perhaps on Coruscant itself. However, humans took to the stars so long ago (perhaps even before the invention of faster-than-light travel) that now, humans claim countless planets as their homes. 

[P][B]Language:[b] The main language that connects "baseline" humans is Basic, though each society has its own dialect and sometimes even sub-language.</Description>
  <Sources>
    <Source Page="48">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Source Page="57">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Source Page="55">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Sources>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>110</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>HUMANAB</Key>
      <Name>Skills</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>HUMANABSK</Key>
          <Name>Additional Non-Career Skills</Name>
          <Description>Humans start the game with one rank in two different non-career
          skills of their choice.</Description>
          <StartingSkillTraining>
            <SkillTraining>
              <SkillCount>2</SkillCount>
              <Requirement>
                <NonCareer>true</NonCareer>
              </Requirement>
            </SkillTraining>
          </StartingSkillTraining>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>