<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Species>
  <Key>NIKTO</Key>
  <Name>Nikto</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Nikto[h4]

Perhaps the most well-known slaves of the Hutts, the fierce and humorless Niktos of Kintan have served their masters for thousands of years, though not always with unwavering loyalty. Hardy and stoic, the five Nikto subspecies are a common sight throughout Hutt Space and the Outer Rim Territories. 

[P][B]Physiology:[b] Reptilian humanoids with tough, leathery skin and standing roughly the height of an average human, the Niktos are a product of their harsh environment. Bombarded for thousands of years by gamma radiation from a nearby magnetar star known as M'dweshuu, life on Kintan has had to adapt rapidly or face extinction. The frequency of mutation among the Niktos has sped up their evolution, altering their genome thousands of times faster than would otherwise be the case. The Niktos are capable of only very limited facial expression due to their lack of well-developed mimetic musculature, and their eyes are protected by a thin, transparent membrane. Their seemingly blank expressions and unblinking stares often cause others to underestimate their intelligence. 

[P][B]Society:[b] Nikto civilization grew from necessity. Banding together to survive against their homeworld's fearsome, mutated predators—vicious spine dragons, enormous trogwhales, and ferocious tuskbeasts among them—the Niktos learned the value of cooperation as they worked together to tame and conquer their harsh world. Though racial tensions between the various subspecies of Niktos resulted in several bloody, planetwide wars prior to the Treaty of Vontor, the Hutts imposed a unified peace on the Niktos. While there are certain long-standing taboos against interbreeding among the subspecies, children are occasionally born of mixed parentage. Most offspring of such couplings display only the characteristics of one parent or the other; relatively few genuine hybrids are born. 

[P]Life for most Niktos is harsh, in spite of the "beneficence" of the Hutts, and they toil hard in the service of their callous and cruel masters. Few Niktos are natural leaders, and servitude is simply a way of life—relatively few aspire to anything more than bondage to a Hutt who has fewer sadistic tendencies than a Dark Lord of the Sith. Even so, there is an undercurrent of yearning for freedom among the Niktos that has not been entirely extinguished by millennia of slavery. Occasion-ally a Nikto will escape his master or purchase his freedom, but such an emancipated slave must remain ever-vigilant lest he fall into the clutches of another Hutt. 

[P][B]Homeworld:[b] The Niktos evolved on Kintan, a planet in the Si'klaata Cluster. It is a world of varied climates and environments, from vast deserts and dry tundra to forested mountains and tropical archipelagoes. The unifying factor on Kintan is M'dweshuu and its radiation, which permeates the whole planet, causing strange mutations among the ecosystems. While the radiation levels are not lethal (at least not immediately), Kintan is still a dangerous, violent world. 

[P][B]Language:[b] Unlike the Klatooinians and Vodrans, the Niktos have not abandoned their own language. Most Niktos are able to speak their native tongue, as well as Huttese. Many Niktos are also able to speak at least some Basic, though the limited articulation of their mouths can make them somewhat difficult to understand.</Description>
  <Source Page="96">Lords of Nal Hutta</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>3</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>1</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>11</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <OptionChoices>
  </OptionChoices>
  <SubSpeciesList>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>NIKTOCH1OP1</Key>
      <Name>Kajain'sa'Nikto (Red Nikto)</Name>
      <Description>The most common subspecies, the Kajain'sa'Nikto or "Red Nikto", adapted to survive in the Wannschok, or "Endless Wastes", a desert region on Kintan. They have a series of forehead ridges and small facial horns surrounding their eyes and on the chin.</Description>
      <SkillModifiers>
        <SkillModifier>
          <Key>RESIL</Key>
          <RankStart>1</RankStart>
        </SkillModifier>
      </SkillModifiers>
      <OptionChoices>
        <OptionChoice>
          <Key>NIKTOSP1OC1</Key>
          <Name>Environmental</Name>
          <Options>
            <Option>
              <Key>NIKTOSP1OC1OP1</Key>
              <Name>Arid/Hot Environments</Name>
              <Description>Red Niktos may remove [SETBACK] imposed due to arid or hot enviromental conditions.</Description>
            </Option>
          </Options>
        </OptionChoice>
      </OptionChoices>
    </SubSpecies>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>NIKTOCH1OP2</Key>
      <Name>Kadas'sa'Nikto (Green Nikto)</Name>
      <Description>Kadas'sa'Nikto, or "Green Nikto," originated in the milder climatic regions of Kintan, such as the forests and the seacoasts. Their scaly faces have small facial horns surrounding the eyes and on the chin. Their main distinguishing features are the long climbing claws on their hands, which can also be used in combat.</Description>
      <SkillModifiers>
        <SkillModifier>
          <Key>COORD</Key>
          <RankStart>1</RankStart>
        </SkillModifier>
      </SkillModifiers>
      <WeaponModifiers>
        <WeaponModifier>
          <AllSkillKey>BRAWL</AllSkillKey>
          <DamageAdd>1</DamageAdd>
          <Crit>3</Crit>
        </WeaponModifier>
      </WeaponModifiers>
      <OptionChoices>
        <OptionChoice>
          <Key>NIKTOSP2OC1</Key>
          <Name>Claws</Name>
          <Options>
            <Option>
              <Key>NIKTOSP2OC1OP1</Key>
              <Name>May use claws when brawling</Name>
              <Description>When a Green Nikto makes Brawl checks to deal damage to an opponent, he deals +1 damage and has a Critical Rating of 3.</Description>
            </Option>
          </Options>
        </OptionChoice>
        <OptionChoice>
          <Key>NIKTOSP2OC2</Key>
          <Name>Athletics</Name>
          <Options>
            <Option>
              <Key>NIKTOSP2OC2OP1</Key>
              <Name>Climbing</Name>
              <Description>Green Nikto gain [BOOST] to Athletics checks made to climb trees and other surfaces their claws can pierce.</Description>
            </Option>
          </Options>
        </OptionChoice>
      </OptionChoices>
    </SubSpecies>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>NIKTOCH1OP3</Key>
      <Name>Esral'sa'Nikto (Mountain Nikto)</Name>
      <Description>Esral'sa'Nikto, or "Mountain Nikto", adapted to the variable climate of the mountains of Kintan. They have large facial fins which are used for heat regulation. These fins also improve the Esral'sa'Nikto's hearing. Their skin is blue-gray, and they have neither horns nor breathing tubes.</Description>
      <SkillModifiers>
        <SkillModifier>
          <Key>SURV</Key>
          <RankStart>1</RankStart>
        </SkillModifier>
      </SkillModifiers>
      <TalentModifiers>
        <TalentModifier>
          <Key>NATOUT</Key>
          <RankAdd>1</RankAdd>
        </TalentModifier>
      </TalentModifiers>
    </SubSpecies>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>NIKTOCH1OP4</Key>
      <Name>Gluss'sa'Nikto (Pale Nikto)</Name>
      <Description>Gluss'sa'Nikto, or "Pale Nikto", came from the Gluss'elta Islands of Kintan, causing them to be natural sailors. They have white-gray skin, eye-horns like the Kadas'sa'Nikto, and fins similar to those of the Esral'sa'Nikto, but smaller.</Description>
      <SkillModifiers>
        <SkillModifier>
          <Key>ATHL</Key>
          <RankStart>1</RankStart>
        </SkillModifier>
      </SkillModifiers>
      <OptionChoices>
        <OptionChoice>
          <Key>NIKTOSP4OC1</Key>
          <Name>Aquatic</Name>
          <Options>
            <Option>
              <Key>NIKTOSP4OC1OP1</Key>
              <Name>Swimmer</Name>
              <Description>A Pale Nikto never suffers movement penalties for traveling through water and can hold his breath for a number of rounds equal to twice his Brawn rating before beginning to drown.</Description>
            </Option>
          </Options>
        </OptionChoice>
      </OptionChoices>
    </SubSpecies>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>NIKTOCH1OP5</Key>
      <Name>M'shento'su'Nikto (Southern Nikto)</Name>
      <Description>M'shento'su'Nikto, or "Southern Nikto", have no horns, a covered nose, and several pairs of breathing tubes. These tubes are larger than those of the Kajain'sa'Nikto, and also act as primitive ultrasonic sensory organs. Their skin color varies from white to yellow or orange.</Description>
      <SkillModifiers>
        <SkillModifier>
          <Key>PERC</Key>
          <RankStart>1</RankStart>
        </SkillModifier>
      </SkillModifiers>
      <OptionChoices>
        <OptionChoice>
          <Key>NIKTOSP5OC1</Key>
          <Name>Detection</Name>
          <Options>
            <Option>
              <Key>NIKTOSP5OC1OP1</Key>
              <Name>Sounds</Name>
              <Description>Southern Nikto may add [BOOST] to Perception and Vigilance checks to detect sounds.</Description>
            </Option>
          </Options>
        </OptionChoice>
      </OptionChoices>
    </SubSpecies>
  </SubSpeciesList>
</Species>