<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Species xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>SELONIAN</Key>
  <Name>Selonian</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Selonian[h4]

For Selonians, nothing is more important than the protection and preservation of their species, and they will go to any lengths to defend their homeworld and their kin. Honorable and forthright to a fault, Selonians appear backwards and gullible to outsiders, but what they lack in cunning they make up for in ferocious determination. 

[P][B]Physiology:[b] Covered in short, sleek brown or black fur, Selonians are carnivorous, mammalian bipeds with long, slender bodies and elongated heads that bristle with whiskers. Adult females average about two meters tall, making them significantly taller than most humans, with slightly longer arms and legs. Males of the species tend to be smaller and weaker than the females. Selonians have strong tails about a half meter long that they use to counterbalance themselves when walking upright. Though generally bipedal, Selonians can move comfortably on four limbs, and their retractable claws can be used for digging and burrowing, climbing, or defense. Most Selonians are sterile females, with only one fertile female per den, and relatively few males. 

[P][B]Society:[b] Selonian society is governed by a rigid caste system, which is itself a product of their biology. Though a technologically advanced society, there is no central authority on SeIonia. Their culture is organized around dens, which are composed of a single fertile female known as the Queen, a few males, and large number of sterile females. The dens are further divided into septs, the offspring of individual males. The females of the septs tend to serve specific functions within the den based on their genetic lineage, as determined by the Queen. Males in Selonian society have virtually no purpose beyond breeding and are generally dismissed as essentially useless for anything but procreation with the Queen. 

[P]Pragmatic, industrious, and sober, Selonians put the necessities and security of their den and their race in general above all else. Individual needs and desires are almost always subsumed to those of the den. Since the actions of an individual can affect the whole den, Selonians put a high value on honesty and fidelity. Duplicity among the members of a den is taboo in the extreme; lying is a crime on a par with murder. While Selonians are aware that most alien species are not as scrupulously honest in their dealings, they have difficulty comprehending deception and they are virtually incapable of outright deceit. 

[P]Some Selonians are trained to deal with outsiders, being schooled in language, culture, and expressions intended to put humans and other aliens at ease. To those unfamiliar with Selonian ways, they may appear outgoing and friendly, though most have no interests outside those of their den. Occasionally, a Selonian thus trained may become enamored of alien cultures and decide to travel beyond the Corellian System. These individuals are called Dravas (°Wanderers" in the Selonian tongue) and are generally viewed by most Selonians with a mixture of pity and disgust. Yet even these Wanderers put their den and race above all else, and most eventually return home to Selonia. 

[P][B]Homeworld:[b] Selonians are native to the fifth planet of the Corellian System. Selonia is a temperate world abundant in water, with vast oceans covering most of its surface. The myriad small islands and archipelagos that make up the planet's landmass are connected by a sprawling and complex network of tunnels exca-vated by the Selonians beneath their world's oceans, allowing the natives to journey across Selonia without ever setting foot on a vessel.

[P][B]Language:[b] The Selonian language, Mandaba, is difficult for non-Selonians to speak, and virtually impossible for them to speak well. While several models of protocol droids are able to communicate fluently in Mandaba, even they cannot precisely convey every nuance of the language. The Selonian language is almost never heard outside of the Corellian System, but most Selonians who deal with outsiders are at least conversant in Basic.</Description>
  <Source Page="91">Suns of Fortune</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>3</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>1</Cunning>
    <Willpower>3</Willpower>
    <Presence>1</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>11</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>80</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>COORD</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>SELONIANCH1</Key>
      <Name>Sight</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>SELONIANCH1OP1</Key>
          <Name>Sees in Darkness</Name>
          <Description>Selonians see in almost total darkness.  Remove all [SETBACK] added due to darkness.</Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
  <WeaponModifiers>
    <WeaponModifier>
      <UnarmedName>Tail</UnarmedName>
      <SkillKey>BRAWL</SkillKey>
      <DamageAdd>1</DamageAdd>
      <Crit>5</Crit>
      <RangeValue>wrEngaged</RangeValue>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>DISORIENT</Key>
          <Count>2</Count>
        </Quality>
        <Quality>
          <Key>KNOCKDOWN</Key>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
    </WeaponModifier>
  </WeaponModifiers>
</Species>