<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Species xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>HUMANCOR</Key>
  <Name>Corellian Human</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Corellian Human[h4]

It is said that Corellians have rocket fuel for blood, and there is no doubt that they have a penchant for speed. Renowned pilots and spacefarers, Corellians tend to have an independent, somewhat reckless streak coupled with an enterprising, can-do attitude that makes them ideal smugglers, free traders, and explorers. 

[P][B]Physiology:[b] Humans are the dominant species on Corellia. Though Corellians have a reputation for possessing quick wits and even quicker reflexes, there are no significant biological or physiological differences between the human natives of Corellia and humans elsewhere in the galaxy. They are genetically and anatomically as varied as most other human populations, though they tend to be slightly taller than average, and there are an unusually high number of Force sensitives among certain Corellian bloodlines. 

[P][B]Society:[b] Corellians have a reputation for being individualistic and pragmatic, with a recklessness that causes them to act impulsively. Often possessing a deep-seated rebellious streak, Corellians tend to view themselves as a breed apart from other humans in the galaxy, whom they generally consider somewhat staid and spiritless. This combination of enterprising individualism and confidence can easily be taken for arrogance (which in some cases it is) but Corellians generally prefer determined resolve and immediate action to any perceived indecision or vacillation. While thoughtful reflection and sagacity is considered a virtue among Corellians, it is not always a quality they possess. 

[P]One trait seemingly shared by nearly every Corellian is a particular fondness for piloting fast ships. This characteristic has translated to the Corellian philosophy of shipbuilding, namely that faster is better. Nearly all Corellians are capable pilots by maturity, and swoop and speeder racing are popular pastimes. It is generally accepted wisdom that Corellians have naturally good instincts and quick reflexes, explaining their ability to push vehicles and starships to their limits (and survive), though evidence for this is often more anecdotal than scientific. In addition to their piloting skills, Corellians are renowned explorers, traders, engineers, and tinkerers. Corellians pioneered many of the trade routes that crisscross the galaxy, and their ships are nearly ubiquitous. They also have a not-wholly-undeserved reputation as smugglers and pirates. 

[P]For a people often thought of as self-centered lone wolves, Corellians put a high premium on family bonds and filial loyalty. Honor and fidelity are universally valued among them, and a Corellian's word is his bond. Though it is said there is no honor among thieves, even the basest Corellian criminal possesses some sense of honor and a moral code that guides his actions.

[P][B]Homeworld:[b] One of the founding planets of the Galactic Republic, Corellia is among the foremost worlds in the galaxy. The nearest planet to the star CoreII, Corellia is a temperate world of varied landscapes. Though much of the planet's surface remains pristine and rural, Corellia is dotted with sprawling cities—its capital, Coronet City, is one of the most lively, sophisticated metropolises in the galaxy. Massive shipyards and smelteries orbit the world, producing some of the fastest starships on the market.

[P][B]Language:[b] Though a distinct Corellian language exists, Corellians most commonly speak Basic. Olys Corellisi or "Old Corellian" is rarely spoken and is virtually a dead language. Olys Corellisi is occasionally used by smugglers and other Corellians on the fringes of society as a simple code to keep their communications secret from prying ears.</Description>
  <Source Page="93">Suns of Fortune</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>110</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>HUMANCORCH1</Key>
      <Name>Skills</Name>
      <Description />
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>HUMANCORCH1OP1</Key>
          <Name>Piloting - Planetary</Name>
          <Description>May begin game with one rank in Piloting - Planetary.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>PILOTPL</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
              <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
        <Option>
          <Key>HUMANCORCH1OP2</Key>
          <Name>Piloting - Space</Name>
          <Description>May begin game with one rank in Piloting - Space.</Description>
          <SkillModifiers>
            <SkillModifier>
              <Key>PILOTSP</Key>
              <RankStart>1</RankStart>
              <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
            </SkillModifier>
          </SkillModifiers>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>