<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Species>
  <Key>KELDOR</Key>
  <Name>Kel Dor</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Kel Dor[h4]

Best known as a kindly and soft-spoken species, Kel Dors are most easily identified by the protective eye-wear and rebreather masks that they must wear when outside of their native environment. In spite of Kel Dors' gentle natures, they are renowned for their sense of justice and willingness to enforce it with great prejudice. 

[P][B]Physiology:[b] Near-hairless humanoid mammals, Kel Dors average 1.7 meters in height. Their respiratory systems are well adapted to Dorin's unusual atmosphere of helium and unique gas compounds, so that they must make use of filtration masks in order to survive in other environments. This, combined with innate toughness. does allow them to survive hard vacuum for a short time, an extraordinarily useful ability. 

[P]Similarly, they wear protective and enhancing goggles because their black eyes are sensitized to the dim light and unusual atmospheric conditions of Dorin. A highly developed extrasensory organ is located at the back of the Kel Dor skull. tightly linked to the brain. Kel Dor skin tone ranges from a pale orange to a dark red. 

[P][B]Society:[b] Kel Dors are tightly linked into their extended families. Several generations of a family often live together by choice. This offers an opportunity to share responsibility for the extended family's younglings and ease in consulting the family's elders for advice. Often, entire families share a common career, which can lead to family-owned businesses that span successive generations. 

[P]Technological advancement drives Kel Dor society strongly. Due to its own specialized needs, the species has become particularly adept at designing environmental systems. These include individual and large-scale systems suited to a wide variety of environments. 

[P]Justice is certain and swift on Donn. Security workers are quick to offer assistance to those in need, but they are also unwilling to wait long to see justice delivered. Instead, they interpret legal and moral issues in stark black-and-white terms, ignoring any potentially mitigating factors. 

[P][B]Homeworld:[b] Dorin is located in the Expansion Region. Due to its location between two black holes, it remained isolated from the rest of the galaxy until only a few centuries before the start of the Galactic Civil War. Dorin's atmosphere is composed largely of helium and a second unidentifiable gas that is unique to the system. Dorin's oxygen levels are low enough that most non-natives require technological assistance to venture there. 

[P][B]Language:[b] Kel Dors learn both Kel Dorian and Basic from childhood. They speak Basic as well as any native speaker and seldom speak Kel Dorian off-world. Their native language is easier to speak and understand when they are breathing Dorin's native atmosphere.</Description>
  <Source Page="57">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>1</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>3</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>EDU</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>KELDOROC1</Key>
      <Name>Sight</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>KELDOROC1OP1</Key>
          <Name>Dark Vision</Name>
          <Description>
            Kel Dors remove up to [SETBACK][SETBACK] imposed due to darkness from any skill checks.
          </Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>KELDOROC2</Key>
      <Name>Mask</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>KELDOROC2OP1</Key>
          <Name>Atmospheric Requirement</Name>
          <Description>
            Kel Dors must wear a specialized mask to breath and see outside of their native atmosphere.  However, Kel Dor may survive in vacuum for up to five minues before suffering its effects.
          </Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>