<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>A36PTHFNDR</Key>
  <Name>A-36 Pathfinder-class Force Recon Vessel</Name>
  <Description>
    [H3]A-36 Pathfinder-class Force Recon Vessel[h3]

Essentially an enhanced version of lncom's successful A-24 Sleuth-class scout vessel, the A-36 is designed for spacers who prefer direct action as opposed to skulking about and watching from afar. Using a batch of unsold A-24 hulls as a starting point, Incom stretched the hulls and enlarged the command deck, providing just enough space for a crew of four to operate the ship. 

[P]Along with increasing its size and crew capacity, Incom stripped most of the reconnaissance sensor suite out of the ships, replacing it with a long-range pin-point sensor array, a suite of more powerful weapons, and a sophisticated tracking/targeting/fire control computer. Extra armor was added to sensitive areas, the keels were strengthened, more powerful engines were installed, and a number of other systems were upgraded, hardened, and recalibrated to turn the ship from a passive scouting vessel to a fast, hard-hitting force recon ship. 

[P]The Pathfinder-class force reconnaissance ships retain the graceful, wasp-waisted silhouette of their A-24 predecessor. The command deck, while noticeably larger now, is still wrapped in photosensitive transparisteel sheets that give the crew a commanding view of their surroundings. Despite their upgrades and lengthening, Pathfinders blend in easily with their smaller, meeker A-24 cousins, a fact that organizations who keep both ships in their inventory use to great effect. 

[P]Aside from the obvious changes to the ship's length and bulk, the most notable item about the Pathfinder class is the sheer number of weapon systems that Incom managed to mount to them. In addition to the Taim &amp; Bak laser cannons inherited from the original A-24, the A-36 carries a dorsal turret-mounted light repeating ion cannon on the midships section, giving it full command of the area around the vessel. Additionally, a concussion missile launcher is mounted along the starboard side of the command deck. Mated to a specially calibrated Anq 3.6 tracking computer with an upgraded "Longshot" fire-control system, the weapons of the Pathfinder class give it a heavy, long-range punch well out of scale with its size. While not particularly common, Pathfinder-class ships are gaining a following in the Outer Rim, where they are used as patrol craft, interdictors, gunboats, and long-range scouting vessels.</Description>
  <Source Page="60">Enter the Unknown</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Patrol Boat</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Non-Fighter Starship</Category>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <Encumbrance>0</Encumbrance>
  <HP>2</HP>
  <Price>135000</Price>
  <Rarity>7</Rarity>
  <MaxAltitude />
  <HyperdrivePrimary>2</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>12</HyperdriveBackup>
  <StarFighters />
  <NaviComputer>true</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srMedium</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one co-pilot, one sensor operator, one gunner</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>40</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>4</Passengers>
  <Consumables>Nine months</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>4</Silhouette>
  <Speed>4</Speed>
  <Handling>0</Handling>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <DefAft>1</DefAft>
  <DefPort>0</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>0</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>3</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>16</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>16</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>false</Turret>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
          <Index>0</Index>
          <MiscDesc />
          <DefZone />
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERLT</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Port>true</Port>
        <Starboard>true</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>true</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>true</Turret>
      <Location>Dorsal</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities />
      <Key>IONLT</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>false</Turret>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LIMITEDAMMO</Key>
          <Count>8</Count>
        </Quality>
        <Quality>
          <Key>SLOWFIRING</Key>
          <Count>0</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>CML</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <BuiltInAttachments>
    <Key>ANQ36</Key>
  </BuiltInAttachments>
</Vehicle>