<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>ALIDADESURV</Key>
  <Name>Alidade-Class Long-Range Survey Ship</Name>
  <Description>[H3][I]Alidade[i]-Class Long-Range Survey Ship[h3]

Once a common sight in the out-of-the way places of the galaxy, the 
 [I]Alidade[i]-class Long Range Survey Ships are fast becoming a rarity in today's spacelanes. Designed by Sienar Ships, a long-defunct civilian subsidiary of Sienar Fleet Systems, they were first produced centuries before the Clone Wars. Initially designed as long-range survey vessels, they would fly to the very edges of the known galaxy to chart distant, unknown stars and plot new hyperspace lanes. To that end, they were outfitted with robust life-support systems to keep the crew and any passengers healthy, happy, and mentally stimulated for months or even years at space. While these ships were never considered fast, they were comfortable, tough, well-equipped vessels that could take a small crew of pilots and surveyors into the unknown in relative safety and comfort.
[P]As is the case with most vessels of their age and type precious few [I]Alidade[i]-class vessels remain in space. Time has been their most dangerous enemy. Many succumbed to fatigue or critical malfunction in far-off systems and were then simply abandoned by their crew, too old and expensive to fix. Others fell prey to pirates, stellar phenomena, or one of the countless other threats inherent in exploring the galaxy's wild spaces. Those that remain in use are lovingly tended to by their crews, and a thriving ownership culture has sprung up around them. An [I]Alidade[i] in port always attracts former owners, pilots, crew, or even passengers with fond memories of their time spent aboard one. Current owners are often bombarded with offers to buy their ship, to buy parts of their ship, or simply to join the company with like-minded aficienados of these old, reliable vessels.</Description>
  <Source Page="58">Savage Spirits</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Survey Vessel</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Non-Fighter Starship</Category>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>3</HP>
  <Price>150000</Price>
  <Rarity>6</Rarity>
  <HyperdrivePrimary>3</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>14</HyperdriveBackup>
  <NaviComputer>true</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srExtreme</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one co-pilot, two engineers, four sensor operators</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>250</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>5</Passengers>
  <Consumables>Two years</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>5</Silhouette>
  <Speed>2</Speed>
  <Handling>-1</Handling>
  <DefFore>2</DefFore>
  <DefAft>1</DefAft>
  <DefPort>1</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>1</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>3</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>35</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>30</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERMED</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Port>true</Port>
        <Starboard>true</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>true</Dorsal>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>true</Turret>
      <Location>Dorsal</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>IONLT</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <SensorRange>Extreme</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>