<Vehicle>
  <Key>ATPT</Key>
  <Name>All-Terrain Personal Transport</Name>
  <Description>
      [H3]All-Terrain Personal Transport[h3]

Developed by the Republic during the Clone Wars, the AT-PT is a small, one person infantry walker designed to carry a single trooper into battle in even the most hostile environments. Known for their sturdy and relatively simple construction, these vehicles are composed of a well armored central command pod suspended between two dextrous, reverse-articulated legs. The central pod houses a cramped, environmentally sealed cockpit with just enough room for the pilot, a sidearm, and an emergency kit. The AT-PT easily traverses a wide variety of terrains from thick forest to plains and cramped urban centers, fording shallow bodies of water and climbing inclines up to forty-five degrees. 

[P]AT-PTs are armed with a versatile array of anti-personnel weaponry, including a powerful twin blaster cannon and a repeating concussion grenade launcher in the walker's "chin," allowing it to destroy troops and light vehicles. While their sensors are, at best, rudimentary, they are equipped with a powerful, encrypted comlink that allows a squad of these small walkers to work extremely efficiently together.</Description>
  <Source Page="252">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <MaxAltitude>
  </MaxAltitude>
  <SensorRangeValue>srClose</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One Pilot</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>15</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>1</Passengers>
  <Silhouette>2</Silhouette>
  <Speed>2</Speed>
  <Handling>0</Handling>
  <DefFore>0</DefFore>
  <DefAft>0</DefAft>
  <DefPort>0</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>0</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>3</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>6</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>5</SystemStrain>
  <HP>1</HP>
  <Price>30000</Price>
  <Rarity>7</Rarity>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Walker</Category>
  </Categories>
  <Type>Walker</Type>
  <SinglePilot>true</SinglePilot>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <Key>BLASTCANLT</Key>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <Key>CONGRENLAUNCH</Key>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
</Vehicle>