<Vehicle>
  <Key>ATEST</Key>
  <Name>AT-EST Exploration and Survey Walker</Name>
  <Description>
      [H3]AT-EST Exploration and Survey Walker[h3]

Developed by Rothana Heavy Engineering to serve the needs of the Old Republic's civilian exploratory corps, the AT-EST is a six-legged, low-slung walker designed to haul both passengers and cargo through rough terrain and hazardous environments. Resembling a scaled-down version of the Old Republic's AT-TE combat walker, the AT-EST consists of a bulbous, heavily armored hull supported by six sturdy multi-jointed legs with broad, four-toed feet. The hull contains a forward cockpit, a central living and working area with tiny, two-person private berths, a common area, a workshop, and a secure cargo hold. 

[P]In its role as an exploration and survey vehicle, the AT-EST is equipped with a number of sophisticated computers and sensors that can detect sound, radiation, and energy, as well as take samples and assess the exact nature of a world's environment. Since it is designed to operate on untamed worlds and in hostile environments, the entire vehicle is environmentally sealed. These walkers are a common sight among the worlds of the Outer Rim, and are in high demand among militaries and civilian groups alike.</Description>
  <Source Page="253">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <MaxAltitude>
  </MaxAltitude>
  <SensorRangeValue>srLong</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One Pilot, One Co-Pilot, One Sensor/Comms Operator</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>50</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>8</Passengers>
  <Silhouette>4</Silhouette>
  <Speed>1</Speed>
  <Handling>-2</Handling>
  <DefFore>0</DefFore>
  <DefAft>0</DefAft>
  <DefPort>0</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>0</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>2</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>20</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>12</SystemStrain>
  <HP>4</HP>
  <Price>12000</Price>
  <Rarity>5</Rarity>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Walker</Category>
  </Categories>
  <Type>Walker</Type>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <Key>BLASTCANLT</Key>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
</Vehicle>