<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>ATFRC</Key>
  <Name>AT-FRC Force Reconnaissance Walker</Name>
  <Description>[H3]AT-FRC Force Reconnaissance Walker[h3]

KDY’s AT-FRC is a small, two-position walker designed
for use by ARC troopers toward the end of the Clone
Wars. Derived from the smaller, one-position AT-RT,
the force reconnaissance walker features a narrow,
lightly armored body slung low between two
reverse-articulated legs, giving the walker a surprisingly
small silhouette and allowing it to utilize cover
better. The two crew members sit in tandem—the
driver in the higher, rear seat and the reconnaissance
systems operator (RSO) in the lower, forward
position—beneath a transparisteel bubble canopy
that provides excellent visibility around the walker,
with few blind spots.
[P]The AT-FRC is fitted with a sophisticated reconnaissance
sensor suite, Fabritech’s LongView-341 .A, and a highpowered
encrypted comms system, which allow the
vehicle’s crew to gather information and transmit their
intel back to base quickly and securely. The LongView
is a scaled-down version of FabriTech’s LongView-382.X
sensor array. It is packed with numerous light, energy,
sound, pressure, and seismic sensors mated to an
encrypted recording device that can compress telemetry
into small data packets for easy transmission. In
addition to its sensor suite, the AT-FRC is fitted with a
number of stealth systems, including a sound-baffling system to muffle the noise of its
engine and drive servos, a thermal/EMP dampening
system that hides the vehicle’s energy emissions, and a
simple variable optical camouflage system that allows
the walker to blend in with its surroundings.
[P]While ostensibly an observation walker designed
to survive by dint of speed and stealth rather than
brute strength, the AT-FRC mounts a small assortment
of defensive weaponry. Mounted in a ball turret
beneath the walker’s chin is a double-barrel autoblaster
for anti-personnel work, as well as a rapid-fire
concussion grenade launcher for heavy infantry and
light anti-armor defense. The walker’s light,
armorplast-coated durasteel hull is proof against
small arms, splinters, and even some light repeating
blasters, but it can’t stand up to concentrated heavy
fire or ordnance attacks. The driver’s position contains
all piloting controls, as well as the controls for
the weapon systems, leaving the RSO free to concentrate
on scanners and telemetry. In an emergency,
control can be transferred to the forward RSO position,
but this is typically only used to escape in dire
combat situations.</Description>
  <Source Page="51">Lead by Example</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Walker</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Walker</Category>
  </Categories>
  <Encumbrance>0</Encumbrance>
  <HP>1</HP>
  <Price>75000</Price>
  <Rarity>8</Rarity>
  <Restricted>false</Restricted>
  <BaseMods>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>[B]Sound-Dapening Camouflage System[b]: Skill checks made to detect the AT-FRC have the difficulty upgraded once.</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
  </BaseMods>
  <WeaponModifiers />
  <MaxAltitude />
  <HyperdrivePrimary>0</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>0</HyperdriveBackup>
  <StarFighters />
  <NaviComputer>false</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srMedium</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One driver/gunner, one reconnaissance systems operator</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>5</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>0</Passengers>
  <Consumables />
  <Silhouette>2</Silhouette>
  <Speed>2</Speed>
  <Handling>1</Handling>
  <DefFore>0</DefFore>
  <DefAft>0</DefAft>
  <DefPort>0</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>0</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>2</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>5</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>8</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>false</Starship>
  <Massive>0</Massive>
  <SinglePilot>false</SinglePilot>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>false</Turret>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities />
      <Key>AUTOBLAST</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>false</Aft>
        <Port>false</Port>
        <Starboard>false</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>false</Turret>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Retractable>false</Retractable>
      <Qualities />
      <Key>CONGRENLAUNCH</Key>
      <Count>1</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <BuiltInAttachments />
</Vehicle>