<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>CATSEYESENS</Key>
  <Name>Cat's Eye Multipurpose Sensor Suite</Name>
  <Description>[H3]CryonCorp Mk. I Cat's Eye Multipurpose Sensor Suite[h3]
CryonCorp is a relative newcomer to the galactic technology
market, having been founded in the last decade
of the Clone Wars. A small electronics firm based
out of the Corporate Sector, it specializes in highresolution
sensor systems for personal, commercial,
and industrial use. Its breakthrough product, the venerable
EnhanceScan general-purpose scanner, remains
one of the most popular personal scanning rigs on the
market, even two decades after its introduction. A bitter
enemy of the Empire and its tyranny, CryonCorp’s
board of directors has dedicated itself to providing the
Alliance with high-quality, low-cost sensor equipment
with which to wage its ongoing guerrilla war. Its latest
development for the Alliance is the compact, versatile
Mk. I Cat’s Eye multipurpose sensor suite.
[P]Released just prior to the Battle of Yavin, the Mk. I
Cat’s Eye is designed for use in permanent and semipermanent
military camps. It combines a Pav.8r omniprobe
long range terrain following scanner, a KpR.4a
omnidirectional aerospace defense sensor suite, and
an FRR.v80a tightbeam visual tracking unit in a small,
highly efficient package. Mated to a powerful computer
suite and typically operated by a team of six
sensor technicians, the Cat’s Eye provides a comprehensive,
long range, 360-degree combination active
and passive sensor net that can detect ground, air,
and orbital units, with auxiliary systems that provide
internal security networks equipped with multi-optic
cameras and sensitive audio pickup systems.
[P]While they are extremely sensitive and provide
excellent early warning and detection, Cat’s Eyes
require quite a bit of power to operate, are relatively
easily spoofed, and can be detected from high orbit,
thanks to their energy output. They are also vanishingly
rare, as they have only recently entered production
and their construction process is long and complex;
few Alliance bases are equipped with them. With
improvements in the Alliance’s internal logistics chain
and an increase in production by CryonCorp, this system is slated for a wider rollout to Alliance garrisons
in the near future.
[P]The Cat’s Eye Multipurpose Sensor Suite uses the
planetary range scale and has a range of long. It adds
[BO][BO] to any Perception, Computers, or Vigilance checks
its operators make to detect incoming orbital air traffic
within its range, and it adds [SE][SE] t o Stealth checks made
by land units approaching the device and operator.
[P][I]Disclaimer: This is a piece of field equipment found in the Lead by Example Sourcebook.  It is created as a stationary "vehicle" because it is the most appropriate format.  While any mods or benefits are per the official source, the actual vehicle stats are an interpretation only and are not official.  Feel free to modify them if you think any changes are required.[i]</Description>
  <Source Page="46">Lead by Example</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Field Equipment</Type>
  <Categories />
  <Encumbrance>0</Encumbrance>
  <HP>0</HP>
  <Price>2750</Price>
  <Rarity>5</Rarity>
  <Restricted>true</Restricted>
  <BaseMods>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>Adds [BO][BO] to any Perception, Computers, or Vigilance checks to detect incoming orbital air trafic within long range (planetary).</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>Adds [SE][SE] to Stealth checks made by land units approaching the device within long range (planetary).</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
  </BaseMods>
  <WeaponModifiers />
  <MaxAltitude />
  <HyperdrivePrimary>0</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>0</HyperdriveBackup>
  <StarFighters />
  <NaviComputer>false</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srLong</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew />
  <EncumbranceCapacity>0</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>0</Passengers>
  <Consumables />
  <Silhouette>1</Silhouette>
  <Speed>0</Speed>
  <Handling>0</Handling>
  <DefFore>0</DefFore>
  <DefAft>0</DefAft>
  <DefPort>0</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>0</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>0</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>2</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>3</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>false</Starship>
  <Massive>0</Massive>
  <SinglePilot>false</SinglePilot>
  <VehicleWeapons />
  <BuiltInAttachments />
</Vehicle>