<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>HAET221</Key>
  <Name>HAET-221 Transport</Name>
  <Description>[H3]HAET-221 Transport[h3]
The High-Altitude Entry Transport-221 is a military
dropship that dates back to the Clone Wars. These
highly aerodynamic craft sport a smooth, bubbled
nose and a long, thin tail, which allow them to maintain stability even at incredible velocity. From ground
level, the HAET-221 has a relatively weak repulsorlift
flight system that cannot achieve more than a few hundred meters of altitude, but the craft’s main purpose
is to be launched from cruisers in orbit. From there,
the HAET-221 descends upon unknown territory at a
terrifying clip. Enemies often don't see the craft until
it is almost upon them, but the HAET-221 's superb
sensor array gives it plenty of forewarning of upcoming obstacles, its main laser cannon ready to pick off
other vehicles as soon as they come into range.
[P]As it arrives in the target area, the High-Altitude
Entry Transport can deploy its crew of five through
the top-rear hatch, then circle around the battlefield
providing reconnaissance and medium-range support. The craft is surprisingly durable, although its
utilitarian construction precludes the use of deflector
shields. The HAET-221 has grown uncommon following the Republic’s transform ation into the Galactic
Empire. Stormtroopers tend to treat the HAET-221
with suspicion, having swapped many tales of dropships that were abandoned to the atmosphere after
the interstellar cruiser that deposited them fled a battle turning sour. In truth, the disuse of the HAET-221
has more to do with the Empire's position, where it
wages more defensive battles over territory already in
its control. Still, the Alliance to Restore the Republic
has found more than a few fully functional craft abandoned on the surfaces of various planets, corroborating the stories of the stranded soldiers.</Description>
  <Source Page="63">Forged in Battle</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Recon Airspeeder</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Air Vehicle</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>1</HP>
  <Price>50000</Price>
  <Rarity>4</Rarity>
  <MaxAltitude>100 kilometers</MaxAltitude>
  <SensorRangeValue>srLong</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one co-pilot, one gunner</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>20</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>5</Passengers>
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>4</Speed>
  <Armor>2</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>8</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>10</SystemStrain>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Dorsal</Location>
      <Key>LASERMED</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Port>true</Port>
        <Starboard>true</Starboard>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Key>BLASTCANLT</Key>
      <Count>2</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
</Vehicle>