<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Vehicle>
  <Key>MULTITROOPTRANS</Key>
  <Name>Multi Troop Transport</Name>
  <Description>[H3]Multi Troop Transport[h3]
Produced by Baktoid Armor Workshop, the Multi Troop Transport is a heavy, broad-shouldered, snub-nosed vehicle designed to transport battle droids into combat. A massive, lumbering, imposing vehicle, the MTT is part troop carrier, part tank, and part siege ram. It is extremely hard to stop, and compared to the AAT, it is extremely capable in its role.
[P]With its hulking forward hull, sloping front end, and small aft hull, the MTT has a vaguely elephantine silhouette. A small armored cockpit is mounted atop the towering hull, just above a huge, thick, circular hatch. Most of the vehicle’s internal space is given over to the droid deployment rack, a long rotating assembly that holds more than one hundred deactivated battle droids. To deploy its droids, an MTT must come to a halt, open its hatch, and extend the rack. From there, the droids quickly deploy and activate, creating an instant infantry formation.</Description>
  <Source Page="68">Rise of the Separatists</Source>
  <Custom>AddedItem</Custom>
  <Type>Landspeeder</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Land Vehicle</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>1</HP>
  <Price>120000</Price>
  <Rarity>5</Rarity>
  <Restricted>true</Restricted>
  <BaseMods>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>[B]Droid Deployment[b]:  As a maneuver, a crew member can begin deployment of the MTT's complement of battle droid, which will be deployed and actrive at the end of the following round.</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>[B]Ram Prow[b]:  An MTT traveling at top speed may ram a stationary target of silhouette 2 or greater by ussing a maneuver to engate it.  If the target is mobile, this instead requires an action and a [B]Hard ([DI][DI][DI]) Piloting (Planetary) check[b].  Use collision rules to determine the effects of a collision.  Add +20 to any Critical Hit rolls the MTT inflicts on its target.</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
  </BaseMods>
  <Crew>One pilot, one co-pilot/gunner/engineer, one deployment rack operator, one vehicle commander</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>100</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>112</Passengers>
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>2</Speed>
  <Handling>-2</Handling>
  <DefFore>4</DefFore>
  <Armor>4</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>30</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>20</SystemStrain>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>BLASTCANLT</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>BLASTCANHVY</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <SensorRange>Close</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>
