<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Vehicle>
  <Key>NUTRANS</Key>
  <Name>Nu-Class Transport</Name>
  <Description>[H3][I]Nu[i] - Class Transport[h3]
At the beginning of the Clone Wars, the Republic Navy found itself wanting when it came to small ships. It had sub-capital and capital ships aplenty—although many of them were decades, if not centuries, old—but little in the way of gunboats, shuttles, landing ships, and other small craft. To fill this void, the Navy hastily pressed a number of civilian craft, like the Consular-class cruiser and various diplomatic shuttles, into service. The admiralty knew this was a stopgap solution at best, and while these civilian vessels were being outfitted for war, it initiated a campaign to provide the Navy with the ships it needed.
[P]The Nu-class transport was born out of a design competition for a multi-role vehicle capable of transporting troops and providing combat air support. The LAAT-series gunships ultimately won that competition thanks to their heavier lifting capacity and lower cost; Rothana Heavy Engineering decided that its ship did not require hyperspace capabilities, and the admiralty agreed. Shut out of the heavy CAS/transport competition, the Nu-class was ultimately purchased to fill the need for a vessel with long-range transport and light attack capabilities.
[P]Roughly the size of its LAAT-series competitors, the Nu-class has a triangular hull flanked by two long, folding wings. Its narrow, blunt-nosed, forward-mounted flight deck holds both crew members in tandem. The co-pilot sits in the lower, forward-most seat, while the pilot sits behind and above. Access to the ship and the flight deck is through a forward fold-down ramp beneath the flight deck. The ship can carry thirty fully equipped troops in relative comfort and safety.
[P]The Nu-class has been a remarkable success since its purchase by the Republic Navy. Its range, respectable laser armament, and heavy armor give it plenty of flexibility and allow it to fulfill both its transport and light attack roles with ease. Along with many fleets, the Nu-class has found a following among GAR special forces units and Jedi, who appreciate the sturdy little vessel’s utility and versatility.</Description>
  <Source Page="73">Rise of the Separatists</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Shuttle</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
    <Category>Non-Fighter Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>2</HP>
  <Price>85000</Price>
  <Rarity>5</Rarity>
  <HyperdrivePrimary>1</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>12</HyperdriveBackup>
  <NaviComputer>true</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srShort</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one co-pilot/gunner</Crew>
  <Consumables>One month</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>4</Silhouette>
  <Speed>3</Speed>
  <DefFore>2</DefFore>
  <DefAft>1</DefAft>
  <Armor>3</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>30</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>12</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERLT</Key>
      <Count>2</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERHVY</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <SensorRange>Short</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>
