<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Vehicle>
  <Key>SHEATHIPEDE</Key>
  <Name>Sheathipede-Class Transport Shuttle</Name>
  <Description>[H3][I]Sheathipede[i] - Class Transport Shuttle[h3]
The Sheathipede-class shuttle, known colloquially as the Neimoidian shuttle, is the CIS navy’s premier light lifter and VIP transport. Manufactured by Haor Chall Engineering, the oddly named vessel is a small, fast, hyperspace-capable transport used primarily to shuttle officers and light, high-priority materiel between CIS bases. It is also kept aboard CIS warships for use as a captain’s barge, and it sees a fair amount of duty in the various CIS Navy battle groups.
[P]Shaped roughly like a Neimoidian soldier beetle, the Sheathipede-class has a swooping, organic-looking hull with a tall, vertical stabilizer mounted aft and a long, protruding flight deck forward. The flight deck of a standard Sheathipede is covered by an expansive plasteel canopy that provides excellent visibility for the pilot and co-pilot. The passenger compartment is sleek and surprisingly well-appointed, with enough room to comfortably hold eight passengers of roughly human size.
[P]Stock Sheathipedes are unarmed and have only a basic shield generator. They rely on speed and a small sensor cross-section rather than brute strength to get their passengers safely to their destinations. That said, many ships in service with the CIS have been upgraded with light weapon systems, improved armor and shielding, and larger engines. These armed transports are typically used to ferry very high-ranking officers and officials, such as Count Dooku, or extremely valuable materiel through hostile territory.</Description>
  <Sources>
    <Source Page="63">Unlimited Power</Source>
    <Source Page="73">Rise of the Separatists</Source>
  </Sources>
  <Custom>AddedItem</Custom>
  <Type>Shuttle</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
    <Category>Non-Fighter Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>2</HP>
  <Price>120000</Price>
  <Rarity>6</Rarity>
  <HyperdrivePrimary>1</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>10</HyperdriveBackup>
  <NaviComputer>true</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srShort</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one co-pilot, one comms operator, one engineer</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>150</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>8</Passengers>
  <Consumables>Two months</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>4</Silhouette>
  <Speed>3</Speed>
  <Handling>1</Handling>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <DefAft>1</DefAft>
  <Armor>4</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>25</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>15</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <SensorRange>Short</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>
