<Vehicle>
  <Key>STARWIND</Key>
  <Name>Starwind Pleasure Yacht</Name>
  <Description>
      [H3]Starwind Pleasure Yacht[h3]

The Starwind-class pleaure yacht was originally Kuat Drive Yards' attempt to create a competitor for Corellian Engineering Corporation's VT series. However, before the project even launched, KDY changed their mind and repackaged the ship as a luxury yacht. 

[P]The Starwind has been moderately successful on the market, although its redesign never quite shook its light freighter origins. The trident-shaped starship has two side sections mounted along each side of the ship's main hull. One side section houses the ship's crew quarters, the other contains a reasonable sized cargo hold. The central spar contains the bridge, guest quarters, stateroom, lounge, galley, conference room, holotheater, and even a zero-gee relaxation table. All in all, the ship has a thorough catalog of amenities, as well as substantial cargo space. 

[P]However, the Starwind's main drawback is that it costs as much as a light freighter and luxury yacht combined. This has kept sales lukewarm, although some particularly rich smuggler barons and criminal lords have taken the ship as their personal vessel/command center.</Description>
  <Source Page="263">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <HyperdrivePrimary>1</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>15</HyperdriveBackup>
  <NaviComputer>true</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srMedium</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One Pilot, One Co-Pilot, One Engineers, Two Gunners</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>85</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>10</Passengers>
  <Consumables>Four Months</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>5</Silhouette>
  <Speed>3</Speed>
  <Handling>-2</Handling>
  <DefFore>2</DefFore>
  <DefAft>1</DefAft>
  <DefPort>1</DefPort>
  <DefStarboard>1</DefStarboard>
  <Armor>3</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>25</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>20</SystemStrain>
  <HP>2</HP>
  <Price>210000</Price>
  <Rarity>6</Rarity>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
    <Category>Non-Fighter Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <Type>Freighter</Type>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <Key>LASERMED</Key>
      <Location>Dorsal</Location>
      <Turret>true</Turret>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Port>true</Port>
        <Starboard>true</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>true</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>false</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <Key>LASERMED</Key>
      <Location>Ventral</Location>
      <Turret>true</Turret>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Port>true</Port>
        <Starboard>true</Starboard>
        <Dorsal>false</Dorsal>
        <Ventral>true</Ventral>
      </FiringArcs>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
</Vehicle>