<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>TIERP</Key>
  <Name>TIE/rp "Reaper" Attack Lander</Name>
  <Description>[H3]TIE/RP "Reaper" Attack Lander[h3]
The TIE/rp "Reaper" attack lander is easily recognizable for its trademark Sienar solar collectors, while its hull presents a marked departure from other craft in the TIE line. Forward angled collector panels serve the same aerodynamic function as those on the TIE/sk striker and, in fact, TIE strikers often serve as escorts for a Reaper during atmospheric insertions. Unlike the TIE/sk, the TIE/rp functions equally well in atmosphere and vacuum. Reapers primarily serve as transports for the Empire's elite troops, delivering them into the thick of combat, from amphibious planetary landings to deep-space boarding actions. Despite the menacing appearance of its blade-like solar collectors and coffin-like hull, the Reaper likely earned its unofficial moniker from its association with the Empire's infamous Death Troopers.
[P]In accordance with its primary role, the craft sports considerably better defenses than others in the TIE line.
[P]The TIE Reaper's advanced comm systems and powerful scanners are equally effective in relaying orders and monitoring a battle's progress, allowing it to fulfill a secondary function as a mobile command bunker. When it is used in this capacity, a Reaper's passenger complement might serve as bodyguards for an officer.</Description>
  <Source Page="59">Knights of Fate</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Starfighter</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <Price>100000</Price>
  <Rarity>6</Rarity>
  <Restricted>true</Restricted>
  <BaseMods>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>[B]Electronic Countermeasures[b]: Comms systems add [BO][BO] to checks to spoof missiles or jam enemy communications.  Upgrade the difficulty of Computers checks to bypass a TIE/ Reaper's jamming once.</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
  </BaseMods>
  <SensorRangeValue>srMedium</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one comms operator</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>30</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>10</Passengers>
  <Consumables>Two weeks</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>4</Speed>
  <Handling>1</Handling>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <DefAft>1</DefAft>
  <Armor>3</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>18</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>10</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERMED</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <SensorRange>Medium</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>