<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>TX130TANK</Key>
  <Name>TX-130 Saber-Class Fighter Tank</Name>
  <Description>[H3]TX-130 [I]Saber[i]-class Fighter Tank[h3]
The TX-130 is a light, quick-strike repulsortank first deployed by the Grand Army of the Republic as an anti-infantry and escort tank. Produced for the GAR by Rothana Heavy Engineering, the Saber was designed to provide fire support for infantry formations and to engage light enemy armor. Remarkably quick and nimble for an armored fighting vehicle, the TX-130 was sometimes compared to the Delta-7 [I]Aethersprite[i]-class starfighter due to its ability to get quickly into a fight, hit hard, and escape without a scratch. GAR and Jedi commanders used these fast little tanks to frightening effect during the Clone Wars, and more than one clone trooper unit was saved by the timely arrival of a squadron.
[P][I]Saber[i] fighter tanks mount a versatile mix of energy weapons and ordnance launchers, which gives their commanders quite a bit of tactical flexibility. Their primary weapons are a pair of fire-linked heavy laser cannons mounted to the tank 's hull. Although they have a fixed-forward firing arc, they can easily be brought to bear on any target, thanks to the [I]Saber[i]'s agility. A smaller support weapon-either a twin medium laser cannon or a powerful Taim &amp; Bak beam cannon-is mounted in a turret atop the vehicle, and rapid-fire ordnance launchers are mounted in each of the tank's sponsons for anti-armor and anti-fortification work. To ensure their survivability in combat, [I]Sabers[i] are covered in lightweight ablative armor, which can shrug off most lighter anti-vehicle weapons, and have a quick-cycling shield generator.
[P]The [I]Saber[i]'s mix of speed and firepower made it extremely popular among tank crews and clone troopers throughout the Clone Wars. Many of there tanks are still in service today, in the Imperial Army, various Rebel cells, and even some mercenary companies. As is the case with many old Gar fighting vehicles. TX-130s are in high demand among Rebel commanders, and the Alliance is always looking to expand its inventory of both operational tanks and salvage hulls.
[H4]Taim &amp; Bak KB-50A Beam Cannon[h4]
Some Sabers were equipped with beam cannon turrets in place of the standard twin medium laser cannons. Beam cannons are specially tuned laser weapons with a high output and long dwell time. They fire continuous beams of energy at a target for roughly three seconds, and then require a few seconds to recharge before firing again. These weapons hit incredibly hard, can punch through light and medium armor with ease, and have a nasty tendency to set targets on fire.
[P]Sabers equipped with KB-50a beam cannons are used in heavy support roles, providing cover fire for more lightly armed Saber platoons and squads of infantry during advances and assaults.
[P]A turret-mounted KB-50a Beam Cannon has the following profile: (Fire Arc All; Damage 7; Critical 3: Range (Medium); Breach 2, Burn 2, Slow-Firing 2, Vicious 1).</Description>
  <Source Page="54">Knights of Fate</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Repulsor Tank</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Land Vehicle</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>2</HP>
  <Price>85000</Price>
  <Rarity>6</Rarity>
  <Restricted>true</Restricted>
  <MaxAltitude>10 meters</MaxAltitude>
  <SensorRangeValue>srMedium</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one co-pilot, one gunner, one vehicle commander, one astromech droid</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>20</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>2</Passengers>
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>4</Speed>
  <Handling>1</Handling>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <DefAft>1</DefAft>
  <Armor>2</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>20</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>17</SystemStrain>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Port>true</Port>
        <Starboard>true</Starboard>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>true</Turret>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERMED</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Hull</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>LASERHVY</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Sponson</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>CML</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <SensorRange>Medium</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>