<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Attitudes>
  <Attitude>
    <Key>ANCIENTRELIGION</Key>
    <Name>An Ancient Religion</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]An Ancient Religion[h4]

More than twenty years ago, then—Supreme Chancellor Palpatine wiped out the Jedi. Before he did so, the Jedi were figures of whom many people had heard, but with whom few had ever interacted. To most, they were a tiny and aloof band of warriors and peacekeepers. not people one interacted with on a daily basis. 

[P]After the purge, those few who had formerly had the most opportunity to interact with the Jedi, the people engaged in the work of galactic governance. worked directly for the man responsible for wiping out those same Jedi. Some dismissed the Jedi as a dangerous cult that had almost overthrown the galactic government. Some figured the best way to survive in the growing Galactic Empire was to forget the Jedi had ever existed. Some refused either of these paths. only to vanish quietly as they drew the attention of the Imperial Security Bureau. Many beings in the rest of the galaxy had never even seen a Jedi or experienced the Force. For them, it was all too easy to believe the Force was a hoax. and the Jedi were gone. 

[P]Now, the Galactic Empire works tirelessly to stamp out the last rumors and legends of the Jedi's existence. Many who live under the Empire's dominion believe the Force is little more than an outdated legend. Citizens who have the potential to use the Force almost never come to recognize their inborn talents. Instead, they simply attribute any signs of their ability to luck, spiritual favor, or some other natural ability. Most vigorously deny any connection to the Force, insisting that their skills and abilities are not enhanced by its influence. Learning to embrace the Force as well as to use his abilities deliberately could be a central part of a character's initial development.</Description>
    <Source Page="46">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Attitude>
  <Attitude>
    <Key>DUTYTRAD</Key>
    <Name>Duty to Tradition</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Duty to Tradition[h4]

Even at the height of the Empire's power, the Force still plays a major cultural role on some worlds. In less sophisticated cultures. Force-sensitives may occupy leadership roles as shamans or spiritual advisors. Individuals could be inducted into an order during their early childhood. so that they could engage in a rigorous course of study. Such trainees are seldom given any other option but to embrace their education. The ability to manipulate the Force provides them with a moral obligation to use it for the betterment of their culture and the greater galaxy beyond it. The character may be selfless in making decisions to help others and may face the consequences which come from intuitive self-sacrifice.</Description>
    <Source Page="46">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Attitude>
  <Attitude>
    <Key>PRAGPOWER</Key>
    <Name>Pragmatic Power</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Pragmatic Power[h4]

Characters who recognize their Force potential do not always readily acknowledge its spiritual associations. Some see their powers and talents as tools they can use to advance their lives or accomplish their goals. This may help them to be more successful in their career of choice, enabling them to transform the world in a way that fits with their personal philosophies. 

[P]Many deny the fundamental goodness or evil of the Force. insisting that consequences for success and failure are far more important than any spiritual elements. Such characters are no more or less likely to make choices or perform actions that could be classified as "good" than those that could be classified as "evil." However, in their minds, their preference for a certain moral choice is independent of the powers they wield. This can prove problematic if. for example, a character believes his righteous anger is a reasonable motivator for his actions. Such a character may constantly flirt with the dark side of the Force and never realize it. 

[P]Learning or denying Force philosophies and histories invariably plays into the stories of characters from this background. Eventually, the character likely learns of the truth of the Force. Whether he embraces this knowledge or denies it and continues on his chosen path can prove to be a very Interesting opportunity for character development.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Attitude>
  <Attitude>
    <Key>ONEFORCE</Key>
    <Name>One with the Force</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]One with the Force[h4]

Some adepts are so deeply grounded in the Force that it influences their every action. These characters constantly perceive the world through its lens, and it decides their every thought. Often, their education has included a thorough grounding in Force philosophies. so that they choose to act with deliberate devotion to the light (or dark) side of the Force. 

[P]Such knowledge is deliberately suppressed In the Empire and thus incredibly hard to come by. However, it is not impossible. A character with this background may have been raised by one of the last Jedi to escape the purges, who, before dying, passed on a measure of knowledge of the Force to the character. Alternatively, the character may have known someone who would have reason to be familiar with the Jedi and their knowledge. A former Republic soldier or sympathetic Senator, an old friend of the Jedi, or even an ally who worked with the Jedi but was not Force-sensitive may have escaped the Emperors purges and passed on what he has learned. It may be that the character is one of those individuals, and as he has aged, he has realized that he too can tap into the power of the Force.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Attitude>
</Attitudes>