<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<BaseOfOperations>
  <BaseOfOperation>
    <Key>HOMESTEAD</Key>
    <Name>Homestead</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Homestead[h4]

To start a homestead, the party chooses the location where they would like the build the homestead and a core function they would like to serve: ranching, farming, mining, or something similar. Ranches focus on raising animals for pets, food, or labor. Farms grow crops for food or industrial purposes. Mines extract natural resources from the environment. The particular animal, crop, or resource can be determined by the players and the GM. The party might have a nerf ranch on Delaya, a hydroponic farm on Tatooine, or a tibanna gas mine on Bespin. It is also possible to use the homestead rules to represent a small commercial space station run by the party. In this case, the station usually sells consumables, repairs, and entertainment to passing ships (although this could also be considered a business, its self-sufficiency makes the homestead rules more appropriate).

[B]Basic Homestead:[b] The basic homestead includes a main house, kitchen, power generator, water well, and a living quarters. It also attracts one NPC employee per party member, and includes an area up to ten square kilometers that is suitable for the selected focus of the homestead. In the case of a space station, it includes a hangar bay as well as quarters for the crew, and instead of ten square kilometers, it has accommodations for ten visitors and two docking tubes that can connect to visiting spacecraft. 

[P][B]Basic Homestead Cost:[b] 50,000 credits and 5 Obligation. These costs are waived if the homestead is selected in lieu of a ship at character creation. 

[P][B]Party Career Skill:[b] The party must select one homestead focus. The focus determines the career skill granted to the entire party: Farm (Resilience), Ranch (Survival), Mine (Athletics), Space Station (Piloting [Space]). Each character in the party counts this skill as a career skill.</Description>
    <Source Page="82">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <Cost>
      <Credits>50000</Credits>
      <Obligation>5</Obligation>
    </Cost>
    <NPCPerMember>true</NPCPerMember>
    <Foci>
      <Key>BASEFARM</Key>
      <Key>BASERANCH</Key>
      <Key>BASEMINE</Key>
      <Key>BASESTATION</Key>
    </Foci>
    <AvailableUpgrades>
      <Key>HOMECORE</Key>
      <Key>HOMESEC</Key>
      <Key>HOMENPC</Key>
      <Key>HOMEINF</Key>
      <Key>HOMEMECHGAR</Key>
      <Key>HOMELANDBAY</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITHANG</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITINFIRM</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITREPAIR</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITSEC</Key>
    </AvailableUpgrades>
  </BaseOfOperation>
  <BaseOfOperation>
    <Key>BUSINESS</Key>
    <Name>Business</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Business[h4]

Not all campaigns work thematically with the isolated and insular nature of a homestead. An alternative is to open a business in town, where the party can regroup between adventures and be a part of a larger community. To create a business, the party chooses both a location and a focus for it. The different business focuses are entertainment, retail, and service. Entertainment venues include cantinas, nightclubs, casinos, and restaurants. Retail shops stock and sell a single category of gear, such as ranged weapons, melee weapons, armor, communications, detection devices, medical, cybernetics, recreational entertainment, security, survival, tools, droids, ground vehicles, airspeeders, or starships. Service businesses might include a repair shop, medical clinic, gym, adventure travel firm, consulting firm, a taxi stand, or countless others.

[B]Basic Business:[b] The basic business includes a main floor for customers, a back room for storage, and either an upstairs or basement the party can use as a living area. It contains the basic equipment needed to operate the business (a medical clinic might include cots and basic medical supplies, a repair shop may include lifts and repair tools, and a retail shop would include shelves and basic retail stock). It also includes one employee or droid per party member. 

[P][B]Basic Business Cost:[b] 50,000 credits and 5 Obligation. The costs are waived if selected in lieu of a ship at party creation. 

[P][B]Party Career Skill:[b] The party must select one business focus. The focus determines the career skill granted to the entire party: Entertainment (Charm), Retail (Negotiation), Service (choose either Mechanics, Computers, or a single applicable Knowledge skill for the entire party). Each character in the party counts this skill as a career skill. </Description>
    <Source Page="82">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <Cost>
      <Credits>50000</Credits>
      <Obligation>5</Obligation>
    </Cost>
    <NPCPerMember>true</NPCPerMember>
    <Foci>
      <Key>BASEENT</Key>
      <Key>BASERETAIL</Key>
      <Key>BASESERVICE</Key>
      <Key>BASESTATION</Key>
    </Foci>
    <AvailableUpgrades>
      <Key>BUSCORE</Key>
      <Key>BUSSEC</Key>
      <Key>BUSORDERS</Key>
      <Key>BUSWHOLE</Key>
      <Key>BUSLIC</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITHANG</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITINFIRM</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITREPAIR</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITSEC</Key>
    </AvailableUpgrades>
  </BaseOfOperation>
  <BaseOfOperation>
    <Key>REBELBASE</Key>
    <Name>Rebel Base</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Rebel Base[h4]

Ideally, the players should decide what type of base they wish to establish when they choose to create one. Rather than serving as a broad-reaching facility, the base should instead focus on some particular aspect of the war effort. The group should consider how planetary loyalty, culture, and environment might affect the base and provide advantages for different specific applications. The Player Characters can either establish a base if they select this option at character creation (see page 111 of the [B]Age of Rebellion[b] Core Rulebook), or they can ask to receive it as a special reward for increasing their Contribution rank (see page 49 of the [B]Age of Rebellion[b] Core Rulebook). While a full base of operations is a larger reward than the default recommendation, it also offers the GM a great many interesting opportunities for plot hooks. At the GM's discretion, the PCs can also acquire a base if they capture a stronghold in battle, undertake the effort to build a base of operations, or otherwise perform the tasks narratively required to get a home base. 

[P]After the characters have acquired their base, they can then consider how they might focus the function of the base. Each possible focus on page 88 recommends upgrades that could be added to the core base to better serve the base's function. Teams might wish to expand a facility in directions not presented here, and they are encouraged to work with their GM to do so.</Description>
    <Source Page="86">Desperate Allies</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <Cost>
      <Credits>0</Credits>
      <Obligation>0</Obligation>
    </Cost>
    <NPCPerMember>false</NPCPerMember>
    <Foci>
      <Key>BASESAFE</Key>
      <Key>BASETRAIN</Key>
      <Key>BASERESEARCH</Key>
      <Key>BASEMEET</Key>
      <Key>BASEWEAP</Key>
    </Foci>
    <AvailableUpgrades>
      <Key>REBELCORE</Key>
      <Key>REBELSEC</Key>
      <Key>REBELNPC</Key>
      <Key>REBELMED</Key>
      <Key>REBELHANG</Key>
      <Key>REBELARM</Key>
      <Key>REBELTRAIN</Key>
      <Key>REBELLAB</Key>
      <Key>REBELCOMMAND</Key>
      <Key>REBELRES</Key>
    </AvailableUpgrades>
    <NPCs>
      <Adversary>
        <Name>NPC Caretaker</Name>
        <Key>c7624c72-1d17-44ee-a992-b485de6e11de</Key>
        <Category>Base NPC</Category>
        <Characteristics>
          <CharCharacteristic>
            <Key>BR</Key>
            <Name>Brawn</Name>
            <Rank>
              <StartingRanks>1</StartingRanks>
              <PurchasedRanks>1</PurchasedRanks>
            </Rank>
          </CharCharacteristic>
          <CharCharacteristic>
            <Key>AG</Key>
            <Name>Agility</Name>
            <Rank>
              <StartingRanks>1</StartingRanks>
              <PurchasedRanks>1</PurchasedRanks>
            </Rank>
          </CharCharacteristic>
          <CharCharacteristic>
            <Key>INT</Key>
            <Name>Intellect</Name>
            <Rank>
              <StartingRanks>1</StartingRanks>
              <PurchasedRanks>1</PurchasedRanks>
            </Rank>
          </CharCharacteristic>
          <CharCharacteristic>
            <Key>CUN</Key>
            <Name>Cunning</Name>
            <Rank>
              <StartingRanks>1</StartingRanks>
              <PurchasedRanks>1</PurchasedRanks>
            </Rank>
          </CharCharacteristic>
          <CharCharacteristic>
            <Key>WIL</Key>
            <Name>Willpower</Name>
            <Rank>
              <StartingRanks>1</StartingRanks>
              <PurchasedRanks>1</PurchasedRanks>
            </Rank>
          </CharCharacteristic>
          <CharCharacteristic>
            <Key>PR</Key>
            <Name>Presence</Name>
            <Rank>
              <StartingRanks>1</StartingRanks>
              <PurchasedRanks>1</PurchasedRanks>
            </Rank>
          </CharCharacteristic>
        </Characteristics>
        <Talents />
        <ForceAbilities />
        <Skills>
          <CharSkill>
            <Key>EDU</Key>
          </CharSkill>
          <CharSkill>
            <Key>MECH</Key>
          </CharSkill>
          <CharSkill>
            <Key>VIGIL</Key>
          </CharSkill>
        </Skills>
        <Experience>
          <UsedExperience>60</UsedExperience>
        </Experience>
        <Attributes />
        <Weapons />
        <Armor />
        <Gear>
          <CharGear>
            <ItemKey>DATAPAD</ItemKey>
            <Key>1cdff020-c839-461c-b769-f8cc20ac9dad</Key>
            <Equipped>true</Equipped>
            <Count>1</Count>
          </CharGear>
        </Gear>
        <Abilities />
        <Items>
          <AdvItem>
            <Key>0</Key>
            <Name>Work clothes</Name>
          </AdvItem>
          <AdvItem>
            <Key>1</Key>
            <Name>Maintenance supplies</Name>
          </AdvItem>
        </Items>
        <SpecialWeapons />
        <SpecialArmor />
        <Type>Minion</Type>
      </Adversary>
    </NPCs>
  </BaseOfOperation>
  <BaseOfOperation>
    <Key>WORKSHOP</Key>
    <Name>Workshop</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Workshop[h4]
      A Technician's workshop is many things. It is a place of business and a place of refuge, where the Technician can get away from worldly concerns and dive headlong into the latest project. Many Technicians make do with nothing more than a table, a few power outlets and some tools, but a proper workshop can provide opportunities and resources that would not otherwise be available. A basic workshop might be little more than a garage with a few machines to keep a moisture farm running, while a vast, industrial workshop might include state-of-the art diagnostic technology, a research library and rapid prototyping facilities.
[P] A Technician PC could be granted a workshop or the materials to make one by a wealthy patron or might be able to purchase the space and materials by taking on Obligation to a supplier. If the PC is particularly flush with credits, the workshop could even be purchased outright, although even a basic workshop costs tens of thousands of credits. Of course, the GM may wish to consider offering an appropriately priced workshop to  a Technician PC as a means of divesting the character of credits if the PC has become too rich to be concerned with normal work.
[H3]Workshop Benefits[h3]
The form and capacity of a workshop is decided in large part by its location. A workshop in a cramped cargo bay aboard a tramp freighter does not have the capabilities of one that takes up a sprawling planetside warehouse, but it is mobile and secure in a way that the warehouse cannot match
[P]All workshops worthy of the name provide the same basic utilities. A Technician's workshop offers storage space, including space to house large or unwieldy equipment as well as access to the essentials of technical work, such as power, tools and materials.
[H3]Basic Benefits[h3] Upon acquiring a workshop, a character chooses the workshop's focus. This is a particular skill for which it is optimized and is on of the character's career skills for which a workshop is relevant (generally Computers, Mechanics or Medicine). When making checks with the workshop's focus skill, the character is always treated as having the right tools for the job (see page 171 of the [B]Edge of The Empire Core Rulebook[b]).
[P]Further, a default workshop has space to store tools, equipment and other helpful accoutrements up to 25 encumbrance.
[H3]Advanced Benefits[h3] Advanced or expansive workshops can offer additional benefits to appropriate projects or cover more types of work. Additional benefits include upgrading relevant checks, downgrading their difficulty or reducing the cost or time spent on a project. Depending on a workshop's location, there are certain limits to the effects of a workshop.
[P]By default, a workshop has the capacity for three advanced benefits. The workshop's owner must acquire and install these in the workshop separately, through narrative efforts or, at the GM's discretion, through time and labor.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="94">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <Cost>
      <Credits>0</Credits>
      <Obligation>0</Obligation>
    </Cost>
    <NPCPerMember>false</NPCPerMember>
    <MaxUpgrades>3</MaxUpgrades>
    <Foci>
      <Key>WORKCOMP</Key>
      <Key>WORKMECH</Key>
      <Key>WORKMED</Key>
    </Foci>
    <AvailableUpgrades>
      <Key>WORKSPACE</Key>
      <Key>WORKHOME</Key>
      <Key>WORKCONT</Key>
      <Key>WORKRECLAM</Key>
      <Key>WORKRES</Key>
      <Key>WORKSPARE</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITHANG</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITINFIRM</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITREPAIR</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITSEC</Key>
    </AvailableUpgrades>
  </BaseOfOperation>
  <BaseOfOperation>
    <Key>WORKSHOPSHIP</Key>
    <Name>Shipboard Workshop</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Shipboard Workshop[h4]
For Technicians without a stable home a workshop on board a starship or vehicle may be the best option. Such workshops are often cramped and have limited potential for expansion but they are typically quite secure and offer unparalleled access to new clients and jobs. A Technician can put a shipboard workshop only on a craft of silhouette 4 or larger.
[P][B]Basic Workshop:[b] A basic shipboard workshop takes up a spare storage compartment or cargo bay. It can only contain tools and supplies up to 20 total encumbrance, and it can accommodate three advanced benefits. At the GM's discretion, the workshop's owner can use on of the ship's unused hard points to increase the number of advanced benefits it can sustain by one. When a PC acquires an advanced benefit for a spacecraft, the character may choose a Low-Grav Workspace as that advanced benefit.</Description>
    <Source Page="95">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <Cost>
      <Credits>0</Credits>
      <Obligation>0</Obligation>
    </Cost>
    <NPCPerMember>false</NPCPerMember>
    <MaxUpgrades>3</MaxUpgrades>
    <Foci>
      <Key>WORKCOMP</Key>
      <Key>WORKMECH</Key>
      <Key>WORKMED</Key>
    </Foci>
    <AvailableUpgrades>
      <Key>WORKSPACE</Key>
      <Key>WORKHOME</Key>
      <Key>WORKCONT</Key>
      <Key>WORKRECLAM</Key>
      <Key>WORKRES</Key>
      <Key>WORKSPARE</Key>
      <Key>WORKLOWGRAV</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITHANG</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITINFIRM</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITREPAIR</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITSEC</Key>
    </AvailableUpgrades>
  </BaseOfOperation>
  <BaseOfOperation>
    <Key>WORKSHOPHOME</Key>
    <Name>Homestead Workshop</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Homestead Workshop[h4]
      Locating a workshop on a planet can mean it is inaccessible when on the move, but it comes with a lot of room for expansion. Depending on how large a space the workshop is housed in, there might be almost no practical limit beyond expense to the improvements that could be installed. Of course, these improvements are only accessible when working in the workshop in person and there could be security concerns if the Technician is away too long.
[P][B]Basic Workshop:[b] A basic homestead workshop might be an attached room, a tool shed or even a full separate building. It can contain tools and supplies up to 30 total encumbrance. It automatically has one Comforts of Home advanced benefit and can accommodate up to five additional advanced benefits.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="95">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <Cost>
      <Credits>0</Credits>
      <Obligation>0</Obligation>
    </Cost>
    <NPCPerMember>false</NPCPerMember>
    <MaxUpgrades>3</MaxUpgrades>
    <Foci>
      <Key>WORKCOMP</Key>
      <Key>WORKMECH</Key>
      <Key>WORKMED</Key>
    </Foci>
    <AvailableUpgrades>
      <Key>WORKSPACE</Key>
      <Key>WORKHOME</Key>
      <Key>WORKCONT</Key>
      <Key>WORKRECLAM</Key>
      <Key>WORKRES</Key>
      <Key>WORKSPARE</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITHANG</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITINFIRM</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITREPAIR</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITSEC</Key>
    </AvailableUpgrades>
    <BuiltInUpgrades>
      <Key>WORKHOME</Key>
    </BuiltInUpgrades>
  </BaseOfOperation>
  <BaseOfOperation>
    <Key>WORKSHOPIND</Key>
    <Name>Industrial Workshop</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Industrial Workshop[h4]
      While Technicians who operate alone or with a small crew use private workshops out of necessity, those with ties to larger groups, such as corporations or crime syndicates, often have other options. Powerful patrons might have access to their own facilities, which they can share with favored underlings. These workshops are often outfitted as befits the wealth and influence of their owner, but their use usually comes with the expectation that the patron gets a cut of the work done there.
[P][B]Basic Workshop:[b] A basic industrial workshop usually consists of a building with workspaces for several assistants, a manufacturing facility that can handle the creation of prototypes and organized storage space. It can contain tools and supplies up to 60 total encumbrance. It automatically has on Additional Workspace advanced benefit, one Research Records advanced benefit and on Spare Parts Bin advanced benefit and it can accomodate any number of additional advanced benefits.</Description>
    <Source Page="96">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
    <Cost>
      <Credits>0</Credits>
      <Obligation>0</Obligation>
    </Cost>
    <NPCPerMember>false</NPCPerMember>
    <Foci>
      <Key>WORKCOMP</Key>
      <Key>WORKMECH</Key>
      <Key>WORKMED</Key>
    </Foci>
    <AvailableUpgrades>
      <Key>WORKSPACE</Key>
      <Key>WORKHOME</Key>
      <Key>WORKCONT</Key>
      <Key>WORKRECLAM</Key>
      <Key>WORKRES</Key>
      <Key>WORKSPARE</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITHANG</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITINFIRM</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITREPAIR</Key>
      <Key>CIVREFITSEC</Key>
    </AvailableUpgrades>
    <BuiltInUpgrades>
      <Key>WORKSPACE</Key>
      <Key>WORKRES</Key>
      <Key>WORKSPARE</Key>
    </BuiltInUpgrades>
  </BaseOfOperation>
</BaseOfOperations>