<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Characteristics>
  <Characteristic>
    <Key>BR</Key>
    <Name>Brawn</Name>
    <Abbrev>Br</Abbrev>
    <Description>
    [H4]Brawn[h4]

[P]A character's Brawn represents a blend of a character's brute power, strength, and overall toughness, as well as the ability to apply those attributes as needed. Characters with a high Brawn are physically fit and hardy, tend not to get sick often, and have strong constitutions. Brawn is used for a number of physical skills such as Athletics and Brawl. Brawn is also used to determine a character's starting wound threshold. </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="16">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="23">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="24">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Characteristic>
  <Characteristic>
    <Key>AG</Key>
    <Name>Agility</Name>
    <Abbrev>Ag</Abbrev>
    <Description>
    [H4]Agility[h4]

[P]The Agility characteristic measures a character's manual dexterity, hand-eye coordination, and body control. Characters with a high Agility have a good sense of balance, flexibility, and deft hands. Agility is used for a number of physical skills such as Coordination, and is key to ranged combat skills such as Ranged (Light) and Ranged (Heavy). </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="15">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="23">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="24">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Characteristic>
  <Characteristic>
    <Key>INT</Key>
    <Name>Intellect</Name>
    <Abbrev>Int</Abbrev>
    <Description>
    [H4]Intellect[h4]

[P]The Intellect characteristic measures a character's intelligence, education, mental acuity, and ability to reason and rationalize. Characters with a high Intellect can extrapolate or interpolate data, can recall details and draw from previous experience, and can think of long-term strategies and envision the ramifications of present actions. Intellect is used for a number of mental skills, such as Astrogation, Computers, and all the Knowledge skills, such as Lore and Xenology. </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="16">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="23">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="25">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Characteristic>
  <Characteristic>
    <Key>CUN</Key>
    <Name>Cunning</Name>
    <Abbrev>Cun</Abbrev>
    <Description>
    [H4]Cunning[h4]

[P]Cunning reflects how crafty, devious, clever, and creative a character can be. Characters with a high Cunning are savvy, quickly pick up on social and environmental clues, and can more readily come up with short-term plans and tactics. Cunning is used for a number of mental skills, such as Deception, Perception, and Survival.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="16">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="23">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="24">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Characteristic>
  <Characteristic>
    <Key>WIL</Key>
    <Name>Willpower</Name>
    <Abbrev>Wil</Abbrev>
    <Description>
    [H4]Willpower[h4]

[P]The Willpower characteristic reflects a character's discipline, self-control, mental fortitude, and faith. Characters with a high Willpower can withstand stress and fatigue, remain composed during chaotic situations, and exert influence over the weaker-willed. Willpower is used for a number of skills, such as Coercion and Vigilance. Willpower is also used to determine a character's starting strain threshold. </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="16">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="23">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="25">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Characteristic>
  <Characteristic>
    <Key>PR</Key>
    <Name>Presence</Name>
    <Abbrev>Pr</Abbrev>
    <Description>
    [H4]Presence[h4]

[P]A character's Presence characteristic is a measure of his moxie, charisma, confidence, and force of personality. Characters with a high Presence make natural leaders, draw attention when they enter a room, can easily strike up a conversation with nearly anyone, and are quick to adapt to social situations. Presence is the key characteristic for interpersonal skills such as Charm and Leadership. </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="16">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="23">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="25">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Characteristic>
</Characteristics>