<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Duties>
  <Duty>
    <Key>AIRSUP</Key>
    <Name>Air Superiority</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Air Superiority[h4]
The Player Character knows that keeping the skies clear of enemies is often a deciding factor in achieving victory. PCs that pilot starfighters and airspeeders, operate ground-based anti-air emplacements, or even hold the reigns of a flying beast are all dedicated to providing close air support and top cover for ground forces, and denying the enemy the same advantage.</Description>
    <Source Page="19">Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>ANTIISB</Key>
    <Name>Anti-ISB Efforts</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Anti-ISB Efforts[h4]
The Empire has a vast information network headed by the Imperial Security Bureau, or ISB. Characters with this Duty focus their efforts on undermining this network with actions that specifically target the ISB, such as feeding false information to its known moles, recovering captured prisoners from ISB detention calls, developing profiles of ISB agents, and ensuring that the hated agency spends its resources chasing dead-end leads.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>CAMAR</Key>
    <Name>Camaraderie</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Camaraderie[h4]
Each fighting unit is a family of sorts, and this is equally true within the ranks of the Alliance military. These
Commanders seek to bring the troops together in a way that fosters trust, respect, and pride. By fostering the bonds that
develop between comrades in combat, Commanders are able to strengthen morale and drive their people to fight harder
and better than other, similar units. Unfortunately, camaraderie can have unfortunate results—alienation from fellow units,
instances of hazing and initiation within the ranks, and overconfidence in the face of overwhelming odds.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Lead by Example</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>CHEMBIO</Key>
    <Name>Chemical/Biological Analysis</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Chemical/Biological Analysis[h4]
The Player Character identifies environmental problems from sources either biological (alien flora and fauna, viruses, bacteria) or chemical (toxic gases, poisons, heavy metals in the soil), The Engineer understands that environments can damage delicate machinery, make it seize up, or cause it to perform under spec. The environment can also affect the construction and destruction of structures, and harm or hinder soldiers who have to march through the terrain.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>CIVOUT</Key>
    <Name>Civilian Outreach</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Civilian Outreach[h4]
The PC believes that the Alliance fights for the civilians. That includes spearheading urban repair as well as communicating with the local population to coordinate and establish supply agreements and recruit new trainee mechanics. The Engineer's work doesn't change, merely the focus. Sometimes, Engineers integrate themselves with the civilian populace to provide technological resources, work with them in resisting the Empire, or prevent civilians from receiving retribution due to Alliance actions.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>CLEARSKIES</Key>
    <Name>Clear Skies</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Clear Skies[h4]
The PC recognizes the danger that infantry units face from enemy air power. A pair of TIE fighters can turn certain victory on the ground into disaster. This PC always has a plan to take out any enemy air support, whether through the judicious use of portable launchers, jammers, camouflage, concealing terrain, or even anti-air emplacement weapons.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Forged in Battle</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>COMBATVICTORY</Key>
    <Name>Combat Victory</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Combat Victory[h4]
The Player Character is driven to show that the Alliance can hold its own against Imperial forces in any troop vs. troop engagement. He wants to engage the Empire's military—their best, whenever possible—and provide more victories for the Alliance to tout to the galaxy as proof it can ultimately win the war. This means daring raids, excellent tactics, and acquiring the best firepower possible.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>COMM</Key>
    <Name>Communications</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Communications[h4]
Player Characters with this Duty understand that the Empire maintains its stranglehold on the galaxy via a strong communications network. Whether working locally or across the galaxy, they specialize in deciphering Imperial communications as well as encrypting and concealing Rebel transmissions. Often these PCs are on the forefront of innovative communication methods, such as using special patterns on fabrics to alert agents of enemy activities of inserting code into Imperial broadcasts to pass secret messages to sleeper agents.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>COMMFAC</Key>
    <Name>Communication Facilitation</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Communication Facilitation[h4]
The Rebel Alliance is a scattered, often inconsistent organization. Alliance Command occasionally gathers the fleet for big, critical strikes, but usually individual Rebel cells work independently. The PC acts as an intermediary between leadership and other Rebel cells, ensuring that his group is coordinated with others, preventing accidental collisions.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Desperate Allies</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>COUNTERINTELLIGENCE</Key>
    <Name>Counter Intelligence</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Counter Intelligence[h4]
The PC knows that the survival of the Alliance depends upon its ability to hide from the Empire and avoid complete destruction at the hands of its overwhelming military superiority. To this end, he wants to hunt down and eliminate enemy agents and threats, feed false information to Imperial intelligence networks, and cover the movements of all Alliance assets from observation and reporting.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>COUNTERMEAS</Key>
    <Name>Countermeasures</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Countermeasures[h4]
Characters with this Duty serve as cryptographers, secure communications specialists, and data manipulators. Whether spreading false transmissions across subspace or the HoloNet, crafting new electronic protection to keep Rebel data secure, or slicing into Imperial transmissions and data vaults, they are phantoms in the code, capable of weaving digital misdirection while ensuring Rebel electronics remain secure.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>DISREL</Key>
    <Name>Disaster Relief</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Disaster Relief[h4]
While similar to Civilian Outreach, Disaster Relief involves procuring and delivering medical supplies, food, water, and temporary shelters after natural or artificial disasters. This PC destroys fallen buildings to clear areas for traffic and repairs buildings to provide safe places to congregate. Ground vehicles, ships, and droids need to be repaired or repurposed to handle rubble and tight urban environments. These Engineers try to help get civilians' live back to normal.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>DOUBLEAGENT</Key>
    <Name>Double Agent Recruitment</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Double Agent Recruitment[h4]
PCs selecting this Duty focus on turning Imperial personnel—especially its spies—into Rebellion assets. By playing on the sentiments of those who remain idealistic about the betterment of the galaxy, they gain valuable insight from individuals in positions of trust within the Empire. When that fails, tactics such as blackmail, extortion, and other coercive efforts may be necessary in these desperate times.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>DROIDRETASK</Key>
    <Name>Droid Retasking</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Droid Retasking[h4]
While the Empire seems to have an infinite number of organic beings in its service, droids also play a critical role in almost all Imperial operations. PCs with this Duty focus their efforts on disabling and reprogramming these droids to gather intelligence or even setting them against their Imperial masters. By attacking this vulnerable and often-overlooked Imperial resource, such PCs provide vital aid to the Rebel Alliance.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>ENEMYDEMOR</Key>
    <Name>Enemy Demoralization</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Enemy Demoralization[h4]
Undermining enemies' psychological ability to wage war is just as important as defeating them in
battle. Commanders realize this, and do their best to ensure that the Empire suffers every defeat on a psychological level.
By fostering a unit's notoriety, a Commanders can ensure that that its reputation precedes it among the enemy, thereby
weakening the enemy’s resolve before a fight even begins. Once a battle is won, a Commander must ensure that the enemy
knows it’s been soundly beaten, though the Commander must take care not to resort to the Empire's brand of brutality.
</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Lead by Example</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>ENVMANIP</Key>
    <Name>Environmental Manipulation</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Environmental Manipulation[h4]
These PCs use their skills to alter the environment to clear the way or obstruct passage. This includes constructing and destroying bridges, burrowing around natural and artificial obstructions, and improving or impeding movement. These Engineers also manipulate the environment of outer space, exciting the ions in a nebula to provide sensor cover or harnessing the electromagnetic core of an asteroid to protect a fleet from a solar flare.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>FIELDTRAIN</Key>
    <Name>Field Training</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Field Training[h4]
The PC trains new Engineers and rank-and-file soldiers to use new and old specialty equipment. Some bases schedule classes and provide classroom space so that Engineers can become full-time instructors. Most Alliance outposts don't have these luxuries, however, so Engineers teach by training in the field. Field training includes teaching civilians with potential, either to assist their own communities or to serve as contracted help for the Alliance.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>GROUNDSUP</Key>
    <Name>Ground Superiority</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Ground Superiority[h4]
No matter how good air support might be, battles are eventually decided on the ground. This PC knows that taking out enemy infantry and armor in combat from turrets, armored walkers and speeders, mechanized cavalry, and even traditional, mounted cavalry is what holds the line and wins the day. This PC is always on the lookout for key enemy ground assets to disable and destroy.
</Description>
    <Source Page="19">Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>INSECURITY</Key>
    <Name>Internal Security (Cyphers and Masks)</Name>
    <Description>[H4]Internal Security[h4]
Deceivers know their own kind. PCs with this Duty focus on protecting the Alliance from moles, double agents, and traitors. They also help maintain safety by ensuring that strongholds, outposts, and safe houses remain undetected by the Empire. This sometimes includes ensuring that supply lines for these locations are maintained and kept secret.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>AddedItem</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>INTELLIGENCE</Key>
    <Name>Intelligence</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Intelligence[h4]
The PC knows that every victory hinges on knowing as much about the Empire's military might and other assets as possible. He is driven to gather any and all potentially useful data, wishing to locate vital and vulnerable targets for Rebellion forces to strike at. He not only wants to know what the Imperial military factions are up to, but also the state of technological research, economic policies, and other aspects of Imperial strength.
</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>INTERNALSECURITY</Key>
    <Name>Internal Security</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Internal Security[h4]
The most dangerous threat to the Alliance comes from within its own ranks. Any Rebel soldier, operative, or ally could be an insidious threat waiting to take an action at a critical moment to bring entire operations crashing down, costing lives and assets. Knowing that vigilance against these threats is the truest form of devotion to the cause of the Alliance, the PC watches for any and all signs of betrayal.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>INTERORESIST</Key>
    <Name>Interrogation Resistance</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Interrogation Resistance[h4]
Even the most skilled Rebel agent can be captured and subjected to Imperial interrogation. PCs with this Duty specialize in ensuring that they and their fellow Rebels have the physical and mental fortitude to endure interrogation. They also work to ensure that information critical to the Alliance is compartmentalized and secure, so that agents who are unable to resist Imperial questioning don't compromise the entire Rebellion.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>LEGENDCRAFT</Key>
    <Name>Legend Crafting</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Legend Crafting[h4]
PCs selecting this Duty work to create fictitious histories and evidence to back up an infiltrating Spy's cover identity. Known as legends, these false histories help Spies assume a cover identity that becomes a fully realized person and can be easily presented to others. These efforts usually also include planting falsified information or doctored holos into Imperial databases, so that anyone researching the Spy's cover identity will find a host of data that corroborates the legend, enough to pass rigorous examination.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>LOSSPREV</Key>
    <Name>Loss Prevention</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Loss Prevention[h4]
Ensuring that their troops are as safe as possible under battlefield conditions is these Commanders'
primary concern. They never send their troops into hopeless situations in which defeat is certain, preferring instead to
preserve their unit’s strength for meaningful battles if sacrifices must be made. If taken too far, this ideology can result
in weak commanding officers who lose ground because they aren’t even willing to try. They may gain a reputation for
cowardice, which harms both discipline and their own chances for advancement.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Lead by Example</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>MORALE</Key>
    <Name>Morale</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Morale[h4]
While the troops of the Rebel Alliance know their cause to be just, the hopeless odds stacked against them can be demoralizing. This PC knows that to have any hope of victory, the freedom fighters have to keep their spirits up, and works to help with this via well-timed jokes or inspirational gestures such as flying the Rebellion's insignia on the battlefield.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Forged in Battle</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>MUNITIONS</Key>
    <Name>Munitions</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Munitions[h4]
This includes the maintenance and use of ammunition and weapons that should detonate at the appropriate time, or at least shouldn't do so while within the soldier's gun or vehicle. Work with munitions also includes placing minefields, disarming explosives. and setting explosives to destroy environmental obstacles or enemy fortifications. Those who work with vehicles, starships, or droids often modify the machines to handle and use specialized munitions.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>OPPLAN</Key>
    <Name>Operation Planning</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Operation Planning[h4]
Efficient use of resources is a key to the success of the Rebel Alliance. Rebel strikes must be carefully organized to be as effective as possible, while consuming minimal supplies. The Rebellion can tolerate few losses. The PC recognizes this and takes it upon himself to ensure that each mission is engineered for success, with nothing forgotten or wasted.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Desperate Allies</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>PERSONNEL</Key>
    <Name>Personnel</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Personnel[h4]
More than machines, credits, or information, the people of the Alliance are the most important and vital assets there are, and the Player Character knows this. He is devoted to seeing to their safety, well-being, and capacity for success. No one should ever be left behind; the most successful missions might not achieve every goal, but they are successful nonetheless when no one dies.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>PLACHUNT</Key>
    <Name>Placard Hunter</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Placard Hunter[h4]
This PC seeks out the most skilled and famous Imperials on the battlefield, and takes them out head on. These duels are often recorded and released on shadowfeeds as a part of Rebel propaganda efforts to showcase how vulnerable the Empire is to Rebel assaults. Whether the PC sees this Duty as a means of testing himself or a way to help larger Rebel efforts, he is likely to be seen abandoning his mission objectives if a tempting enough target is fleeing the scene.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="19">Stay on Target</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Forged in Battle</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>POLITICALSUPPORT</Key>
    <Name>Political Support</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Political Support[h4]
Every blaster, starfighter, and thermal detonator in the galaxy is useless without the political will to truly challenge and overthrow Palpatine and his New Order. The Player Character understands this all too well and is determined to see to it that as many factions, systems, and sectors as possible come to the side—and the aid of— the Alliance against the Empire.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>PSYCHOWAR</Key>
    <Name>Psychological Warfare (Cyphers and Masks)</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Psychological Warfare[h4]
Fear is not only the purview of the Empire. PCs with this Duty attempt to spread fear among enemy forces in an effort to weaken morale and destroy the discipline that is the hallmark of the Imperial Army and Navy. They also regularly combat Imperial propaganda and look within the ranks of the Empire itself for personnel who might easily be swayed into joining the Rebellion. </Description>
    <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>AddedItem</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>PSYCHWAR</Key>
    <Name>Psychological Warfare</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Psychological Warfare[h4]
While Imperial stormtroopers might appear fearless and disciplined, others within the Imperial Army and Officer Corps aren't as willing to die for the Emperor. Some PCs recognize that it is possible to intimidate, confuse, or frighten an enemy to gain an advantage in an engagement, or avoid one altogether.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="17">Forged in Battle</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>RANDD</Key>
    <Name>Research and Development</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Research and Development[h4]
Engineers also partake in research and development for technologies and other applied solutions. Necessity is the parent of invention, and every situation, enemy, and environment creates new necessities. Research can include stealing technology from the enemy or finding it in a ruin. These characters set aside time and resources to keep their base evolving, growing, and learning; that knowledge can also be passed on to other Engineers at other bases.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>REBELBASE</Key>
    <Name>Rebel Base</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Rebel Base[h4]
[P]If a campaign is centered around a Rebel Base, then, at the GM’s discretion, one or more of the characters may choose to have a Rebel Base be his Duty. This Duty behaves much like any other, and the CM can use the following as guidance for how to reflect it in the story. If multiple characters choose to have this be their Duty (or one of them, anyway), the CM should consider condensing it into a group Duty. A group Duty is tracked cumulatively. Whenever a group Duty triggers, it counts as triggering for all characters who share in it.
Generally, when one or more characters' Rebel Base Duty triggers, the narrative events should relate to that facility and its inhabitants. [P]At times, this could be relatively mundane. The bonus to the PCs’ wound thresholds might come from the base staff recognizing their hard work or even doing something special to make the team more at home. Alternatively, when it triggers, it might mean that the story focuses on the base itself in some way. Perhaps the base comes under attack, for instance, and the PCs’ increased wound thresholds represent their desire to protect their home. Much like any other Duty, a Rebel Base Duty provides the CM with plenty of narrative hooks.
[P]Alternatively or in addition to any narrative ramifications, the GM can use the Rebel Base Duty triggering to offer the PCs chances to upgrade their stronghold. If the PCs are at the base, this could mean that an opportunity comes to them. Perhaps a smuggler reaches the base, offering to trade various important supplies for protection from bounty hunters, or a group of fresh recruits arrives and the PCs must train them to work as support staff and soldiers on the base. If this Duty triggers while the PCs are off-base, it might mean that they run across a unique chance to improve the base, recruit a new staff member, or get much-needed supplies. At the GM’s discretion, when the Rebel base Duty triggers, the GM can offer the PCs an opportunity to acquire one of the base upgrades found on pages 88-89 without paying the normal price in credits for it.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="87">Desperate Allies</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>RECRUITING</Key>
    <Name>Recruiting</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Recruiting[h4]
Every engagement with the Empire is a war of attrition, and that is a war the Rebellion simply cannot win. Nonetheless, more people must be found to serve, and they are needed in every capacity. Not only does the Alliance military need more soldiers and pilots, it needs more technicians, engineers, mechanics, scientists, doctors, slicers. and just about every other kind of worker. This Player Character understands the risks of recruitment, as well as the needs, and is constantly on the lookout for allies who are both talented and trustworthy.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>RESCUEREC</Key>
    <Name>Rescue and Recovery/Evac</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Rescue and Recovery/Evac[h4]
This PC prepares and plans the logistics and execution of rescue operations of both civilians and military personnel. While similar to the Transportation Duty, this work includes defense training, medical support, survival training, observation, and rapid deployment operations. These Engineers live and die by their comms; they need to communicate exactly where they and their personnel are and where they need to be at a moment's notice.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>RESOURCEACQ</Key>
    <Name>Resource Acquisition (Cyphers and Masks)</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Resource Acquisition[h4]
Blasters and bacta are important for survival, but Spies with this Duty endeavor to acquire other resources to aid the Alliance. These include enemy uniforms, Imperial credentials, and other tools of deception. Spies with this Duty are certainly glad to acquire medical supplies, weapons, and other necessities, but their skill set allows them to obtain equipment more suited to subtle missions. </Description>
    <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>AddedItem</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>RESOURCEACQUISITION</Key>
    <Name>Resource Acquisition</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Resource Acquisition[h4]
There are never enough supplies to fully support those fighting against the juggernaut that is the Empire, and this PC knows it very well. He is determined to seek out new sources of raw materials, food, clothing, weapons, armor, and equipment of all kinds. One spare crate of medpacs can save quite a few lives, and a handful of comlinks can mean the difference between success and failure on a mission. He will trade, beg, borrow, and steal anything for the cause.
</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>SABOTAGE</Key>
    <Name>Sabotage</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Sabotage[h4]
The largest and most powerful military force in the history of the galaxy is also the most vulnerable to acts of destruction and asset denial. The character is focused on disrupting Imperial operations in any way possible, whether it's the manufacture of weapons, troop movements, supply shipments, banking systems, or any other key operation, in order to make the Empire act more slowly and less capably. Truly showy acts of destruction also work to erode a population's will to support the Empire, or so the PC often believes (though the Alliance expressly forbids actual acts of terrorism).
</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>SIEGEENG</Key>
    <Name>Siege Engineering</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Siege Engineering[h4]
Engineers often set up and build defensive fortifications (bunkers, trenches, and walls) , artillery (gun towers, and weapon reinforcements), and orbital defense platforms (ground attack satellites, anti-ship satellites, and orbital flak). Natural formations such as caves, ancient temples, canyons, and even asteroid fields can form the basis of an outpost. This PC emphasizes the importance of this kind of constructive support in warfare.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>SPACESUPERIORITY</Key>
    <Name>Space Superiority</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Space Superiority[h4]
As the Combat Victory-driven PC feels about troop conflicts, so this Player Character feels about ship-to-ship combat and naval engagements. To him, the war will ultimately be decided in the stars, and what the Alliance lacks in sheer numbers, it more than makes up for in the quality and tenacity of its pilots. Every single space battle is an opportunity to show the rest of the galaxy that the Alliance not only can win the war, but is destined to do so.
</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>SUPPORT</Key>
    <Name>Support</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Support[h4]
Individually, the lone agents of the Alliance don't stand a chance against the combined might of the Galactic Empire. Only by working together can they hope to achieve a victory in this civil war. This PC is devoted to helping fellow Rebels fulfill their Duties by providing whatever assistance they need. Although he might not get the same amount of reward or recognition as the people he is helping, the PC has many more opportunities than his fellows to fulfill his Duty to the Rebellion.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>SURVEYENEMY</Key>
    <Name>Surveying the Enemy</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Surveying the Enemy[h4]
This PC focuses on the technical aspects of scouting. the gathering of geographical knowledge, and the mapping of data via the use of sensors, drones, droids, and satellites. This includes constructing physical and electronic camouflage to hide a Rebel base and any vehicle movements from Empire scouts. More destructive methods include eliminating similar enemy systems with electromagnetic devices, damaging probes or satellites, and providing snipers and anti-aircraft ordnance data useful in targeting enemy units.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>TACTINSIGHT</Key>
    <Name>Tactical Insight</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Tactical Insight[h4]
Wars are sometimes won before a battle is ever fought. These PCs specialize in gathering information on Imperial military tactics and using these secrets to exploit weaknesses in the Empire's deployment plans and combat strategies. They also attempt to undermine Imperial tactics by planting false intelligence in Imperial battlefield reports or allowing fabricated reports on Rebel troop movements to "fall into enemy hands."</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>TECHPROCUREMENT</Key>
    <Name>Tech Procurement</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Tech Procurement[h4]
There is no more prolific or productive time for technological developments than during a war, and this one is no exception. This Player Character sees the true opportunity for Alliance victory in the hands of scientists, engineers, and technicians. Not only can they get the most performance from existing machines and resources, but they can design and develop new ships, weapons, medical techniques, and equipment that can provide the vital edge necessary to survive against the Empire's might. The way this PC sees it, stealing the best developments of the Empire is a crucial way to even the odds.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>TECHSUPERIORITY</Key>
    <Name>Tech Superiority</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Tech Superiority[h4]
As a stick jockey, this PC knows that while having the best-trained crew is the most important thing, having that crew on the best combat platforms is a very close second. If not for Rebels focused on maintaining tech superiority, the Alliance never would have acquired X-wings, or created the A-wing or B-wing starfighters. These PCs are always looking to bring new designs, schematics, and the engineers that create them back to base.</Description>
    <Source Page="19">Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>TESTING</Key>
    <Name>Testing</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Testing[h4]
The Alliance often must procure new supplies and technologies from less-than-reputable sources. This PC tests first and tests often. The moment an Engineer neglects safety checks, devices become a dangerous uncertainty. Stolen Imperial technology also carries the risk of sabotage. This PC tests researched technologies and methodologies in controlled labs, during live-fire exercises, and in the middle of battle.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>TRANSPORT</Key>
    <Name>Transportation</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Transportation[h4]
This PC takes on the responsibility of establishing protected routes to and from a base and the front lines. The Alliance uses a wide variety of transports, ranging from swift airspeeders, agile corvettes, and blocky freighters to slow, wheeled haulers and even pack animals. The character might also recruit private or public civilian transportation organizations. While an army marches on its stomach, this PC would rather it rode instead.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>WETWORK</Key>
    <Name>Wetwork</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Wetwork[h4]
PCs with this Duty know that sometimes questionable, if not downright immoral, acts must be committed in the name of the greater good. The quiet death of a single key individual, after all, can save many lives or keep important secrets buried for good. They're willing to do the unthinkable for the cause, and eliminate or assassinate critical Imperial personnel to prevent or undo a greater evil.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Duty>
</Duties>
