<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Hooks>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ACADEMIC</Key>
    <Name>Academic</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Academic[h4]
For the student who seeks history, science, and other knowledge beyond the halls of academia, the stars can be an undeniable siren's song. First-hand experience can mean the difference between theoretical knowledge and true understanding, and the academic who understands the importance of the latter is the true master of his field.
[P]True exploration requires an appreciation for all that is already known, as well as a desire to add to that knowledge. An Explorer with a strong foundation in academia is armed with the knowledge to see himself and his team safely through many situations in which ignorance is a lethal failing. Big guns, fast ships, and all the credits in the galaxy cannot overcome a problem if there isn't sufficient understanding of what the problem is.
[P]Most academics learn quickly that life out in the Rim requires adaptation and versatility. One learns how to fight, how to survive, and many other skills as necessary if he doesn't want to end up a footnote in someone's journal. One also learns to make the right kinds of friends, trading knowledge for protection and expertise for mutual benefit.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="13">Enter the Unknown</Source>
      <Source Page="12">Fully Operational</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ACCREB</Key>
    <Name>The Accidental Rebel</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Accidental Rebel[h4]
The vast majority of the sentient beings of the galaxy have no desire to join the Alliance or serve in the Rebellion. They may not be ardent supporters of the Empire, but this doesn't mean they are willing to drop everything in their lives to go blasting away at hordes of stormtroopers or weaving a dilapidated starship through swarms of TIE fighters. They would rather go about their business and live their lives, hopefully out of the way of any battles or other trouble.
[P]Unfortunately for some hapless individuals, the galaxy has other plans. Cases of mistaken identity can result in innocents becoming wanted for crimes they never even considered. Receiving goods marked for Alliance use may find one or more PCs fleeing for their lives from Imperial agents or hired mercenaries. A friend's—or even casual acquaintance's—involvement with the Rebellion can saddle a character with unintended guilt by association. Of course, there are times when people simply find themselves in the wrong place at the wrong time and have no choice but to become heroes.
[P]Alternately, unexpected situations may cause an epiphany for someone who was previously not interested in getting involved. While it may be easy to ignore tales of injustice and atrocity when they happen far away from an individual's daily life, many individuals have altogether different reactions when they come face-to-face with the horror of the Empire's policies. Apathy is difficult to maintain when someone watches another sentient executed for seeking out, a family enslaved because of their species, or an entire population wiped out for political expediency.
[P]In such situations, a person's apathy can quickly turn to anger. That anger, in turn, often turns to action, usually with violent and irrevocable consequences. Once steps are taken toward open and direct opposition, such a character has joined the Rebellion in spirit, even if not yet in fact.</Description>
    <Source Page="45">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ACTIV</Key>
    <Name>Activist</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Activist[h4]
Many Sentinels start off as activists in some form of another. Even unawaked to the Force, activists find themselves fighting injustice through social and legal pressure. They spread awareness, organize bodies of experts, and push for new laws. on planets that have (or claim to have) progressive rights and equalities, activistswork out in the open—or at least not in hiding. On more oppressive planets, activists work queitly in the shadows but are no less effective. Those who fall to the dark side give in to their rage and desperation, their activism turning destructive for desctruction's sake or even becoming murderous in the name of justice.</Description>
    <Source Page="10">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ANCIENTORDER</Key>
    <Name>Ancient Order</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Ancient Order[h4]
[P]Some characters become Guardians because they are chosen to follow an order with a long history, which naturally prepares them for their eventual role. Such characters have likely known their intended destiny for a long time, many trained from birth. Their teachers may have also been Force-sensitive, or they might have been completely unaware of the mystical powers their students possessed. No matter how an individual Guardian reached this place, The PC's skills are a natural fit for this specific role that years of training entail.
[P]Guardians of this sort tend to be guided by a concrete code passed down by their ancestors or predecessors, though invariably, some rebel against even the most ironclad of laws and codes of honor.</Description>
    <Source Page="12">Keeping the Peace</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ANTIQ</Key>
    <Name>Antiquarian</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Antiquarian[h4]
Technology often seems an inherently progressive idea, and to many people it represents only efforts to build and improve upon the things of the past. However, some Technicians are actually deeply engaged in the past. The galaxy is unfathomably ancient, and over countless millenia, thousands of species have lived and discovered new ways to transform their environments to their needs. At first glance, manufacturing techniques used only in a single community on a backwater world might seem less advanced than those used in a vast starship constuction facility. However, these unique methods may produce results that are not directly comparable, or may even perform certain tasks better than their "modern" counterparts. The metallurgy of some societies whose members have never left their homeworlds have been found to surpass the industrial standards used to fabricate starship hulls due to the specialized techniques used by these enclaves. Other cultures have found inventive solutions to problems the wider galaxy never even thought to address, from creative energy solusions in absence of traditional fuels, to esoteric weapons that function on principles that still evade even the sharpest researchers and academics.
</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ARISTO</Key>
    <Name>Aristocrat</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Aristocrat[h4]
Aristocrats have (or had) money and perhaps a title. They may belong to an actual aristocracy, come from moneyed families or bear historic names that grant them privileges, even if only token privileges. Somtimes these privileges oppress another group. Like elected or appointed officials, aristocrats are bolstered by their position and hampered by the conservatism of the system it is part of. In this case, cultural pressures rather than bureaucratic ones maintain the status quo. Sentinels with this background may still have family and friend who search for them, providing a resource, a source of conflict, and an emotional tie that enemies might exploit.</Description>
    <Source Page="11">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ARTIST</Key>
    <Name>Artist</Name>
    <Description>
	  [H4]Artist[h4]
The Force grants people thoughts, visions, and emotions that some can't process, so they turn to other means to communicate these ideas. These artists often find themselves frustrated, driven to express an idea bigger than the artistic medium. While most artists create in order to find an audience, Mystic artists create to find answers. The answers can be personal, to seek enlightenment. The answers can be social, motivating others to be and do better. Because of art's emotional nature, however, artists can be tempted to the dark side. These artists use their work to shock, provoke, and upset-not to illustrate a greater truth, but to enhance those dark feelings, reinforcing hate and anger.</Description>
    <Source Page="10">Unlimited Power</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>AUGUR</Key>
    <Name>Augur</Name>
    <Description>
	  [H4]Augur[h4]
Augurs served a straightforward function: they exposed the truth to those who listened. They could have been anything from a fortune-teller to a psychologist, offering insights on what people should do, but also revealing hidden truths to help people make their own decisions. Some augurs received academic or institutionalized training, while others simply had an uncanny intuition (such as a village elder or community leader). Most were content with this role. The few who had the humility to delve deeper discovered the Force as the source of their wisdom.
[P]Augurs who fell to the dark side encouraged their victims' darkest desires and instincts, enhancing their anger and pushing them toward violence. These augurs sometimes inflicted harm on others, mistaking pain, deprivaton. and violence for a means to understanding.</Description>
    <Source Page="12">Unlimited Power</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>AVENGER</Key>
    <Name>The Avenger</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Avenger[h4]
Some say a man who seeks vengeance should dig two graves: one for his target, and one for himself. However, these words never seem to reach the beings who need to hear it most. Following the one that wronged him, this character is in pursuit of righteous vengeance, leaving everything else he knew and loved behind. He lives a life of quiet desperation, planning his revenge and stalking his prey. The character does what he has to do to survive until he delivers retribution. He is proud to wield a blaster for any employer, especially if that gets him closer to his goal.
[P]Characters with this backstory should consider choosing their Obligation (with GM approval) instead of rolling randomly, so that it aligns with their background. Alternately, they can tie their Motivation into their background instead.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="14">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
      <Source Page="12">Forged in Battle</Source>
      <Source Page="12">Knights of Fate</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>BATTLEADER</Key>
    <Name>Battlefield Leader</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Battlefield Leader[h4]
[P]Being the first to battle necessarily means putting oneself in harm's way. A Guardian who jumps into the fray first and leads every charge has likely taken a lifetime's worth of hits. Guardians of this sort often leap before they look, and consider risks to themselves to be acceptable as long as they can protect the ones they lead in battle.
[P]Characters of this sort also tend to make moral judgments on the fly, doing what they see as right in the moment rather than binding themselves to any specific code. Still, some - especially those who go on to command - develop a concrete philosophy of right or wrong over time, based on their own past experiences rather than ancient texts.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Keeping the Peace</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>BORNENG</Key>
    <Name>Born Engineer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Born Engineer[h4]
Some characters take to tinkering as children or as adolescents, displaying a prodigious skill with technology at a young age. A Born Engineer's precocious skill might have been learned from an influential mentor while growing up. The mentor could be a parent, an older sibling, a neighborhood mechanic, or a formal instructor. Alternatively, such a character could be a loner or misfit in a family or community that is focused on other aspects of life. Whether the character is carrying on the legacy of a mentor or fighting against tradition will have a substantial impact on the way the PC views technology. A character who honors a beloved teacher by continuing that person's craft will take considerable pride in technical prowess, while a PC who was scorned for early success might still be ashamed of these skills on some level.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>BORNNBRED</Key>
    <Name>Born and Bred</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Born and Bred[h4]
 Some Smugglers have never been anything else. They may come from a long line of Smugglers. They may not know where they came from, but were forced into the life of a Smuggler before they were old enough to make a decision for themselves. Either way, smuggling is all this Smuggler knows, and he does it well.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>CITSOLD</Key>
    <Name>Citizen Soldier</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Citizen Soldier[h4]
Citizen soldiers are commoners from across the galaxy who fight to protect their families, their planets, and their people. Though many such individuals serve in the ranks of the Rebel Alliance, only a handful reveal themselves to be exemplary leaders, especially in times of great strife. For these people, the Rebel Alliance is a temporary but absolute obligation; the only things that might end their service are victory or death.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Lead by Example</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>CONARTIST</Key>
    <Name>Con Artist</Name>
    <Description>
	  [H4]Con Artist[h4]
Force sensitives don't necessarily need to come from a background of enlightenment and self-reflection. Especially during these tumultuous times, Mystics can emerge even from a history of gambling, trickery, and swindling. Some used their abilities to con the wealthy or powerful, rationalizing that two wrongs do make a right. Others pulled cons to make a living while doing what they could to mitigate harm. A few did their best to ignore their conscience. What united these con artists wasn't their criminal skills, but a nagging sense that life could offer something greater. While a criminal life doesn't usually lead to enlightenment, when these con artists sought  answers, they found them rather quickly. After all, they could recognize a good con, and when the Force turned out to be the real thing, they became ardent true believers.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Unlimited Power</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>CRIMINAL</Key>
    <Name>Criminal</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Criminal[h4]
The reasons for pursuing a life of crime are as varied as the types of crime one can commit. Some are born into it. Some find it the only way to survive. Some are anxious to grab the "quick score" rather than work for a living. Some pursue crime as a way of life, understanding that it is a profession like any other and indeed one that requires immense skill and a little luck.
[P]Naturally, the farther one travels from the center of Imperial power, the easier a life of criminal activity can be. Criminals may well become Explorers due to sheer necessity, mastering the skills and talents required to find places to hide, ways to pursue their agendas, and means to survive and thrive.
[P]Additionally, the life of a criminal is not often one that is consciously chosen; instead, it is thrust upon a person because he has a horrible streak of bad luck, winding up in the wrong place at the wrong time. Grasping at any means of survival is the natural response, yet it can be nearly impossible to escape the life of a criminal once that path is chosen.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="13">Stay on Target</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>CRUSADER</Key>
    <Name>Crusader</Name>
    <Description>[H4]Crusader[h4]
These Warriors may have encountered someone who chose them to champion a cause. Initially, such Warriors might have been reluctant and needed persuading, or perhaps they have always felt compelled to stand up for a just cause. Whatever hardships these characters have witnessed, they have only hardened their resolve to fight for change and make the galaxy a better place. These Warriors like to take personal responsibility and to incite others to do the same. They are natural leaders, activists, and moralists who rouse the masses and encourage them to take a stand against tyranny. Depending on these characters' morals, their crusade might be anything from forcing corrupt merchants to offer fair prices to struggling locals, to overthrowing an unjust regime, to reclaiming some stolen relic of Jedi heritage. Crusaders do not accept defeat, and they take up arms against those who refuse to settle issues peacefully.</Description>
    <Source Page="12">Knights of Fate</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>CYNIC</Key>
    <Name>Cynical</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Cynical[h4]
Some of the most prized possessions of a Smuggler are the stories he can tell, both tales of his exploits and rumors he has heard on his travels. The cynical Smuggler has one definitive story: the moment that not only changed the course of his life but his whole view of the galaxy. Due to a traumatic even, this Smuggler carries a big chip on his shoulder. He's lost faith in law, order, or people in general. In a galaxy of infinite possibilities, this event could be anything from the destruction of his homeworld to a personal betrayal.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>DEFECTOR</Key>
    <Name>Defector</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Defector[h4]
Prior to joining the Rebel Alliance, defector characters were among the ranks of an enemy. Their former master was most likely the Empire, but even criminal organizations or regional governments that have crossed swords with the Alliance are possible. [P]For whatever reason—a moral quandary, disillusionment, or disgrace—such characters have defected from their original organization and offered their loyalty to the Alliance. Though accepted by the Rebels, defectors have yet to earn their complete trust. To make matters worse, defectors are fugitives who face certain death should they be captured by their former masters.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Lead by Example</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>DESUND</Key>
    <Name>Desire for Understanding</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Desire for Understanding[h4]
Having realized he has some untapped power at his disposal, the character now wishes to know what this power is. Simple research on his home planet or via the HoloNet has yielded nothing, so he must set out into the wider galaxy to see what he can learn about his odd abilities..</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>DISADV</Key>
    <Name>Disadvantaged</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Disadvantaged[h4]
 For most beings in the galaxy, life is a constant battle for survival. Whether on a planet under strict Imperial rule or some backwater moon far from any trade route, the career of a Smuggler becomes an attractive prospect, a way of exchanging the familiar daily struggle for a life full of potential. Work as a Smuggler is not easy, but the dream of one great score to set him up forever keeps him running the hyperlanes.
[P]The Smuggler with a disadvantage background is tough and a little rough around the edges. He may have lived in poverty, been a slave, worked for an oppressive employer, or otherwise had it hard growing up.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>DISSART</Key>
    <Name>Dissident Artist</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Dissident Artist[h4]
Some people have a creative drive that cannot be stilled, and craft works that not only give expression to their thoughts and emotions but also push others to question their own positions. The PC has always been an uncompromising artist, and his controversial works eventually drew the ire of the Empire. In the face of pressure to tone down his creations, the PC refused to compromise his art and redoubled his efforts, challenging the establishment and inspiring the resistance. He became wanted as a political dissident of the Empire, but is now a welcome asset to the Alliance.
[P]The value of an artist should not be underestimated. The character might possess an uncanny insight into how people of all species think, or he might have honed his skills and ingenuity through countless crafts and creations. Further, many artists have a level of celebrity that gives them unique access to people and places across the galaxy.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Desperate Allies</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ECCENTRIC</Key>
    <Name>Eccentric</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Eccentric[h4]
Eccentrics pursue engineering and science with reckless abandon. Though often highly trained professionals, they are unfettered by orthodox thinking, common sense, and even morality. They see endless possibilities in their chosen field, and they are inveterate inventors and innovators. Eccentrics constantly strive to push barriers and break molds, often to the detriment of themselves and those around them. They are the mad scientists of the galaxy, the cranks and dreamers who are too flighty or erratic for traditional academia but whose knowledge and skills, combined with their imaginations and ambition, make for powerful allies and dangerous enemies.
[P]There are few eccentrics in the Imperial military, as the rigid conformity and draconian punishments drive out or grind down such individuals. The Alliance, however, has more than its fair share of oddballs. dreamers, and cranks. Attracted to the cause by their freethinking nature, eccentrics from all manner of scientific and engineering disciplines have found their way into the Alliance. They are often brilliant, insufferable, and difficult to work with. On the other hand, they have developed numerous surprisingly successful technologies and weapon systems.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ECONOMIST</Key>
    <Name>Economist</Name>
    <Description>
	  [H4]Economist[h4]
Economics is the study of resource allocation, but deep in its heart, it is the study of people and their choices. These proto-Mystics saw patterns, an invisible hand that moved resources to people in need, enriched planets, and connected disparate communities, defying the black-and-white morality of a profit spreadsheet. Cold economic theories and practices can clash with the warmth and light of the Force, however. If a policy can make five million people ten times as wealthy, but at the oppression of one million, could that be argued as good policy? What promotes a fall to the dark side more than turning suffering into mere numbers to be manipulated?</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Unlimited Power</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ENEMIES</Key>
    <Name>Enemies and Antagonists</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Enemies and Antagonists[h4]
Simply put, the character rubbed someone the wrong way and found himself fleeing his former life. Even if the player decides that the enemy may not be the source of an Obligation, or may not be around any more to cause the character grief, this could be used as a hook to reintroduce the enemy later on in a campaign.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="38">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ENTREPRENEUR</Key>
    <Name>Entrepreneur</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Entrepreneur[h4]
The galaxy is overflowing with opportunities for those willing to search for them. The best of those opportunities - especially for someone with more imagination than money - can be found far from the galactic center, where societies and technology are still developing.
[P]A successful Entrepreneur in the outer reaches will surround himself with a team possessed of various skills. He may have a business plan, or he may simply seize upon whatever jumps out at him as he explores his environment. Regardless, Entrepreneurs who leave the safety and security of the Core Worlds are true pioneers, and they have to be adaptable and quick on their feet to survive, much less to thrive.
[P]The old saying about larger risks being necessary for larger rewards holds especially true for the Entrepreneur who explores opportunities in the far corners of the galaxy. Of course, without a great deal of luck and a few allies, the penalty for failure can be quite lethal.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Enter the Unknown</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>EXILE</Key>
    <Name>Exile</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Exile[h4]
While many Seekers choose their paths, some are set upon them by events beyond their control. Whether they are cast adrift by the will of the Force or just cruel chance is difficult to say, but these new circumstances demeand that Seekers adapt quickly. They might be constantly on the run from the past they left behind, dodging bounty hunters, Imperials, or even their own family and fromer friends. Alternatively, these characters might simply be cut off from what was once their home, unable to return becasue of the events that precipitated their departure.
[P]Although most exiles long for their past life to some degree. This longing is rarely more than bittersweet. By leaving the past behind, they have freed themselves from what once was and have plunged into a crucible of new adventures that call with an intesity their old life rarely offered. Any one might have to reluctantly leave their home, but the best Seekers are those who leave and never look back.</Description>
    <Source Page="12">Savage Spirits</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>EXIMP</Key>
    <Name>Ex-Imperial Operator</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Ex-Imperial Operator[h4]
The Empire's bureaucracy and its military employ billions of beings. The vast majority are happy with their lot in life, even under the harsh rule of the Emperor.
[P]Yet there are plenty who, for one reason or another, find themselves departed from their service. Some are simply fired. Others leave Imperial service hoping for something more. More than a few find reasons to escape serving the Empire because their freedom, or even their very lives, depend on it.
[P]The safety of such a move depends a great deal upon what kind of role the character played within the Empire before his departure. A minor functionary with little access to important information will probably be able to simply quit or resign, moving on to private pursuits. Someone who knows where bodies are buried and who did what to whom as the Empire rose to power, however, may find his way out very difficult indeed.</Description>
    <Source Page="16">Enter the Unknown</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>EXMILITARY</Key>
    <Name>Ex-Military</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Ex-Military[h4]
The galaxy is full of armies, from numerous planetary defense forces to the awesome might of the Imperial Military. Countless millions of sentients fight in the ranks of these forces, but countless more have served their time and left the military. While some manage the transition back to civilian life, many former soldiers find that their most marketable skill is their fighting ability. For them, mercenary work or even criminal enterprise is a lucrative (if dangerous) career choice.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="13">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
      <Source Page="14">Fly Casual</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>FAILEDINIT</Key>
    <Name>Failed Initiate</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Failed Initiate[h4]
Not all who served in the now-destroyed Jedi Order rose to the rank of Knight. In fact, a great many did not even achieve the status of Padawan. Whether their connection to the Force was judged too weak, they did not possess the maturity to become Padawans when the time came, or no Jedi Knight would accept them into their apprenticeship, they never rose beyond the rank of Initiate. While many of these failed initiates entered the Jedi Service Corps, where they could serve as aides to the order, some simply turned their backs on the organization they felt had abandoned them. With the Empire now ruling the galaxy and the Jedi Knights exterminated, the failed initiates travel the galaxy, finding their own path in the Force.
[P]Other failed initiates received training in traditions outside the Jedi Order, taking lessons from hidden mentors and ecentric wizards before either striking out on their own or being forced into the life of a fugitive by the Galactic Empire or other organizations. They have a great potential, but their lack of understanding may place them on a dangerous path.</Description>
    <Source Page="11">Disciples of Harmony</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>FAILLEAD</Key>
    <Name>The Failed Leader</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Failed Leader[h4]
Not everyone is born to lead. Many individuals are thrust into positions of power against their will, or discover their shortcomings as leaders when it’s too late. These characters are such souls, who, through lack of skill or blatant misfortune, have failed in their attempts to command their people. Whether they have learned from their mistakes, or even recognize the mistakes for what they are, can be a pivotal decision when creating such Commanders. What remains to be seen is how they use the lessons they’ve learned, if they’ve learned them at all, and whether they can earn back the respect they’ve lost—that of their peers, as well as their own.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Lead by Example</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>FALLENNOBLE</Key>
    <Name>Fallen Noble</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Fallen Noble[h4]
There are millions - perhaps billions - of noble families throughout the galaxy, and quite a few of them have black sheep. An aristocrat with a poor reputation finds life in the Core Worlds difficult, perhaps even impossible. The outer reaches offer opportunities for redemption, or at least a chance to start over, for the noble who needs to escape scandal or worse.
[P]Nobles rarely have to pursue any kind of profession. Many, however, enjoy various hobbies and intellectual pursuits, which they invariably learn how to parley into an actual occupation once forced out of their comfortable lifestyles. Naturally, a noble may have to engage in a great deal of on-the-job training to really understand his pursuits. Necessity can be a wonderful motivator in such circumstances.
[P]Whether others even know if one is a noble has a lot to do with the measures he takes to maintain that secret. He may decide that being open about it will somehow give him advantages when dealing with others. If he's smart, however, he will likely go out of his way to suppress that part of his background, preferring to avoid attention on his troubled past.</Description>
    <Source Page="16">Enter the Unknown</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>FLAW</Key>
    <Name>A Failure of Character</Name>
    <Description>
	  [H4]A Failure of Character[h4]
Some inherent flaw in the character causes him to leave behind the life he knew for the unknown. This background hook ties in well with some Obligations such as Addiction, Obsession, or Betrayal. Regardless of the cause, the character finds himself shut out from his former society, left to deal with his own problems. However, the character may view this in a positive light, seeing himself freed from the pressures of scrutiny or keeping on the move to leave trouble behind.</Description>
    <Source Page="38">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>FLEEEMP</Key>
    <Name>Fleeing the Empire</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Fleeing the Empire[h4]
The Empire hunts down Force users diligently and enthusiastically. The character may have betrayed his affinity to the Force in some way, perhaps by anticipating someone's thoughts or saving someone's life by stopping a crashing speeder with his mind. Whatever the cause, the character is now hunted by Imperial agents and must flee his former life or be destroyed.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>FREERUNNER</Key>
    <Name>Freerunner</Name>
    <Description>
	  [H4]Freerunner[h4]
Freerunners turn movement into a highly skilled and specialized art form, using speed, strength, and agility to traverse terrain and cityscapes via quick, unexpected, and sometimes risky routes. To keep moving, they use any reachable surface, whether horizontal, vertical, or somewhere in between. They rapidly cross otherwise impassable or difficult terrain, and their fast and erratic movements make pursuit extremely difficult, if not impossible, for untrained pursuers.
[P]Freerunner-style drivers and pilots use their techniques to achieve similar results in vehicles and starships. Some were once stunt pilots or drivers trained to use their abilities in live and recorded performances. Other might have received formal training in tactical driving as bodyguards or security personnel.
[P]With a high degree of training and talent, drivers might spin a vehicle around in a nearly impossibly small amount of space. They can make spectacular jumps while rotating the vehicle about its axis in death-defying and gut-wrenching fashion.
[P]Species that are light, quick, and agile typically make the best freerunners. Their lighter weight means they can land and climb on weaker structures and smaller surfaces. However, strong and athletic species can achieve similar results when using their muscles to make longer leaps or knock aside obstacles.</Description>
    <Source Page="12">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>FUGITIVE</Key>
    <Name>The Fugitive</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Fugitive[h4]
The galaxy is full of those on the run from something or someone. Some people may be pursued by bounty hunters, while others may be fleeing local governments, corporations, or even the Empire. Many of these people are guilty of their accused crimes, while others are innocent victims of a miscarriage of justice. In either case, colonies provide a safe haven where a person can hide, reinvent themselves, and start over in life.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>GANGL</Key>
    <Name>Gang Leader</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Gang Leader[h4]
Gang leaders don't always organize their groups purely for violence. Some toughs gather together to protect themselves and support each other. Other gangs mobilize to become the unofficial police of a neighborhood, espeically in places where law enforcement refuses to patrol. Gangs are sometimes a symptom of a city suffering from the disease of an injustice, be it poverty or local persecution. They are only as violent and corrupt as their leaders, though, and those led by Sentinels might be the best forces of good in a city.</Description>
    <Source Page="12">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>GREATPOW</Key>
    <Name>With Great Power...</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]With Great Power...[h4]
Some individuals cannot stand idly by while watching the evils the Empire inflicts on the galaxy. The character knows he's been given a gift that few others have. To squander it while innocents suffer would be the height of irresponsibility.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>GRIZZ</Key>
    <Name>The Grizzled Settler</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Grizzled Settler[h4]
     This character usually began as a young idealist, perhaps newly married. He decided the best opportunity for his family were in starting over somewhere new, where the sweat off his back could build something lasting. Unfortunately, life on the frontier is hard, and what starts as a dream for the future can quickly turn sour as children succumb to exotic diseases or local wildlife, leaving some settlers stranded with nothing to live for. The grizzled settler has lived through the worst the planet has to offer, and if asked, takes a pessimistic view of any enterprise— if he does more than spit in response.
</Description>
    <Source Page="12">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>HIGH</Key>
    <Name>A Higher Calling</Name>
    <Description>[H4]A Higher Calling[h4]
Even in the rough-and-tumble world of [B]Edge of the Empire[b], there are those who strive to change the galaxy - often for the better, but sometimes for the worse. Perhaps the character has made a vow to help others, which works nicely into the Oath Obligation. A character may receive some sort of sign that tells him to leave behind his former life and make his way to the fringes of the galaxy to serve this higher calling.</Description>
    <Source Page="37">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="37">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>IDEALIST</Key>
    <Name>The Idealist</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Idealist[h4]
Many Colonists are exiles from more populous worlds, fleeing armed foes or haunting memories. Other Colonists, though, leave the Core Worlds not out of necessity or fear, but with more selfless intentions. The Outer Rim is home to countless settlements of sentients, and many of them are plagued by political instability, impoverished, or oppressed by local powers. From mining colonies threatened by pirates to worlds wracked by plagues brought by careless travelers, the point of light in the vast darkness of untamed space are threatened by many problems unknown in the Core.
[P] Most natives of the Core Worlds would not consider anything as radical as leaving the comfort of their everyday routines to aid individuals they have never laid eyes on before. Apart from the discomfort of leaving familiar surroundings, the Outer Rim can be extremely dangerous. Still, some individuals feel the inexorable pull of empathy urging them to leave their homes and routines to help their fellow sentients, while others see rendering such aid as a matter of duty, a personal debt to society that must be repaid to those less fortunate than themselves. Each individual has unique motives, but it is certain that there are many idealists to be found amongst those who strike out beyond the Core.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>IDEALREC</Key>
    <Name>Idealistic Recruit</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Idealistic Recruit[h4]
While those victimized by the Empire make up a significant portion of rebel forces, as do Imperial defectors, their numbers aren’t enough to threaten a single Imperial fortress world, let alone engage in conventional warfare with the Empire on multiple fronts. The Alliance Army is dependent on a steady stream of young, wide-eyed recruits willing to give their all in an attempt to restore peace and justice to the galaxy. Fresh faces drawn from every corner of the galaxy travel to secret rebel bases to undergo the basic training the Alliance can provide before deployment.
[P]Recruits come from all social and economic backgrounds, but those from the Outer Rim are most eager to join, having only heard about Imperial atrocities secondhand. Brave recruiters carefully spread propaganda vids across backwater planets and arrange meetings to discuss how the Empire impacts the galaxy, eventually swaying local youth to join the Alliance. Most rimfolk already possess most of the skills the rebels want in their recruits. Life on the Rim often teaches them resilience in the face of adversity, familiarity with ranged weaponry, basic equipment repair skills, and an eagerness for any life that gets them offworld.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Forged in Battle</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>IMPOUT</Key>
    <Name>Imperial Outcast</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Imperial Outcast[h4]
For obedient citizens of the Empire, success is said to come from joining the forces of law and order. Whether through Officer School, or as a bureaucrat in one of many local puppet governments, or merely as a low-level desk jockey, people from all worlds are encouraged to contribute to their government and reap the rewards of status and power. The PC started down this road, but events conspired to change his path. Perhaps the character became disillusioned with the chain of authority after being given an unsavory order, or he became a victim of the corruption and discrimination rampant within the Empire.
[P]Forgetting the mindset that comes from years of training in the Empire is no simple task, and the character is likely to feel isolated, like a traitor who abandoned everything he had. However, he is likely to find, amid the ranks of the Rebel Alliance, others who began as the Empire's brightest and eventually realized that they, too, had to leave. </Description>
    <Source Page="12">Desperate Allies</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>INDUST</Key>
    <Name>Industrialist</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Industrialist[h4]
The galaxy is home to a dazzling array of shipyards, factories, and industrial complexes manufacturing all manner of equipment, such as weapons, droids, capital ships, mundane tools, and luxury items. The PC comes from a life of work in such operations, perhaps employed as a labor captain, shift supervisor, bureaucrat, or possibly even as the partial or sole owner of such a corporation. Running an operation that makes and distributes complicated equipment is no easy task, but the PC has made a career of making sure everyone in the business operates in unison to get things built. An astute knowledge of resource management can prove a boon to the beleaguered Alliance.
[P]Unfortunately, many of the challenges facing the Alliance come to rest at the industrialist's doorstep. The Rebel forces are disparate, poorly funded, and frequently constrained to operating in secret. In sec-tors where the Empire's control is tight and regulations are strict, the character must reach into the depths of his experience to make ends meet.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Desperate Allies</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>INITMONEY</Key>
    <Name>In It for the Money</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]In It for the Money[h4]
Bounty hunters are, at their core, exceedingly mercenary. While many bounty hunters may claim to adhere to some higher order or serve a greater good, at the end of the day, they all serve one master—money. Those individuals in the business who have embraced their love of credits may seem crass and avaricious to others, but they are, perhaps, the most honest about their trade.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">No Disintegrations</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>JOURNEYMAN</Key>
    <Name>Journeyman</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Journeyman[h4]
Whereas academics tend to be primarily concerned with theory, journeymen take a more practical approach. Journeymen travel the galaxy, lending a hand where needed and making themselves useful to the general populace. They are licensed professionals, often with advanced degrees and unimpeachable credentials, who prefer to make direct use of their knowledge and skills rather than theorize or teach classes.
[P]Journeymen are often quite mercenary at heart. They wander at will, taking work where they can find it and dropping it when something better comes along. Many find homes among private militaries, tipping the scales in their employers' favor in conflicts. Some, however, are driven by something more than money. These are more dedicated to helping the needy and doing what is right than to personal gain. Many of these altruistic individuals serve in the Alliance military, fighting the Empire with tools, brains, and guts rather than blasters or starfighters.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>LABOR</Key>
    <Name>Laborer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Laborer[h4]
Laborers start off in menial occupations essential but less-valued skills and often involve repetitive, physical work. They often suffer economic injustices on the lower rung of the socioeconomic ladder. Labor leaders fit the Activist background better, so this background often reflects those who grew up in humbler circumstances. a laborer's strugg;es can be about moral corruption but can also include fighting against despair and drudgery.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>LAWBRINGER</Key>
    <Name>Lawbringer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Lawbringer[h4]
Law and order is not typically the first thing that comes to mind when considering the bounty hunting trade. Most galactic citzens, when they consider bounty hunters at all, imagine freewheeling loose cannons who skirt the edge of the law, useful only in desperate situations to capture difficult fugitives. While this is largely the case, there are some among the profession for whom  the rule of law is sacrosanct. These hunters consider themselves extensions of legitimate law enforcement or, in some cases. agents of justice in an unjust galaxy.</Description>
    <Source Page="16">No Disintegrations</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>LAWENF</Key>
    <Name>Law Enforcement Agent</Name>
    <Description>
	  [H4]Law Enforcement Agent[h4]
Plenty of current and former law enforcement agents dislike Imperial laws and enforcement methods. Personnel who observe or are forced to participate in the Empire’s oppressive operations may become sympathizers or join the Rebellion outrights. Officers and detectives have many skills suitable for a Spy career.
[P]Detectives, investigators, and profilers use deductive reasoning and similar skills to analyse new information. These individuals might act as field agents, or they may review incoming data. Patrol officers might have a combination of investigation and fighting skills.
[P]Law officer training depends largely on earlier experience, ability, and residence. Agents on Core Worlds usually receive high-quality training, and are well-versed in Imperial laws, with access to excellent resources and support staff. Agents from less populated or remote worlds are likely to have less training, staff, and resources and depend more on their own skills and experience.
[P]Officers on non-Imperial or more lawless worlds are focused on more regional laws and politics. They are often more concerned with keeping the peace than with following the letter of the law.
[P]These elements impact how law enforcement agents become spies and where best to deploy their skills. Many have extensive knowledge of, and contacts with, underworld elements and criminal syndicates. High-ranking agents know officials of similar standing, providing potential channels for unofficial information.</Description>
    <Source Page="12">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>LOCLEAD</Key>
    <Name>The Local Leader</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Local Leader[h4]
     Many colonies, especially the smaller ones, contain a core cadre of prominent individuals. These business-people, ranchers, professionals, and other citizens in good standing have a strong influence on a local community. A small colony might lack an established political system or authoritative central government. Instead, these local leaders step in to fill the void, doing what they can to keep their community running smoothly.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>MAKEUP</Key>
    <Name>Makeup Artist</Name>
    <Description>
	  [H4]Makeup Artist[h4]
Espionage field agents live in a world of deception and misdirection. Their true identities must be kept secret through technological, visual, audial means. It is perfectly acceptable to publicly wear helmets and masks in some parts of the galaxy, but that typically is too conspicuous when penetrating Imperial targets. While fake identities and falsified records can provide a degree of protection, sometimes it simply isn’t wise, or possible, for an agent’s true appearance to be seen.
[P]Makeup artists and costumers provide the required skills and techniques to turn someone into just about anyone else. The change could be subtle, with slight alterations to hairstyle, facial hair, and eyes. Radical transformations are also possible using high-quality theatrical masks, prosthetics, and even full bodysuits.
[P]Master holographic technicians may know exotic techniques for transforming an individual using advanced holographic imaging. Holomasks and full-body holographic disguise matrices can be extremely useful (though expensive) in the right conditions.
[P]The wide range of skills and experience among those employed in professional makeup artistry means that Rebel recruits may have any level of aptitude. Some may have specialized in broadcast preparations or amateur theatrical productions. Experienced professionals have more knowledge of successful techniques and more expensive supply kits than those newer to the field. In reality, most Rebel groups must make the most of whatever skills their members possess, along with any available materials and technology on hand.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>MERC</Key>
    <Name>Mercenary</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Mercenary[h4]
Not every Soldier of the Rebellion fights for the high and mighty ideals of the cause; some take up arms for purely financial incentives. Hired guns might have signed a contract with the rebels with the expectation of high risk, high reward jobs. While Alliance High Command has few credits to spend on mercenaries, some jobs are just too specialized to assign to Alliance Regulars. On occasion, the Alliance finds an alternative to Imperial credits for payment.
[P]However, most mercenaries find that once they begin working with the Alliance, it has a way of sweeping them up in their cause. Those whose hearts cannot be melted by Alliance idealism and morality might find themselves reported to the Empire as a rebel sympathizer and blacklisted from working for clients in the corporate world.
</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="15">Forged in Battle</Source>
      <Source Page="14">Knights of Fate</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>MILITARY</Key>
    <Name>Military</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Military[h4]
Military groups create effective Warriors. Characters with a military background are likely to be highly skilled and disciplined, having trained with an organized planetary militia or in the army of the Empire itself. Warriors who have left the military may have gone into hiding because of emerging Force abilities, or they may have simply lost the stomach for the Empire’s domination; either way, they retain all the skills and knowledge their training provided. No longer soldiers with colleagues to fight alongside, these characters are lone Warriors who may either harbor bitterness or revel in newfound freedom.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="14">Knights of Fate</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>MINVOICE</Key>
    <Name>Minority Voice</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Minority Voice[h4]
The Empire has built much of its power by taking advantage of conflict, ostracizing and exploiting smaller populations for its own gain. Some species, such as the Wookiees, are enslaved on their own worlds. Others are merely denied the privileges of the common citizen. Rather than choose to accept this injustice silently, the PC spoke up for a group victimized by the Empire's abuses. As a champion who fights for fairness for these outcasts, the PC highlights the injustices brought upon them. The Empire does not tolerate dissent, but the Rebel Alliance welcomes such voices.
[P]The minority voice is likely to be an outspoken member of the Alliance. With a specific cause to champion, the character has good reason to push the group to do more to help those in need.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Desperate Allies</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>NEWREC</Key>
    <Name>The New Recruit</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The New Recruit[h4]
Under the guidance of such wise administrators as Mon Mothma, the Alliance began recruiting efforts very early in its inception. Those skilled in the ways of intelligence, oration, and sheer talent scouting were employed from the start to build growing networks dedicated to finding those who had cause to oppose the Empire as well as the capability and the will to take action against it. As the conflict grows, so, too, does this network dedicated to finding bodies to fill the ranks and serve the needs of the Alliance.
[P]A Player Character may well be a part of the Rebellion because he was discovered by someone in this network—someone who saw his potential and recognized his willingness to fight against the current regime imposed by Emperor Palpatine. It might not even have been someone normally tasked with recruitment who found the PC; chance encounters by those connected to the Alliance with those who might be able to help occur all the time, and risks are frequently taken if it means an opportunity to gain the services of a capable and savvy ally.
[P]The cellular nature of most Alliance operations minimizes the risk of betrayal fairly well. Such recruits are tested considerably before they are ever given access to sensitive material or plans, and their awareness of the extent of the network they are connected to is kept to a minimum until they have truly earned the trust of their superiors.</Description>
    <Source Page="44">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>OFFICIAL</Key>
    <Name>Official</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Official[h4]
Officials once worked in the system, either in the local bureaucracy, law enforcement, a religious organization, or the Empire itself. From their chairs and desks, they had access to those in power, but ironically, they had  little power themselves, being cogs in a machine built of procedures, red tape, and calcified culture. In an organization hostile to Force users, the official's title became a collar, and the positon a leash, forcing the official to abandon this rigid life if the pursuit of something more meaningful is desired.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>OPP</Key>
    <Name>Opportunity Knocks</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Opportunity Knocks[h4]
The simplest reason for a character to live on the fringes of society is the basic desire to grasp some opportunity or challenge oneself. A character from a hard, poor background may strive to better himself and jumps at the first chance to improve his lot. A well-off character may be bored with the steady rhythms of high society or realizes that his chances for advancement must come from his own hard work rather than waiting for things to occur. Lastly, this could be as simple as making a spur of the moment decision to board a starship bound for some far-flung part of the galaxy.</Description>
    <Source Page="37">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="37">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>OPPOR</Key>
    <Name>The Opportunist</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Opportunist[h4]
Founding a colony is hard work, but a generation or two later, when the hardest work is done but opportunity still abounds, the opportunist moves in with fresh resources. These characters are often looked down upon by already established families, especially those opportunists seeking a leadership position before the landing ramp is even fully extended. There are also colonies with corporate or Imperial interests, where a bureaucrat offworld might send in new leadership that has minimal experience. Opportunists are, at their core, enthusiastic and willing to take any risk, but often lack a key understanding of the beings they intend to influence. In truth, this understanding can only come with time.</Description>
    <Source Page="11">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>OUTAGENT</Key>
    <Name>Outlaw Agent</Name>
    <Description>
    [H4]Outlaw Agent[h4]
[P]Not all heroes are able to work exclusively for the forces of good. Sometimes, the only choice is between perpetuating the Empire's oppression and joining a criminal group in opposing it. Some beings are even conscripted forcefully into illegal operations.
[P]Still, working under the umbrella of a criminal empire does not mean that a character cannot help others. This sort of Guardian excels at making the best of a bad situation. Guardians such as these might have codes of personal honor adopted from the organizations they served, or they might see the idea of honor among criminals as a mere pretense that killers such as themselves use to play at being civilized.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Keeping the Peace</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>PEACETURNEDTOWAR</Key>
    <Name>Peace Turned To War</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Peace Turned To War[h4]
While many Hired Guns get their start in some sort of violent enterprise, not all mercenaries or marauders begin their lives as warriors. Some spent a great deal of their lives in an honest career or some other peaceful labor, before some pivotal event set them on the path to become the hardened veteran they are today. Whatever that event was, the character's personality is still defined by the work he did beforehand.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="15">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>PERFORMER</Key>
    <Name>Performer</Name>
    <Description>[H4]Performer[h4]
Not every Spy is a silent killer or martial arts expert. Most rely far more on the art of deception and social engineering than on combat abilities. Still, even Spies adept at social manipulation find it useful to be able to dodge and tumble when the situation calls for it.
[P]Performers can be great spies. Actors may more easily deceive other thanks to their ability to adopt new roles. They might jump between different personas at will, move seamlessly from one to another during a mission. Actors also have excellent memorization skills, allowing them to quickly parrot complex technical knowledge. Often, they can spot enemy Spies due to an impostor’s poor acting.
[P]Stage performers may be able to use some of their act in certain espionage missions. Magicians, illusionists, and sleight-of-hand experts can use their mastery of misdirection to deceive others and palm objects in plain sight. Singers and dancers can employ their skills in social events. Escape artists are naturally good at freeing themselves when captured.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>POLITICALEXP</Key>
    <Name>Political Expert</Name>
    <Description>[H4]Political Expert[h4]
Political experts found themselves able to see the bigger picture and used their time to change (or maintain) local governments. If only people acted this way, these experts thought, then these problems would be solved. The needs and desires of the community should influence the laws of the community, not vice versa. Emboldened or frustrated by the political process, these experts looked for something bigger and more meaningful, and awakened to the power of the Force.
[P]Not all political awakenings come with enlightenment. Some political experts didn't learn to serve their communities, and instead tried to manipulate them by appealing to their base desires and fears, or punished them with restrictive laws. They sought to control others, a seductive desire from the dark side of the Force.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Unlimited Power</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>PRIV</Key>
    <Name>Privileged</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Privileged[h4]
Whether wealth is won, earned or inherited some people just have a lot more credits than anyone else. However, bad luck, poor choices in trade, or extravagant lifestyle can quickly turn a rich person into a poor one. Some Smugglers have lived the good life but lost everything. Some may have even purposefully left wealth behind, tired of the strings attached or dreaming of a life of adventure and glory.
[P]The Smuggler who has known wealth, whether he frittered it away or had it forcibly taken, is not likely to have lost his privileged attitude.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>PSYCHOLOGIST</Key>
    <Name>Psychologist</Name>
    <Description>[H4]Psychologist[h4]
Spies are frequently after information that isn’t simply stored in Imperial databases. This can mean prying it out of individuals who know it or know how to find it. Psychological methods can provide an advantage in getting unsuspecting or uncooperative subjects to reveal what they know.
[P] Psychologists can thus be a great asset to espionage operations. Knowing the likely mental state and thought processes of an individual provides insight into what questions should be asked and how to ask them to gain a truthful and useful response.
[P]Determining how to ask a question and knowing who should do so are equally important. Insulting phrases, inappropriate protocol, and rude mannerisms can be detrimental and even reveal a Spy as a fraud. Crude and harsh language probably won’t get a Spy anywhere when dealing with prominent scientists or loyal Imperial personnel, but it could be exactly the right approach with underworld enforcers or smugglers.
[P]Rebel psychologists are normally educated in their area of expertise before joining the Alliance, which is important as psychology isn’t a subject easily taught in the field. Specific ideas and techniques can be imparted and used in isolation, but amateurs will often miss vital subtleties.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>QUESTER</Key>
    <Name>Quester</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Quester[h4]
Sometimes, Seekers are not content to bide their time in the fringes of society or to follow the guidence of the Force to hidden wisdom. They might do those things out of necessity, but more often than not, Seekers set their own goals establishing new trails for thei own reasons. Such Seekers, find a reason to go out into the galaxy, whether to wilderness, cityscape, or deep space areas, and track down a new secret, treasure, or target. Then, having found what they were looking for, they set their sights on a new goal. Questing Seekers are always in motion, pushing the boundaries of their lives and the galaxy alike. These Seeker aren't easily defined by their pasts, but rather by the missions they seek out new challenges and the methods by which they pursue them.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Savage Spirits</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>RECLUSE</Key>
    <Name>Recluse</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Recluse[h4]
Not all Seekers avoid the centres of galactic activity because they are pursuing particular goals or need to be on the run. For some, dwelling on the fringes of the galaxy is all they have ever known. Their paths may eventually lead them into contact with wider society but they bear the indelible imprint of their origins as outsiders. These Seekers may have come from a society largely undiscovered by other species, or they may have simply been born into a remote area that recieves few visitors. In rare cases, they might possibly be the descendants of other Force users, who fled the Imperial purge or even earlier calamities, and have grown up deliberately cut off from the outside world.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Savage Spirits</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>REFUGEE</Key>
    <Name>Refugee</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Refugee[h4]
Refugees have escaped violence, starvation, and persecution only to face similar problems in their new home. In some cases, cities are unprepared to handle an influx of refugees and have no social services set up to accommodate them. In extreme instances, governments separate refugees from the rest of the population and cut them off from economic opportunities. On other worlds, differences in culture create tenrions among the populations, and refugees face violence from the citizenry rather than the government.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Endless Vigil</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>RELECSTATIC</Key>
    <Name>Religious Ecstatic</Name>
    <Description>
	  [H4]Religious Ecstatic[h4]
Ecstatics allowed the Force to flow through them uninhibited. These people interpreted the Force through their own religions, adding insights and ideas that for some illuminated, others perplexed, and a few terrified. This "madness" and speaking for the gods were actually their attempts to describe their thoughts and feelings of the Force. When they discovered the Force to be a universal power, they didn't abandon their religion, but simply found the truths within, forging a new yet still traditional path.
[P]Allowing unchecked emotion to fuel religious fervor, however, can take an ecstatic toward the dark side. Mistaking fear and anger for religious insight can lead people toward victimizing innocents. Instead of listening to the Force, these ecstatics listened only to pain, rage, and terror, and then channeled it right back into the world.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Unlimited Power</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>RELSEEK</Key>
    <Name>Relic Seeker</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Relic Seeker[h4]
[P]The past lives on, even when all those who were there to witness it have become one with the Force. Whether holocrons, ancient lightsabers, or personal journals, relics of the past are some of the galaxy's strongest connections to its once-thriving Force-using traditions, which are now all but annihilated. Some Consulars recognize these relics as tangible and vital links to a bygone era and actively seek these treasures of insight in forgotten and abandoned places. More dangerous than finding them is keeping them, however. Those who are caught carrying a Jedi holocron, Sith artifact, or other trinket are instantly branded traitors by the Empire. They are hunted to the farthest reaches of the Outer Rim Territories, and even beyond. However, this does not stop the seekers of relics. Consulars know that if balance and peace are to return to the galaxy and those strong in the Force are to have a place in it, a connection to the past must be maintained-even strengthened-with the recovery of these lost artifacts. Relic seekers who discovers a dark side artifact may unknowingly be carrying the very thing that will undo them, in the hope that it can be protected from the prying eyes and machinations of greater evil.</Description>
    <Source Page="12">Disciples of Harmony</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>REPOSPEC</Key>
    <Name>Repo Specialist</Name>
    <Description>[H4]Repo Specialist[h4]
Not all Spy recruits come from honourable professions. Many already operate in the gray regions of galactic society. One such profession is the starship repossession specialist, more commonly known as repo specialist. Some work for legitimate corporations under Imperial licenses and laws. Most, though, work for shady third-party resellers, used starship lots, or even criminal syndicates. In any case, repo specialists use a combination of bounty hunting, burglary, intimidation, and stealth to find and repossess their target. While they might have the legal authority to do so, their techniques work for either side of the law.
[P]A tremendous range of security systems is employed in the protection of starships and vehicles. Some vehicles have nothing at all or only require a basic key or code to access and start. Others have advanced systems with sensors for detecting innumerable methods of attack. While high-end and expensive craft can be expected to have many layers or protection, even relatively mundane or innocuous-looking ships could be so equipped, if the owner is rich and paranoid enough. Combined with ray shields, traps, or weapons, these security systems can be dangerous and even lethal to repo specialists.
[P]Of course, none of that matters if the repo specialist cannot find the ship to begin with. While repo specialists usually get some sort of address or suspected location from their employer, vehicle owners behind in their payments are unlikely to remain in the area if they suspect someone is after them. Additionally, hyperspace-capable starships could jump to almost anywhere in the galaxy, making discovery efforts even more difficult.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Cyphers and Masks</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>RESPECT</Key>
    <Name>Respectable</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Respectable[h4]
It's entirely possible for a merchant to spend his whole career transporting and selling legal goods while keeping on the right side of the law, but sometimes laws change and he cannot or will not change with them. Or he might lose legitimate business and need to expand his client base to stay afloat. Either way, it is easy for a respectable trader to turn to smuggling.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ROGSCH</Key>
    <Name>Rogue Scholar</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Rogue Scholar[h4]
Knowledge can be a dangerous thing and rogue scholars know this. Emperor Palpatine builds his Galactic Empire on a foundation of ignorance and propaganda. Rogue scholars dedicate themselves to not only finding the truth but, more importantly, revealing it to those who believe the deception and propaganda fed to them by the Empire. The Force guides these characters in their quest for truth, and the truths they find can shed light on even the deepest darkness. However, Consulars acting as rogue scholars cannot simply shine a beacon into the void. That would most likely get them killed. Instead, they pass on these vital truths to those who can use the information in ways Consulars cannot. After planting the seed of knowledge, they patiently watch and sometimes guide, until it blossoms into the fullness of undeniability-a binding truth that no amount of Imperial deception can diminish.</Description>
    <Source Page="11">Disciples of Harmony</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SCIONOFALEGACY</Key>
    <Name>Scion of a Legacy</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Scion of a Legacy[h4]
One of the most powerful motivations in a character's life can be his parents or other mentors. Many children follow in the footsteps of their fathers or mothers, even if they do so because that is what is expected of them. However, living up to the reputation of an elder can be difficult even when that is what the character desires most. At some point the character's own life, personality, and morality might come in conflict with the reputation of his forebears, and he must change himself or break with the past.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SEARCHINS</Key>
    <Name>The Searching Insurgent</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Searching Insurgent[h4]
Once they make the decision to oppose the terror and atrocities of the Empire, many individuals go looking for a way to contact and join up with the Rebellion. As badly as the Alliance needs people, though, it's not necessarily easy to find Alliance members to talk to about signing on. The vastly superior forces and assets of the Empire make it very dangerous for anyone to openly support the Alliance, as many planets and people discovered in the immediate aftermath of the Declaration of Rebellion. Imperial Intelligence and related agencies—not to mention countless bounty hunters—are constantly searching for any and all beings connected to the Rebellion, so secrecy is paramount to survival.
[P]As such, finding a way to join the Alliance's efforts against the Empire can be a quest all its own. It could even be the basis for the start of an [B]Age of Rebellion[b] campaign. Hopefuls need to do a lot of research, investigation, and sneaking around to discover clues about the Rebellion and to avoid the attention of Imperial agents. At the same time, they must prove themselves capable and trustworthy to anyone with whom they might make contact. Such an endeavor is a very tense, very delicate game of cat and mouse at first; the searchers might even fall under Alliance observation for a time, not knowing they are being observed and judged while they continue to try to find a way in.
[P]Many who want to join the Rebellion do so in rather dramatic fashion, taking it upon themselves to simply start striking against Imperial forces and assets. Such acts can be foolhardy and stupid, but they can also be brave and daring. If the would-be Rebels manage to succeed without getting themselves killed in the process, they may well draw the attention of Alliance operatives who are willing to talk to them about joining.</Description>
    <Source Page="45">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SOTBUSH</Key>
    <Name>Bush Pilot</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Bush Pilot[h4]
Most agriworlds in the galaxy are the same: vast fields used to grow crops or graze herds, with long distances between neighbors. The farmers and ranchers of the galaxy typically use airspeeders as utility vehicles for crop dusting, herding, and transport into town. The bored youth of most quiet agriworlds almost universally chase adventure by buzzing the fields and threading the canyons of their homeworlds, imagining they are anywhere else in the galaxy. These young bush pilots often meet up and race through dangerous terrain unsupervised, and are among the most underrated pilots in the galaxy thanks to their extremely informal training.
[P]Perhaps the most famous bush pilot in the galaxy is Luke Skywalker, who honed his skills flying a T-16 Skyhopper across Tatooine's Beggar's Canyon and moisture farms with his friends. Skywalker went on to become the hero of the Battle of Yavin and a key leader in the elite Rogue Squadron. Countless pilots of the Rebellion come From similar, humble origins, and sometimes their lack of formal training enables them to surprise opponents trained in traditional combat tactics. </Description>
    <Source Page="14">Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SOTCLONEWARS</Key>
    <Name>Clone Wars Veteran</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Clone Wars Veteran[h4]
While many think of the Clone Wars as a conflict between Jedi-led clone armies and Separatist droids, the truth of the matter is that most combatants were part of local defense forces and resistance movements. Veterans of the Clone Wars are valued as instructors first, who pass on their valuable combat experience to bush pilots and freighter captains joining the fight. Still, when called upon to suit up, veterans are able to shake any rust quickly, and become lethal presences in any skirmish.
[P]The Clone Wars gave many Aces the chance to establish heroic legacies, which thrust them into prominent military or political roles in the subsequent Galactic Empire. Others quietly retired, any lust for combat they might have once possessed satisfied ten-fold. On the other hand, most Separatist veterans languished in exile on the Outer Rim or rotted in Imperial prisons. When the Rebellion against the Empire took shape, a number of veteran Aces defected from the Empire, came out of retirement, or were freed by the Rebels to assist in their struggle.
[P]The list of Clone Wars veterans among Rebel ranks is extensive, including Garven Dreis, immortalized for his sacrifice at the Battle of Yavin under the call sign Red Leader. During the Clone Wars, Dreis was a local defense force pilot at Virujansi, and flew alongside Anakin Skywalker.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="15">Stay on Target</Source>
      <Source Page="16">Forged in Battle</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SOTENTERTAINER</Key>
    <Name>Entertainer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Entertainer[h4]
Among civilians, there are few events more popular than a day at the racetrack. Spectators gather from across the planet to witness some of the bravest beings in the galaxy compete to find out who is the fastest. Between races, competitors often participate in exhibitions to hone their skills, test their vehicles, and dazzle spectators with heart-stopping maneuvers.
[P]Most competition pilots are peaceful, living only for the thrill of victory, and for feeling that unique bond with their vehicle that only comes from pushing it to the limit with daredevil stunts and holo finishes. However, if pushed into choosing a side in the Galactic Civil War, entertainers possess the precise control over their vehicles required to make them lethal combatants. </Description>
    <Source Page="13">Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SOTIMPDEF</Key>
    <Name>Imperial Defector</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Imperial Defector[h4]
Imperial academies at Carida, Raithal, Corulag, and Prefsbelt turn out a never-ending stream of officers, stormtroopers, and pilots for the Empire. The academy teaches standard Imperial tactics and maneuvers, so that graduates can assimilate into military units throughout Imperial space. The program weans out undesirables by design, and a fair percentage of each class of trainees washes out.
[P]While the curriculum emphasizes loyalty to the Empire, many cadets find themselves unable to execute what they see as unjust orders. These graduates often desert or defect to the Rebellion. A famous example is the mutiny of the Rand Ecliptic, which was led by recent academy graduates Biggs Darklighter and Derek "Hobbie" Klivian. Once in command of the vessel, Biggs, Hobbie, and a number of other sympathetic TIE pilots joined up with the Rebellion.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="16">Stay on Target</Source>
      <Source Page="15">Forged in Battle</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SOTPROTOTYPE</Key>
    <Name>Prototype Tester</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Prototype Tester[h4]
The tester's job is to stress new, experimental vehicles until they break. He pushes the limits until all the various ceilings and tolerances are defined, refined, and improved. Then, he tries to break the vehicle all over again so corporations can put out a reliable, thoroughly tested vehicle. When an Ace comes from a prototype testing background, he brings nerves of durasteel and more than a little luck with him. Of all the Ace backgrounds, the tester is the most experienced at dealing with a malfunctioning vehicle and making emergency landings.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Stay on Target</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>SURVIVOR</Key>
    <Name>Survivor</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Survivor[h4]
The lives of Seekers can be about more than just establishing their own path. Some Seekers find themselves directly in the paths of others, whether caight up in galactic turmoil, hunted by deadly predators, or always being in the wrong place at the wrong time. For these intrepid soulds their path is about taking everything the galaxy can throw their way and moving onward in spite of it.
[P]These natural survivors might view themselves as unlucky, or they might be too stubborn to admit any alternative route. A rare few even seek out increasingly difficult challenges through whcih to prove themselves. Whatever the reason for their trials their journey forward forges them into some of the toughest and most determined individuals in the galaxy.</Description>
    <Source Page="14">Savage Spirits</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>TALENTAM</Key>
    <Name>Talented Amateur</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Talented Amateur[h4]
Talented amateurs are almost the polar opposite of the academics, with little to no formal training. Instead, they are passionate autodidacts, self-taught tinkerers, or innate savants. While they typically cannot compare to professionals, they are often more creative in their approaches and think outside the bow more easily than those steeping in rigid and hide-bound academia.
[P]These talented and driven amateurs can be found throughout the galaxy. From the far reaches of the Outer Rim, to glittering Coruscant, amateurs live wherever machines and technology are readily available. While those who serve in the Rebel Alliance are from an incredibly diverse cross section of galactic species, cultures, and societies, they are bound together by passion and a common love of learning.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Fully Operational</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>TECHDES</Key>
    <Name>Tech Designer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Tech Designer[h4]
Some Technicians believe that no matter what problem a being faces, the answer always lies in building a better solution, If a starship engine is powerful, it can be made more compact. If a cybernetic amr is as precise as an organic one, it can be made even more exact. Technology transforms the galazy, and those at the cutting edge of design have the power to create a future in their own image.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>THRILLHUNT</Key>
    <Name>Thrill of the Hunt</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Thrill of the Hunt[h4]
The hunting of sentient beings is said by some to be the most thrilling and treacherous challenge in the galaxy. Though some beasts are more powerful, faster, or more savage than any sentient creature, few kinds of prey are more cunning. For most bounty hunters, the pursuit of targets from world to world and sector to secotr is simply a means to an end. For some, however the hunt is an end unto intself, and the payout for collecting the bounty is simply an added bonus.</Description>
    <Source Page="16">No Disintegrations</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>ULTAB</Key>
    <Name>Ultimate Abilities</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Ultimate Abilities[h4]
Some characters see their strange abilities as a sign that they are destined for greatness. They can do things that others around them cannot. Clearly, this means they are a cut above the general population. To leave their life behind is merely the first step in a journey that may see them rise to become the ultimate power in the universe. Whether or not they use that power for good—or for evil—remains to be seen.</Description>
    <Source Page="47">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>UNDTECH</Key>
    <Name>Underworld Tech Expert</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Underworld Tech Expert[h4]
In the [B]Edge of The Empire[b], it can be hard to avoid occasionally interacting with criminal enterprises and underworld culture. Many Technicians support and are supported by shady characters, if not by outright criminals. Specialised underwolrd techs can be highly prized when they fulfull a critical role in a larger organisation, bu the average Mechanic or Droid Tech is sometimes regarded as more expendable than a reliable enforcer. The character might be trying to escape difficult decisions from the past or seeking to advance within a particular criminal organisation.</Description>
    <Source Page="16">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>WANDDIP</Key>
    <Name>Wandering Diplomat</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Wandering Diplomat[h4]
[P]Inner peace and tranquility are hallmarks of those adept in the ways of the Force, but they are by no means easy states to reach. Consulars recognize that peace can be found in all moments, by all people-some just need more help than others. Wandering diplomats use their skills in the Force to help beings they encounter resolve conflict through discussion, concession, and patience. Whether acting as an advisor to a planetary official, a negotiator for a trade guild, or simply a traveling peacekeeper, a wandering diplomat strives to help other beings find harmony in the midst of chaos and stem the tide of the violence and bloodshed in the galaxy.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Disciples of Harmony</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>WANDERER</Key>
    <Name>Wanderer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Wanderer[h4]
Curiosity? Boredom? Tragic circumstances? A desire for something more? Whatever it is that drives someone to wander away from his home and set out among the stars, it must be a powerful force to overcome the fear of the unknown. Most beings are simply overwhelmed by the sheer vastness of the galaxy, much less the uncountable dangers they must face each day as they ramble across the hyperlanes from planet to planet. The hardy soul who does so merely because he is drawn to is either exceptionally brave or a touch mad. Perhaps he is both.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="18">Enter the Unknown</Source>
      <Source Page="15">Savage Spirits</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>WAYFARER</Key>
    <Name>Wayfarer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Wayfarer[h4]
[P]Some who follow the path of the Guardian are not content, or able to stay in one place. The galaxy is a big place, with countless planets, all sorts of strange creatures and civilizations, and naturally, innumerable beings who need protection. Guardians who follow the winds - or the call of the Force - often find others counting on them.  A wayfaring Guardian rises to the occasion, but neither allies nor accolades can keep this character rooted. After all, hyperspace is calling just as surely as the voices of the weak, the powerless, and the oppressed.
[P]Indeed, perhaps the need to protect others keeps this Guardian traveling - lingering too long in one place risks drawing the wrath of the Empire upon the very people the Guardian sought to safeguard. Guardians of this sort often follow only the call of their own conscience, unbound by structured regulations or explicit codes. Still, there are always exceptions; some who wander do so to fulfill oaths, uphold obligations, or pursue more esoteric ends.</Description>
    <Source Page="15">Keeping the Peace</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>WRONG</Key>
    <Name>Wrong Place, Wrong Time</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Wrong Place, Wrong Time[h4]
The character finds himself embroiled in a life of adventure through no fault of his own. He could have been captured by pirates, the sole survivor of a deadly plague, or even something as mundane as being unemployed and forced to find some new way to bring in the credits. Regardless of the method for the character's push from society, he finds it nearly impossible to return to the way that things used to be. The character must quickly adapt to his new and dangerous situation.</Description>
    <Source Page="38">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
  <Hook>
    <Key>YESTERDAYSHERO</Key>
    <Name>Yesterday's Hero</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Yesterday's Hero[h4]
 Once this character was the man of the hour, toasted in every shadowport from Kothlis to Nar Shaddaa. However, everything in this life passes in time, and whether through the machinations of a political enemy, the natural ebb and flow of popularity, or a legitimate mistake or miscalculation, the character has now fallen from grace. Where he once commanded legions, now he only commands the blaster at his hip. Where once he had limitless resources, now he scrounges for credits, his days of glory a distant and probably bitter memory. Regaining his former success might be his overriding goal, but it is just as possible that the character has given up on himself and simply wishes to avoid any reminders of his past.</Description>
    <Source Page="13">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Hook>
</Hooks>
