<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Obligations>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>ADD</Key>
    <Name>Addiction</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Addiction[h4]
The character has a strong addiction he must keep feeding. Whether it's a physical addiction to stims, dust, or alcohol, or a mental addiction such as gambling, law-breaking, or priceless antiques, the character devotes a lot of time, energy, and resources to pursuing or obtaining the object of his addiction. Avoiding this Obligation has an almost immediate result - withdrawal. The exact nature depends on the addiction, but the character finds it increasingly difficult to concentrate on even mundane tasks, often reflected in the GM adding anywhere from [SE] to [SE][SE][SE] to skill checks.</Description>
    <Source Page="39">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>ADRENALINE</Key>
    <Name>Adrenaline Rush</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Adrenaline Rush[h4]
The character is addicted to the rush of adrenaline he gets from battle. It was this character flaw that cost him his position at the upper levels of society. Now he must feed the addiction or the results turn ugly indeed. The character cannot back down from a fight of any kind, and often goes in search of conflict when things get too tame for his tastes. Should the character go an entire session without combat of some kind, the GM may add a penalty of [SE] to any skill checks in the next session (or until the character gets a chance to fight).</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>ANTAG</Key>
    <Name>Antagonist</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Antagonist[h4]
Not all Smugglers are Charmers, and given the contacts a Smuggler makes in his line of work, it's easy for him to insult the wrong person, group, or even species. This doesn't always lead to Bounty, however, since not everyone can afford the credits required for an official bounty. In these cases, the Smuggler just lives with the knowledge that certain parties in the galaxy would make his life very difficult if given the chance.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>BADREP</Key>
    <Name>Bad Reputation</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Bad Reputation[h4]
Whether deserved or not, some Smugglers find themselves with a reputation for being untrustworthy or difficult to deal with. This can make finding jobs a struggle. Since the best way to reduce this Obligation is to successfully complete contracts, proving himself reliable again, the Smuggler might find himself having to take the least desirable jobs for a while. Once he's repaired his reputation, he will be able to pick and choose again.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>BASE</Key>
    <Name>Base of Operation</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Base of Operation[h4]
  [B]Group Obligation:[b] When the base of operations Obligation triggers, the narrative events should relate to the base of operations. This could be
as simple as unexpected bills or an afternoon of repairing moisture vaporators on the South Ridge. Alternatively, it could involve a rampaging gundark breaking into the pastureland or a rival mining baron deciding to execute a hostile takeover of the PCs' land. The GM is free to make the narrative effects of the Obligation triggering minimally invasive, if it would distract from an important ongoing plot line, or an unexpected and major issue for the PCs to deal with immediately and personally.</Description>
    <Source Page="82">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>BET</Key>
    <Name>Betrayal</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Betrayal[h4]
This Obligation can work in one of two ways: either the character is the target of a deep and personal betrayal, or the character is the one who betrayed others. Whether it's as simple as a betrayed confidence or broken promise or as serious as treason or mutiny, the betrayal eats away at the character and affects his everyday life. The target of the betrayal may seek answers, compensation, or simply revenge.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="39">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Fly Casual</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>BLA</Key>
    <Name>Blackmail</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Blackmail[h4]
Someone has discovered one of the PC's dirty secrets and is using that knowledge for some sort of gain. To make matters worse, the blackmailer possesses evidence that could possibly leak out - a holovid, bank records, a weapon used during a crime, and so on. In order to keep the secret safe, the character must do what he is told, although the blackmailer is savvy enough to keep the demand simple enough to maintain the blackmail for as long as possible, generally demanding money or favors.</Description>
    <Source Page="39">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>BOU</Key>
    <Name>Bounty</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Bounty[h4]
For some reason, the character has a price on his head. This may be in the form of a legal warrant or contract by criminals, collection agencies, or even someone who felt his honor violated in some way. What he did to earn this mark is up to his background, and the severity of his actions can be based on the size of his Obligation.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="39">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Far Horizons</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Fly Casual</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>COLLATERAL</Key>
    <Name>Collateral Accountability</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Collateral Accountability[h4]
In the pursuit of a past contract, the character was careless. He accidentally destroyed the prized possession of some major underground figure or killed someone important to that person. Now the figure holds it over the character's head. Ambiguous threats and demands for repayment have become near-constants in this character's life, as the underground figure refuses to let him forget his responsibility. He has a financial blood price or other compensation he could pay, but it is astronomical. Until it is paid off, however, the guilt and fear are ever-present. If this Obligation is triggered, the character can suffer [SE] to some or all skill checks during the session (at the GM's discretion) due to this burden on his nerves.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>CONTRACT</Key>
    <Name>Contract</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Contract[h4]
The PC has a pressing contract to fulfill, whether it is legally binding or an informal deal. The contract may be for providing, installing or repairing technical items, or on call services. Fulfilling terms of the contract reduces the character's obligation, while putting them off or incurring expenses for the sake of fulfilling the contract might increase it.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="18">Special Modifications</Source>
      <Source Page="19">No Disintegrations</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>CONTRACTED</Key>
    <Name>Contracted</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Contracted[h4]
The Colonist has entered into a long-term contract with a corporation or government related to his work at a colony. In many cases, these contracts are how colonists pay their passage to the new world - a form of indentured servitude. Colonists might be contracted to provide bookkeeping, labor, or any other number of services. Failure to live up to a contract can result in financial penalties, imprisonment, deportation, or earning a bounty.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>CREW</Key>
    <Name>Crew</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Crew[h4]
The PC has an Obligation to keep a work crew or ship's complement safe, healthy and in work. Whether or not the PC usually travels with the work crew, this character serves as a mediator between the crew and outside individuals. The PC might owe the debt due from a time the crew saved the PC's career or even life through hard work and sacrifice.</Description>
    <Source Page="18">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>CRI</Key>
    <Name>Criminal</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Criminal[h4]
The character has a criminal record, or was accused of a crime (perhaps one he didn't even commit), and is somehow embroiled in the legal system. Obligation may be settled by paying ongoing legal costs, making attempts to bury evidence, or efforts to prove his innocence.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="39">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Fly Casual</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>DEBT</Key>
    <Name>Debt</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Debt[h4]
 The character owes someone a great deal, whether that debt consists of money or something else. Perhaps the PC has a huge gambling debt to a Hutt, is indebted to the Czerka Corporation for his starship, owes a wealthy family for patronage, or has some other serious financial obligation. To make matters worse, depending on who owns the debt, even fully paying it off might not get the character completely off the hook - if the character can get that money, he can surely get more.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="39">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Far Horizons</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Fly Casual</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>DISGRACED</Key>
    <Name>Disgraced</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Disgraced[h4]
The Colonist did something shameful, often some social taboo that isn't quite illegal. The shame and sideways glances from peers have forced the Colonist to seek a new life where he can start over free of embarrassment. The isolation of some colonies and cultures makes for some strange taboos not observed by the rest of the galaxy. Thus the taboo can be something terrible, or something as benign as drinking from a public fountain or showing a bare but innocuous body part.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>DUT</Key>
    <Name>Dutybound</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Dutybound:[h4]
The PC has a deep sense of duty that he feels compelled to fulfill, such as military service, making good on a contract, or following some sort of thieves' code. Unlike the Oath Obligation (see below), a Dutybound character has some legal or ritualistic bind to an organization or cause making it extremely difficult or detrimental if he fails to live up to that commitment.</Description>
    <Source Page="39">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>EXILED</Key>
    <Name>Exiled</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Exiled[h4]
Going up against politically connected members of the Galactic Empire is a good way to become exiled from the most civilized of the Core Worlds. The Colonist is not allowed to set foot in the Core, or any Imperial-controlled worlds, but is desperate to remove the stain on his reputation. While possible, the smallest misstep can be disastrous, setting progress back months or even years. There is also the trouble of bureaucracy and last minute deadlines that can draw the character away.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>FAILEDREP</Key>
    <Name>Failed Installation/Repair</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Failed Installation/Repair[h4]
A botched modification, installation, or repair job has publicly damaged the character's reputation and rendered the device, droid or vehicle inoperable. The PC must take action to restore the damaged item, and find a way to socially engineer a return to good standing in the public eye.</Description>
    <Source Page="18">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>FAM</Key>
    <Name>Family</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Family[h4]
The character has deep ties with his family that require a great deal of time and attention. This could include providing care for or assistance to siblings or parents, the management of an inheritance, trust, or family business, or simply mediating between squabbling family members.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="39">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Far Horizons</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Fly Casual</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>FAME</Key>
    <Name>Fame</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Fame[h4]
The character's reputation casts a long shadow. Perhaps the PC took a famous and difficult bounty, or owns a recognizable and deadly ship, or has beaten another well-known hunter to the punch in the past. Whatever the case, it is hard for the character to move unnoticed throughout the galaxy. This makes covert operations more difficult, but also means that informants are more likely to spill what they know when the PC arrives.</Description>
    <Source Page="19">No Disintegrations</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>FAV</Key>
    <Name>Favor</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Favor[h4]
The PC owes a big favor. Perhaps officials looked the other way when he smuggled in goods, or a friend got him out of prison. Regardless, the favors are stacking up, and soon he's going to be asked to pay them back or return the favor. This favor may be called in a little at a time, prolonging the Obligation.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="39">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Far Horizons</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Fly Casual</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>FERV</Key>
    <Name>Fervor</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Fervor[h4]
The character is possessed of a powerful drive to act based on religious or spiritual beliefs. As an Obligation, Fervor means that he cannot resist acting in accordance with his beliefs and teachings. He may even have those who support him in some way (thus explaining the resources he potentially attains due to the Obligation), further exhorting him to follow "the Way" they all revere. Consider the Archaeologist who seeks temples dedicated to a lost god or the Big-Game Hunter who truly believes that it his divine destiny to eradicate "monsters" throughout the galaxy.</Description>
    <Source Page="19">Enter the Unknown</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>FRONTIER</Key>
    <Name>Frontier Justice</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Frontier Justice[h4]
Life on the frontier is harsh, cruel, and unfair. Bandits and outlaws can get away with murder and more if the local sheriff is too weak to stop them. Some people are able to let that go and move past it. When the dead are loved ones, however, some can't just move on. The need to get even is so strong it dominates the Colonist's thoughts and dreams, causing him to obsess about the moment of exacted vengeance. The Colonist gladly betrays, abandons, or hurts anyone if it brings him closer to settling the score.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>HIGHRISK</Key>
    <Name>High Risk</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]High Risk[h4]
The Smuggler just can't help it, he has to take the most dangerous jobs and play for the highest stakes. He is a victim of his own pride, and his ego often lands him in trouble. This Smuggler has something to prove and, when challenged, he cannot help but take the opportunity to display his bravery, even if this puts himself and his party in harm's way.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>KEEPERFAITH</Key>
    <Name>Keeper of the Faith</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Keeper of the Faith[h4]
Much to many other freelancers' amusement, this character has sworn to faithfully uphold both the spirit and the letter of some code of honor. The PC believes very strongly in these edicts and adheres to them with an almost religious fervor. The character never knowingly breaks any of the rules laid down in the code, and may turn on colleagues who do so.</Description>
    <Source Page="19">No Disintegrations</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>NOTORIETY</Key>
    <Name>Notoriety</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Notoriety[h4]
If a Smuggler has Notoriety Obligation, then he will be unable to travel incognito, as his face or name may be recognized. This makes any jobs he takes on harder, if not impossible, to complete. This Obligation is only likely to apply in certain sectors, and the extent of its influence determines the size of the Obligation. The Smuggler's own behavior might have caused this, or another party may have maliciously spread information about him. If the latter, the Obligation could be reduced by tracking down the person responsible and stopping him. Of the former, the Smuggler may have to avoid the affected area long enough that the locals forget him, or he might significantly change his appearance or name to avoid recognition.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>OATH</Key>
    <Name>Oath</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Oath[h4]
The character has sworn some sort of oath that dictates his thoughts and actions, shaping his moral view of the world. This could be an oath to a deity, a way of living (such as the Jedi Code), or a willingness to sacrifice for the betterment of some group or cause. Whatever the case, the Oath should be both serious and make life difficult in some ways for the character. It is a personal and deep undertaking, possibly without a truly obtainable end goal in sight. Characters who do not live up to this oath face an internal and moral struggle.</Description>
    <Source Page="39">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>OBS</Key>
    <Name>Obsession</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Obsession[h4]
The PC has some unhealthy obsession that tends to interfere in his life, whether with a celebrity, a region, a political movement, a cultural icon, or some other facet of society or life. He must pursue this, possibly to the detriment of his health, finances, or well-being. A character with this Obligation tends to get along well with others that share his interest, but is looked at with pity, amusement, or even a bit of fear from others who don't understand.</Description>
    <Source Page="39">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>PACIFIST</Key>
    <Name>Pacifist</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Pacifist[h4]
This Colonist abhors violence, either out of a sense of morality or cowardice. Witnessing a violent act can incense or fluster a character so much that he is unable to think straight or control his shaking hands, or simply disgust him to the point that he can't interact with his fellows. If this obligation triggers and the PC participates in a violent act, the GM may add [SE] to any skill checks he makes for the remainder of the session. (This may be avoided through good roleplaying on the player's part, such as having his character always try to talk his way out of a fight, and if he's forced to do battle, only use weapons that stun or incapacitate his opponents).</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>PHILAND</Key>
    <Name>Philanderer</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Philanderer[h4]
Colonies tend to be small places, and if a being gets around, word about it has a tendency to follow close behind. This Colonist has no shortage of scorned lovers still furious over his or her never committing. Former flames have a habit of showing up at the worst moment, or causing delays when the chrono is ticking. The worst is when two or more flings team up to make life miserable for a serial seducer, or when spouses find out and decide the Colonist is deserving of punishment. Nothing is off limits, as all is fair in love and war.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>PRICENAME</Key>
    <Name>The Price of a Name</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Price of a Name[h4]
The character claimed to be someone else, taking credit for his accomplishments in a past negotiation in the hopes of a higher payday. The wronged party, either the person impersonated or the hiring party, is now angry. This enemy might respond by chasing down the character, spreading news of the duplicity, or demanding restitution to his reputation or his credit account.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>RESP</Key>
    <Name>Responsibility</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Responsibility[h4]
A character with the Responsibility Obligation feels a strong sense of accountability or relationship to a person, place, or thing (a responsibility to kin falls under Family Obligation described above). This could include a strong connection to a mentor, a strong desire to care for orphans in a given location, or taking on the needs of an under-represented minority.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="39">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Far Horizons</Source>
    </Sources>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>RULEBREAKER</Key>
    <Name>Rule Breaker</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Rule Breaker[h4]
Either the character very publicly and flagrantly broke one of the rules laid down in the bounty hunter's code, or everyone wrongly believes she did. Whatever the case, this breach of the rules of the code affects the character's personal and professional life in a very real way. Contracts dry up, colleagues refuse to speak to or help the character, or the character is treated in a condescending or irritatingly sympathetic manner.</Description>
    <Source Page="19">No Disintegrations</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>SCORE</Key>
    <Name>A Score to Settle</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]A Score to Settle[h4]
The character has always been rough-and-tumble, but somewhere along the way someone wronged him, and he never forgets a debt, real or imagined This could be as simple as someone promising him backup who then disappeared or someone bad-mouthing him in front of a prospective client Now, the character is always looking for ways to even the score.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>SERVITUDE</Key>
    <Name>Servitude</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Servitude[h4]
Although the Smuggler might act like he's his own boss, he is actually the property of another and must either hand over any earnings or evade his owner entirely. The Smuggler could deal with this Obligation by earning enough credits to buy his freedom, or he could kill or otherwise remove his master.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>SPON</Key>
    <Name>Sponsorship</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Sponsorship[h4]
This represents a legitimate faction that has placed a great deal of resources in the hands of a character (or a team) for some established purpose. For many Explorers, it is the common Obligation they will incur. It could be a mercantile consortium that sponsors a Trader in order to open up trade with a new planet or civilization or an Imperial agency sponsoring a Scout to investigate a newly discovered star and its planets. Archaeologists are frequently sponsored by academies or other scholastically minded organizations for their expeditions, and Big-Game Hunters may well be sponsored by a conservation group to thin a particular population of beasts... or sponsored by less savory firms to completely eradicate a particular life-form.</Description>
    <Source Page="19">Enter the Unknown</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>THRILLSEEK</Key>
    <Name>Thrill Seeker</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Thrill Seeker[h4]
Some people are addicted to alcohol or chems, others to gambling or other seedy vices. This character, however, is a confirmed adrenaline junkie, and chooses bounties not by their challenge or price, but by how exciting or dangerous they are. Avoiding the Obligation—perhaps by being a responsible business operator and considering every job's cost benefit analysis—results in an almost immediate case of excitement withdrawal. when inactive, the character is edgy, moody, easily distracted, and generally unpleasant to be around.</Description>
    <Source Page="19">No Disintegrations</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>UNDERCONTRACT</Key>
    <Name>Under Contract</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Under Contract[h4]
The Smuggler is under contract to obtain rare goods, transport volatile cargo, or provide difficult services. He can only put this off for so long. This Obligation is similar to Debt, but it allows the player and the GM a wider range of possibilities when determining the nature of the contract.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Fly Casual</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>UNFINBUS</Key>
    <Name>Unfinished Business</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Unfinished Business[h4]
The PC is working on a long-term project such as a complex computer program or a light freighter refit. It may be personal or commissioned work. While long breaks may be acceptable, the Obligation cannot be totally fulfilled until the unfinished business is complete and it weighs heavily on the PC's mind whenever the character chooses to postpone working on it for any reason.</Description>
    <Source Page="18">Special Modifications</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>VIGILANTE</Key>
    <Name>Vigilante</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Vigilante[h4]
The character has seen the wheels of justice grind up the innocent and let the guilty walk free. The character has sworn to take the law—or a version of it, at any rate—and bring  justice to those who deserve it. When taking on contracts, this character tends to pursue the most hardened criminals.</Description>
    <Source Page="19">No Disintegrations</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
  <Obligation>
    <Key>WITNESS</Key>
    <Name>Witness Protection</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Witness Protection[h4]
Some Colonists never would have chosen life on a distant backwater, but authorities have deemed it necessary to hide them in the witness protection program. The Colonist is being hunted by the Hutt Cartels, Black Sun, the Tenloss Syndicate, or some other galactic-scale criminal organization as a material witness. The Colonist was given a new identity and sent to an obscure planet to safely await trial, but the syndicate won't stop looking for him.</Description>
    <Source Page="17">Far Horizons</Source>
    <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  </Obligation>
</Obligations>
