<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>IC4ADROID</Key>
  <Name>I-C4a Combat Construction Droid</Name>
  <Description>[H3]I-C4a Combat Construction Droid[h3]
The I-C4a is a smaller, militarized version of the massive I-C2 Civil-Industrial Droid. Produced by Veril Line Systems for the Imperial Corps of Engineers, it is an autonomous construction and fabrication droid. The I-C4a is a long, slow-moving, slab-sided vehicle propelled by a versatile articulated track system similar to the one found on Corellia Mining Corporation digger crawlers. Like that of its larger civilian cousin, the heart of the I-C4a is a powerful and versatile fabrication system consisting of a fusion furnace capable of producing slabs of building materials such as ferrocrete, stresscrete, armorplas, and plasteel from raw or recycled materials. The I-C4a is also equipped with dozens of lifting, tool, and fabricating appendages that allow it to clear land and build structures at a surprising rate.
[P]An on-board droid brain programmed for construction and civil engineering controls the fabrication and construction system. In addition, two combat engineers ride along in an open-air cockpit to monitor the power, propulsion, and control systems.
[P]The Imperial Army owns the majority of I-C4a units, officially classifying them as restricted military-grade materiel. As such, they receive regular memory wipes. Those units that have fallen into civilian or Rebel hands develop fast-talking, obsessive, often distracted personalities and speak in a dense mix of engineering jargon and scientific technobabble.</Description>
  <Source Page="56">Fully Operational</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Droid-Operated Vehicle</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Tracked Vehicle</Category>
    <Category>Land Vehicle</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>1</HP>
  <Price>750000</Price>
  <Rarity>6</Rarity>
  <Restricted>true</Restricted>
  <BaseMods>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>[B]Tracked:[b] Treats any terrain as if it were one step lower in difficulty.</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>[B]Construction in the Field:[b] Can be used to fashion crude defense structures, fortifications, and other constructions.  Droid brain must make a [B]Hard([DI][DI][DI]) Mechanics check[b].  These structures provide cover for up to 20 characters and adds [SE][SE] to Ranged combat checks made against them.</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
  </BaseMods>
  <Crew>None (Droid operated)</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>150</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>2</Passengers>
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>1</Speed>
  <Handling>-2</Handling>
  <Armor>2</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>25</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>15</SystemStrain>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
        <Aft>true</Aft>
        <Port>true</Port>
        <Starboard>true</Starboard>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Dorsal</Location>
      <Key>BLASTHVYREP</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <SensorRange>Close</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>