<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>TL18BTRANS</Key>
  <Name>TL-18b Medium Transport</Name>
  <Description>[H3]TL-18b Medium Transport[h3]
A reconfigured version of the Suwantek Systems TL-1800 light freighter, the transport variant can convey a small party great distances in relative comfort and security. The initial run of TL-1800s flew with an error-prone navicomputer, but by the time Suwantek began to produce the purpose-built transport variant, this had been replaced with a powerful navigational and sensor suite, most probably overcompensating for the reputation earned by the earlier production run.
[P]The blunt wedge shape of the TL-series hull has been augmented in the 18b with an expanded living area along the dorsal spine just aft of the broad viewports of the cockpit/navigational deck. A broad bank of dual Y-v-6 sublight drives contributes to the small transport's perceived similarity to the Corellian Engineering CR90 corvette.
[P]Utilizing superior computing and sensor arrays, the TL-18b has become a favorite for those seeking an alternative to high-cost command and control ships for security or paramilitary purposes. Many large corporations, system governments, and regional combines use TL-18b transports rather than the more expensive diplomatic courier ships employed by the Empire and other powerful organizations.</Description>
  <Source Page="61">Disciples of Harmony</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Transport</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Medium Transport</Category>
    <Category>Starship</Category>
    <Category>Non-Fighter Starship</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>5</HP>
  <Price>157000</Price>
  <Rarity>7</Rarity>
  <HyperdrivePrimary>2</HyperdrivePrimary>
  <HyperdriveBackup>10</HyperdriveBackup>
  <NaviComputer>true</NaviComputer>
  <SensorRangeValue>srMedium</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one co-pilot, one liaison officer</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>400</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>4</Passengers>
  <Consumables>Three months</Consumables>
  <Silhouette>4</Silhouette>
  <Speed>3</Speed>
  <Handling>-1</Handling>
  <DefFore>2</DefFore>
  <Armor>4</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>22</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>16</SystemStrain>
  <Starship>true</Starship>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Turret>true</Turret>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Key>LASERLT</Key>
      <Count>2</Count>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <SensorRange>Medium</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>