<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>DROIDSPEC</Key>
  <Name>Droid Specialist</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Droid Specialist - Artificers for the Artificial[h4]
Like battlefield surgeons working on organic soldiers, Alliance Droid Specialists focus on making their charges functional for combat but often must sacrifice perfection for practicality. A Core World droid factory may have the luxury to produce repairs that return a damaged droid to a like-new state. In the midst of horrific combat or in repair bays lacking proper resources, though, Droid Specialists can't be fancy. When faced with dozens of droids, having to stop and reassess a custom configuration not only slows the repair work, it complicates the job. At the end of the day, if their mechanical comrades are fit for another day of support and battle, then their mission is accomplished.
[P]Droid Specialists receive [B]Computers, Cool, Mechanics,[b] and [B]Melee[b] as additional career skills. Characters who select this as their starting specialization may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]Droids serve two purposes in the Alliance: to assist their organic counterparts and to integrate with computers and other data storage devices. Some Droid Specialists see themselves like the sergeants of a droid platoon, treating their inorganic soldiers harshly but fairly, sending them out into battle without hesitation, and working hard to ensure the droids have the programming and technology they need to come back. Others have a colder practicality. Repairing a damaged droid takes less time and resources than replacing or building a new one.
[P]The topic of droid manumission remains a messy one. Various bases treat droids differently depending on their commander's attitude, the soldiers' attitudes, their morale, and the circumstances. Regardless, Droid Specialists tend to be protective of their inorganic soldiers. Whether it is because they recognize them as sentient beings or as valuable machines depends on the individual. The Alliance as a whole treats droids with more consideration and respect than the rest of the galaxy. Droid Specialists advocating on their behalf have contributed to this positive change.
[P]Although the Rebellion receives equipment en masse, Droid Specialists can't count on consistency or quality. As supply lines and alliances change, so do their sources of parts and droids. As a result, Alliance droids tend to take on a patchwork look much like that of their Outer Rim counterparts. Rebel agents can often tell how well a base is supplied just by the droids: If they look clean and relatively uniform, the base is obviously well supplied. If the droids appear completely different from each other (and have personality quirks to rival a rogue Outer Rim droid), then the agent knows the base is in dire shape.
[P]This is the difficulty most Droid Specialists face in Rebel outposts without a regular supply line. Organics tend to get the most supplies, followed by the machines of war: blasters, cannons, and starfighters. At the bottom of the ladder stand the droids, which must bear the brunt of rationed supplies while functioning to serve their organic commanders. Some Droid Specialists see this work as a punishment. Others come to identify with their charges. Droid Specialists often see their quartermaster as their greatest nemesis, the Empire being a close second.</Description>
  <Source Page="24">Fully Operational</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>COMP</Key>
    <Key>COOL</Key>
    <Key>MECH</Key>
    <Key>MELEE</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>DESFLAW</Key>
        <Key>SPKBIN</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>HIDD</Key>
        <Key>COMBATPROG</Key>
        <Key>REPPATCHSPEC</Key>
        <Key>GEARHD</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GEARHD</Key>
        <Key>MACHMEND</Key>
        <Key>HIDD</Key>
        <Key>SPKBIN</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>DESFLAW</Key>
        <Key>DESPREP</Key>
        <Key>MACHMEND</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>REPPATCHSPEC</Key>
        <Key>MASTART</Key>
        <Key>REROUTEPROC</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>