<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>SHIPWRIGHT</Key>
  <Name>Shipwright</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Shipwright - Designing For War[h4]
In peacetime, a Shipwright designs, oversees, and launches custom ships to grace the hyperspace lanes. During the era of the Republic, Shipwrights crafted ships with elegant fins, spires, and curves that made people wonder, "Who built that?" Currently, the Empire favors ship designs that express power and inspire fear. The Core World shipyards have followed suit, as the Empire remains the dominant culture in the galaxy. Elegance is a bygone ideal, a symbol of Republic corruption or a lost fancy. Even the Alliance often must eschew aesthetics for practicality and utility, something many Shipwrights in the Rebellion understand but mourn.
[P]Shipwrights receive [B]Gunnery, Knowledge (Education), Mechanics,[b] and [B]Piloting (Space)[b] as additional career skills. Characters who select this as their starting specialization may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]In the Alliance, Shipwrights primarily maintain and repair the various ships it fields. An important secondary task is the breaking down and retrofitting of commissioned starships. Since the majority of these vessels come from smuggled sources, civilian donations, or scrapyard rescues, Shipwrights have to determine if they should be utilized, scrapped, or junked.
[P]For ships to be added to the Fleet, they then oversee the installation of new or updated equipment and basic repairs. Then comes crew training, space trials and testing, readying the hull for hyperspace travel, and, for some lucky Shipwrights, naming and serving aboard them.
[P]Alliance shipyards tend to be hidden, remote, or highly mobile-often all three. As always, materials, supplies, and labor are the main factors limiting construction, along with time; at any point, the Empire may suddenly discover the location of the shipyard, prompting a rapid evacuation.
[P]Shipwrights can work on a space station or in its shipyard. Mobile Alliance shipyards can house weapon platforms or support mining and refining facilities. The more advanced shipyards resemble a fully staffed mining colony. In such a shipyard, Shipwrights must incorporate industrial components in to their designs as well as handle worker accommodations and support. At this level, Shipwrights resemble civil engineers. Even something as basic as organic waste elimination can be important to the Alliance. Only Shipwrights, for example, might know that the station's trash disposal hold can hide an allied light freighter attempting to illude Imperial patrols!
[P]On the rare occasion when the Alliance requires a new ship design, Shipwrights usually must throw aesthetics out the transparisteel window to aim for utility, safety, and reliability. Primarily, their designs must try to ensure that the ship and its crew can accomplish the mission and hopefully return in one piece. Good Shipwrights keep in mind that their creations should be easy to repair, offer a modicum of comfort, and be able to throw enough firepower at enemies to make crews happy to fly aboard them into victory.</Description>
  <Source Page="28">Fully Operational</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>EDU</Key>
    <Key>GUNN</Key>
    <Key>MECH</Key>
    <Key>PILOTSP</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>DOCKEXP</Key>
        <Key>EYEDET</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>CREATDES</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
        <Direction />
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SOLREP</Key>
        <Key>FINETUN</Key>
        <Key>EYEDET</Key>
        <Key>DEPSHOT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>KNOWSCH</Key>
        <Key>DOCKEXP</Key>
        <Key>SMARTHAND</Key>
        <Key>CREATDES</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>BOUGHT</Key>
        <Key>PUSHSPEC</Key>
        <Key>SOLREP</Key>
        <Key>CREATDES</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>MASTART</Key>
        <Key>STRGEN</Key>
        <Key>EXHPORT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>