<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>EXECUTIONER</Key>
  <Name>Executioner</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Executioner - Dealing Efficient Death[h4]
Seekers often focus on survival in hostile settings where they must rely soley on their own abilities. Such self reliance can also  be reflected in their combat abilities, as each shot or strike must end a battle as swiftly as possible. Merely wounding or dissuading a foe is not sufficient in these cases, as often only one party can leave the encounter alive. Executioners embody this focus on precise lethality. Many become feared across systems for their effective means of eliminating any threat that requires removal. Determining which threats deserve their deadly and personal attention, though,  can make for complex judgement calls. Such decisions and the methods by which they render them can also lead Executioners down the path to the dark side.
[P]Executioners are perhaps the emodiment of the Seeker career as apex predator, and they excel at the art of death. While other careers and specializations can produce effective fighters. Executioners are more concerned with maximizing the damage they inflict to ensure a quick, definitive end to their conflicts. Given their emerging connection to the Force theire are few who can match these lethal characters' ability to achieve this goal.
[P]Executioners recieve [B]Discpline[b], [B]Melee[b], [B]Perception[b], and [B]Ranged (Heavy)[b] as additonal career skills, reflecting their deadly and efficitent application of violence. Characters who select this as their starting specialization may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]Others might view Exectutioners as brutal killers, but this is a simplistic view. Killing is often the outcome of combat, but Exectioners might attempt to avoid conflict altogether as their aim is only for a fatal end for their target. This could even mean a target is eliminated by long range fire or a decisive lightsaber strike before even becoming aware of any danger. When eliminating one saves hundres f others or frees entire villages from suffering, many Executioners see their work as perhaps distasteful, but certainly necessary.
[P]Executioners are not always grim, dispassionate assassins, though many are driven by intellect rather than emotion. Some may view their calling as a righteous one, celebrating each threat they remove before it can harm others. Others might see each lethal act as a step toward redemption for past sins. Inflicting death should never be an easy act, however. Those who trivialize it or become too emotionally attached to their goals are at risk of becoming enthralled by the dark side of the Force—which some Executioners might not realize until far too late.</Description>
  <Source Page="24">Savage Spirits</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>DISC</Key>
    <Key>MELEE</Key>
    <Key>PERC</Key>
    <Key>RANGHVY</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>QUICKST</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>QUICKDR</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction />
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>MINDMAT</Key>
        <Key>HUNTERQUARRY</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>LETHALBL</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>LETHALBL</Key>
        <Key>HUNTQIMP</Key>
        <Key>QUICKST</Key>
        <Key>PRECAIM</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>TERRKILL</Key>
        <Key>PRECAIM</Key>
        <Key>MARKDEATH</Key>
        <Key>DEATHBLOW</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>LETHALBL</Key>
        <Key>ESSENKILL</Key>
        <Key>FORCERAT</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>