<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>HERMIT</Key>
  <Name>Hermit</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Hermit - Communing with the Living Force[h4]
While most Seekers are often solitary and self-reliant by nature, some go beyond this simple tendancy toward reclusion and desire to operate independently. A life isolated from the impositions and irritations of outsiders is instead the goal for them, so that they can develop their abilities and connections to the Force in relative calm. Free from outside distractions, these Hermits can further themselves in ways previously unimaginable to them. Those who can be convinced to rejoin society can be of great value, ont only int heir use of the Force but also in dealing with wilderness survival and deadly creatures.
[P]For Hermits, solitude is not necessarily a result of abhoring social interactions or lacking any skills with them. Some Hermits might ahve even sought remote life to escape from outside entanglements. They may have had crushing debts, had bounties placed on their heads, or even deserted from the Imperial military. Hermits who desire seculsion after discovering their nescent Force abilities may use their isolation to more fully concentrate on uncovering the secrets of their mysterious new powers. Meditation can not only help them become more in tune with the Force, but also strenthen their connection with nature and the surrounding wildlife.
[P]Hermits are not only solitary and self-reliant, but also seek to maintain their isolation against intruders and others who would disturb their reclusive existence. Some even hone their ability to avoid others to a great extent, the better to escape unwanted attention. To represent this, Hermits recieve [B]Discipline[b], [B]Knowledge (Xenology)[b], [B]Stealth[b], and [B]Survival[b] as additional career skills, allowing them to better develop their connections not only with the Force, but also with local flora and fauna. Characters who select this as their starting specialization may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]Despite their previously isolated ways of life, Hermits are powerful additoins to groups. When parties are stranded in harsh environments, whether sweltering jungles or barren ice wastelands, Hermits likely feel they are returning to their homes. Many find such locations more relacing than the intense industry adn frantic pace of typical cities especially in Core Sytems. Their skills in dealing with these wilderness regions makes them invaluable for ensuring the party's survival when the characters venture into the wilds.
[P]Hermits' skills in uncivilized areas also comes into play when facing dangerous animals or untamed creatures the group desires to use as steeds. Lving in the wild, Hermits often develop close bonds with their fellow creatures and can form companionships that might last lifetimes. Many of these Seekers use their Force abilities, possibly unconciously, to strengthen established connections with animals as well as to form new ones.
[P]Despite having lived in isolation for long periods, Hermits are not unprepared for conflict. Most have maintained themselves well, simlpy in order to survive in an unforgiving wilderness where weather and even local plant life can be as hostile as any sentient enemy. Dealing with dangerous creatures and honing themselves to avoid such attacks can turn Hermits into equally dangerous combatants. Overall, this solitude can build powerful individuals, able not only to thrive in the harshest of environments but also to aid others unprepared for life outside advanced urban settings.</Description>
  <Source Page="26">Savage Spirits</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>DISC</Key>
    <Key>STEAL</Key>
    <Key>SURV</Key>
    <Key>XEN</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>FORAG</Key>
        <Key>SOOTHTONE</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>ONENAT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>CONDITIONED</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>MENACE</Key>
        <Key>ANIMALBOND</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>ENDUR</Key>
        <Key>CONDITIONED</Key>
        <Key>SURVFIT</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>FORCERAT</Key>
        <Key>ANIMALBONDIMP</Key>
        <Key>HARASS</Key>
        <Key>FORCECONN</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>NATOUT</Key>
        <Key>FORCERAT</Key>
        <Key>SHROUD</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>