<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>MODDER</Key>
  <Name>Modder</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Modder - Obsessive Innovation[h4]
If someone keeps disassembling and reassembling the rest of the crew's weapons, armor and gear without permission, it's a safe bet that the culprit is the team's Technician. If those items actually seem to work better afterward, that Technician might well be a Modder. Modders are chronic tinkerers, and most  Modderswould rather add features to machines they already have than build new ones. By turning their engineering prowess toward relentlessly repairing, optimizing, testing, calibrating and re-repairing mechinisms around them. Modders make any piece of technology their own - even if it isn't, strictly speaking, theirs.
[P]A Modder can be extremely versatile; in some ways a modder specializes in generalizing. By spending less time and energy learning how to build devices from the ground up, a Modder can focus on how to optimize and customize all sorts of devices - from weapons to ships, droids to personal gear. Of course, one project might hold a Modder's interest more than others, at least for a while. The Modder's talents allow a character to focus heavily on a single project or flit from one exciting upgrade to another at a moment's notice. Whether it's a starship engine or a shiny new blaster, a Modder can probably find a way to make it better.
[P]Modders recieve [B]Gunnery, Mechanics, Piloting (Space)[b] and [B]Streetwise[b] as bonus career skills. If this is the character's starting specialization, the Modder may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]Many teams of renegades and rogues benefit from having a Modder around, as this character can offer a number of unique upgrades to starships and vehicles as well as better access to attachments for  weapons. Modders can certainly be competent pilots and combatants in their own right. Modders who seek out battle in person benefit from a high Agility. With or without an investment in this characteristic though, combat-oriented Modders are most effective when backed up by teams of specialists carrying the souped-up firepower and piloting the uniquely customized ships that only Modders can provide.</Description>
  <Source Page="32">Special Modifications</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>GUNN</Key>
    <Key>MECH</Key>
    <Key>PILOTSP</Key>
    <Key>SW</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>TINK</Key>
        <Key>RESOLVE</Key>
        <Key>KNOWSOM</Key>
        <Key>SIGVEH</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GEARHD</Key>
        <Key>TINK</Key>
        <Key>FANCPAINT</Key>
        <Key>LARGEPROJ</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>RESOURCEREFIT</Key>
        <Key>RESOLVE</Key>
        <Key>LARGEPROJ</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>JURY</Key>
        <Key>HIDD</Key>
        <Key>TINK</Key>
        <Key>GEARHD</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>JURY</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>NATTIN</Key>
        <Key>CUSTLOAD</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>