<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>KV9T9B</Key>
  <Name>KV 9T9-B Wasp</Name>
  <Description>[H3]KV 9T9-B Wasp[h3]
Kelzar-Volvec, a producer of speeder and starship systems headquartered on the Outer Rim world of Temako, has a reputation for producing well-made, sturdy, and woefully bland products that perform well but are otherwise unexciting. Its first foray into the Podracer factory custom market, the 9T9-B Wasp, more that lives up to this reputation for mediocrity. Also known as the Voltec KT9 Wasp amongst serious racing enthusiasts, it is a competent, well-designed racer that is neither the fastest nor the most agile in its class. Aggressively average, this Podracer sits squarely in the middle of its contemporaries, offering a good, solid racer wieht few advanced features at a competitive price. It is powered by a pair of huge KVT Series 400 high-thrust fanjets mounted to a small but well-equpped Podracer cockpit by the usual control cables. The engines provide ample thrust and are equipped with a sophisticated control system that allows the pilot to fine-tune their output on the fly.
[P]Despite its—perhaps unfair—reputation as a staid and boring Podracer for pilots at the end of their career, the 9T9-B does offer one rare and highly sought after feature—its reliability. The Wasp is an amazingly dependable and user friendly Podracer. It is easy to maintain and has a deep and varied aftermarket of perfomance modifications. In addition, the vehicle was designed around a modular hull and can be modified further than most racers in its class. Boring or not, it has a strong and active fan base in the Podracing community, and a number of Wasp-centric racing series have sprung up as a testament to its surprising popularity.</Description>
  <Source Page="57">Endless Vigil</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Podracer</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Land Vehicle</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>4</HP>
  <Price>13450</Price>
  <Rarity>5</Rarity>
  <BaseMods>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>[B]Easy to Maintain[b]: Decrease difficulty of checks to repair or perform maintenance by 1.</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
  </BaseMods>
  <MaxAltitude>40 meters</MaxAltitude>
  <Crew>One pilot</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>2</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>5</Speed>
  <Handling>-1</Handling>
  <HullTrauma>4</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>7</SystemStrain>
  <SinglePilot>true</SinglePilot>
  <SensorRange>Close</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>