<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vehicle xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>SC2MTANK</Key>
  <Name>SC2-M Repulsor Tank</Name>
  <Description>[H3]SC2-M Repulsor Tank[h3]
The Scout-class 2-M Repulsor Tank is a cutting-edge
addition to the Imperial military. This small repulsor
tank is derived from the more established 2-M Saberclass. The Scout-class tank has a very similar silhouette, with a triangular cockpit in a roughly square
chassis, with pointed "wings” swooping forward on
either side. Like its predecessor, the Scout-class is
equipped with a shield generator for unprecedented
beam defense in a ground based craft, but the SC-2M
cuts back on the heavy armament of the Saber-class.
Instead, the Scout-class clears room for a third passenger and a variety of possible advanced sensors,
although none of them come standard in the vehicle.
Its stripped-down weapons loadout still brings a
frightening amount of power to the battleheld. When
firing in salvo mode, its twin blaster cannons can tear
into even heavy targets with a terrifying barrage.
[P]In terms of mission duty, the SC2-M plays a similar role to that of the venerable AT-ST walker, but its
repulsor drive and ray shielding make it a faster and
more aggressive craft, ideal for hit-and-run tactics. It is
resilient against the weapons most troops carry, and
its high maneuverability makes it difficult for heavier
assault craft to pin it down. Despite the various costcutting simplifications unique to the Scout-class, it suffers from the same problems as many other repulsor tanks: long, expensive periods of maintenance in between tours of duty and infamously tempermental electronics systems.</Description>
  <Source Page="60">Forged in Battle</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <Type>Repulsor Tank</Type>
  <Categories>
    <Category>Land Vehicle</Category>
  </Categories>
  <HP>2</HP>
  <Price>65000</Price>
  <Rarity>5</Rarity>
  <Restricted>true</Restricted>
  <BaseMods>
    <Mod>
      <Count>1</Count>
      <MiscDesc>[B][U]Salvo Fire[u][b]: As a maneuver, if the SC2-M's current speed is 0, pilot may prime guns for salvo fire.  Until the vehicle moves, increase the value of the Linked quality of its light blaster cannons to 4.</MiscDesc>
    </Mod>
  </BaseMods>
  <MaxAltitude>3 meters</MaxAltitude>
  <SensorRangeValue>srShort</SensorRangeValue>
  <Crew>One pilot, one gunner</Crew>
  <EncumbranceCapacity>25</EncumbranceCapacity>
  <Passengers>1</Passengers>
  <Silhouette>3</Silhouette>
  <Speed>2</Speed>
  <DefFore>1</DefFore>
  <DefAft>1</DefAft>
  <Armor>1</Armor>
  <HullTrauma>8</HullTrauma>
  <SystemStrain>4</SystemStrain>
  <VehicleWeapons>
    <VehicleWeapon>
      <FiringArcs>
        <Fore>true</Fore>
      </FiringArcs>
      <Location>Forward</Location>
      <Qualities>
        <Quality>
          <Key>LINKED</Key>
          <Count>1</Count>
        </Quality>
      </Qualities>
      <Key>BLASTCANLT</Key>
    </VehicleWeapon>
  </VehicleWeapons>
  <SensorRange>Short</SensorRange>
</Vehicle>