<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>ARBITER</Key>
  <Name>Arbiter</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Arbiter[h4]

An Arbiter knows that often, no matter how hopeless a situation appears, a path to enlightenment and balance can be achieved through perseverance and negotiation. An Arbiter channels the nonviolent tendencies of the Consular into active negotiation between potential allies who have fallen into conflict through misunderstanding or nefarious influences. Through an understanding of sentient nature and the ebb and flow of conflict, an Arbiter can often pave the way for a group in the face of the most violent opposition.
[P]The additional career skills for an Arbiter are [B]Knowledge (Xenology), Lightsaber, Negotiation,[b] and [B]Perception[b]. Characters who select this as their starting specialization may gain one free rank in two of these skills without spending starting experience. The career path of a Consular is a wide and varied one leading in such directions as those of the healer, student, or mystic. The Arbiter has chosen the path of the negotiator and peacemaker, following an innate impulse to seek peace and balance in the heated atmosphere of conflict and confusion. An Arbiter is able to stand between two foes, see to the heart of the conflict bewteen them, and bring calmness and reconciliation to the situation.
[P]Arbiters are born negotiators. Whether fully aware of their Force powers or not, they tend to find themselves following the career paths of diplomats and mediators, seeking to bring peace to the galaxy. Some Consulars work with the Rebel Alliance, finding like-minded societies and bringing them into the Rebel fold or helping them to overcome Imperial pressure. However, many do their work in secret, laboring with a wide variety of corporations, organizations, and other groups to help bring harmony and tranquility to a wartorn galaxy. Arbiters see the ebb and flow of pressures and struggles and instinctively sense the fault lines of thought and belief that perpetuate the violence and conflict bred by miscommunication and misunderstanding. Arbiters seek to bring balance to the galaxy through negotiation and reconciliation.
[P]The Arbiter understands the importance of calmness, respect, and tact while dealing with a diverse array of possible allies and potential enemies. Although many, when confronted with injustice or intransigent negativity, might reach for their lightsaber, an Arbiter's first recourse will always be discussion and negotiation. When the local situation looks completely hopeless, when ancient grudges or new transgressions threaten to tear a system down into violence or chaos, an Arbiter will be able to find a path through the bedlam, to see a course of action that will restore peace and create an environment conducive to the prosperity and contentment of all.
[P]An Arbiter is skilled in acting as the face of a group, providing an interface between the group and the authorities controlling its current area of operation. An Arbiter can assist her group with social interactions, negotiations, and acquisitions, opening doors that less diplomatic characters may find indelibly closed. The Arbiter must at all times keep in mind the greater scope of her duties. Peace is always the ultimate goal, but there is often a bigger picture that must be considered. And when the time for negotiation is at an end, even Consulars must be ready to use more direct means, no matter regretful they may be.</Description>
  <Source Page="22">Disciples of Harmony</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>LTSABER</Key>
    <Key>NEG</Key>
    <Key>PERC</Key>
    <Key>XEN</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SENSDEMO</Key>
        <Key>SAVVYNEG</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>NOBFOOL</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>CONGENIAL</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>REFLECT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SAVVYNEG</Key>
        <Key>NOBFOOL</Key>
        <Key>PARRY</Key>
        <Key>SUNDERIMP</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>CALMAURA</Key>
        <Key>CRUCPOINT</Key>
        <Key>SAVVYNEG</Key>
        <Key>REFLECT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>FORCERAT</Key>
        <Key>SAVVYNEGIMP</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>AGGRNEG</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>