<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>COLOSSUS</Key>
  <Name>Colossus</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Colossus - Indefatigable and Invincible[h4]

Most Warriors pride themselves on their ability to overcome pain. A Colossus, however, possesses a toughness far beyond that. While many fighters wear their scars with pride, an experienced Colossus ripples with scar tissue, the evidence of wounds enough to kill a normal combatant a dozen times over. Where other Warriors might seek to end conflicts quickly and decisively, a Colossus possesses the stamina, endurance, and strength of will to fight through inconceivable pain and punishment, outlasting the foe no matter the odds.
[P]Colossus characters receive [B]Brawl, Discipline, Melee,[b] and [B]Resilience[b], as additional career skills. If this is the character's starting specialization, the player chooses two of these skills and gains one free rank in each, without spending starting experience. These skills allow Colossi to endure great punishment both mentally and physically, and to ensure that they are prepared for even the most taxing situations and battles.
[P]Knowingly or not, Colossi reflect a number of stoic Force traditions that arose throughout history. Some of these beliefs influenced the Jedi Order, particularly in teachings of the primacy of the mental and spiritual over the physical. By accepting the transience of physical pain, a Warrior can rise above it. Some arrive at such a state of mind independently, perhaps realizing (aided by a robust constitution) that physical pain is passing, and only makes them stronger.
[P]Becoming a true Colossus is rarely a matter of formal training, and there is no single path. Few sentients have the physical endurance or the mental reserves for this approach to combat. Those who do might hone their natural abilities through a number of means, likely never quite the same. Being a Colossus may mean transcending their natural physical limitations through meditation and focus, maintaining an internal calm even in the midst of ferocious battle. Others take the opposite approach, drawing on their pain and the negative emotions it evokes to fuel themselves in combat. This latter method is representative of those who tread closer to the dark side.
[P]Although all who fit the mold of a Colossus share certain traits when it comes to defense and longevity, they can take very different approaches to dishing out damage. There is no particular fighting style that defines a Colossus's approach to attacking. Some might heft a heavy blaster. wading heedlessly through enemy fire to unleash a salvo. Others prefer hefty vibro-axes, swords, or other melee weapons, getting up close to enemies and trading blows, confident in their ability to take punishment and give it back in turn. Regardless of their preferred approach, Colossi are sure to have the strength to overcome an opponent with well-placed strikes should the opportunity arise.
[P]Whether by focusing on suffering or by aspiring to higher ideals, a Colossus achieves a preternatural level of physical hardiness and toughness by drawing on the Force. A hardened Force user possesses reserves of willpower to fight on despite agonizing wounds. More importantly, Colossi can allow the Force to flow through them, usng it to achieve impossible feats of endurance. They may be blasted and slashed, but their wounds do not bleed. They walk on broken legs and continue the fight, though it might worsen their injuries. They harness their pain, returning it twice over.</Description>
  <Source Page="24">Knights of Fate</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>BRAWL</Key>
    <Key>DISC</Key>
    <Key>MELEE</Key>
    <Key>RESIL</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>DURA</Key>
        <Key>HARDHD</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>DURA</Key>
        <Key>HARDHD</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>DURA</Key>
        <Key>HEADBUTT</Key>
        <Key>ENDUR</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>UNSTOP</Key>
        <Key>HARDHDIMP</Key>
        <Key>INDWILL</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>TOUGHIMP</Key>
        <Key>HERO</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>POWPAIN</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>