<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<Specialization>
  <Key>DWWAR</Key>
  <Name>Death Watch Warrior</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Death Watch Warrior[h4]
The Death Watch are either fanatics or patriots, depending which side of their blasters one faces. Historical revisionists and a terrorist group to the Republic, the Death Watch believes that the Mandalorians should return to their warrior roots. In order to reclaim their so-called heritage, they allied with the Separatists, performing commando raids and sabotage against the Republic in exchange for political support against the recognized Mandalorian government.
[P]Mandalore's location at the border of the Outer Rim and the inner rims of the galaxy makes Mandalorian Space highly coveted and contested. Historians have debated whether this constant invasion into the Mandalorians' space led to their ancient warrior culture, or if their prime location led them toward dreams of conquest. Regardless, Mandalore has chosen a peaceful path. The Death Watch, however, sees this as a betrayal of both their past and their future.
[P]The Mandalorian Civil War saw the progenitors of the Death Watch exiled to the moon Concordia. The survivors re-formed as the Death Watch, which wants a strong and independent Mandalore ruled by warriors, free from the machinations of the Galactic Republic but also unshackled from the Separatists' idealistic rebellion. First, they must overthrow the current Mandalorian government, whose Republic membership keeps them tied to galactic politics and whose pacifism is an affront to Death Watch militarism. The Death Watch intends to transform Mandalore into a militant culture once more and reclaim its lost territory.
[P]A Death Watch Warrior utilizes hit-and-run tactics and rapid, surgical strikes. Without a true army, the Death Watch cannot hold territory, but it can disrupt, destroy, and raze strategic locations such as communication outposts, power plants, and defense systems. To assist in their lightning attacks, each warrior trains in the use of a jetpack. This helps them to gain higher ground, find cover, and access targets. With time and planning, a warrior can engage in acts of sabotage. To achieve these goals, a Death Watch Warrior receives the following additional career skills: [B]Coercion, Mechanics, Piloting (Planetary)[b] and [B]Ranged (Light)[b].
[P]A Death Watch Warrior also needs to express their aggression at the negotiation table. Compromise breeds weakness. Extortion, strong-arming, and even a little blackmail showcase power and command. The Death Watch doesn't need compromise; it needs victories.
[P]The Death Watch has no disdain for the Mandalorian people, just for their misguided belief in peace. It merely needs to show them the glory of battle and the rewards of taking their birthright. To cleanse the peaceful rot in their society, Death Watch aims to eliminate leaders who cannot change and the Republic that backs them. If the Separatists refuse to give aid - or worse, dictate Mandalore's destiny - then the Death Watch intends to fight the whole galaxy to the end.</Description>
  <Source Page="28">Collapse of the Republic</Source>
  <Custom>AddedItem</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>COERC</Key>
    <Key>MECH</Key>
    <Key>PILOTPL</Key>
    <Key>RANGLT</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>INTIM</Key>
        <Key>CONDITIONED</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>ARM</Key>
        <Key>SIDESTEP</Key>
        <Key>JUMP</Key>
        <Key>JETEXP</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>INTIM</Key>
        <Key>POINTBL</Key>
        <Key>SIDESTEP</Key>
        <Key>POINTBL</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>ARMIMP</Key>
        <Key>CONDITIONED</Key>
        <Key>HITRUN</Key>
        <Key>DTHFRABOVE</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>TOTHEDTH</Key>
        <Key>SIDESTIMP</Key>
        <Key>MOMTUM</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
  <Universal>true</Universal>
</Specialization>
