<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>DROIDTECH</Key>
  <Name>Droid Tech</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Droid Tech - Creating Sentience[h4]
Droids are prevalent across the galaxy, from the shining spheres of the Core to the dingy backwater worlds far from the center's light. To most inhabitants of the galaxy, droids are little more than particularly complex tools. However, some organic sentients find a kinship with these mechanical beings, seeing a spark of life in them beyond their shells and circuitry. Whether or not they treat the droids around them as mere objects or as sentient beings. Droid Techs possess an unparalleled skill at inventing, repairing and dealing with droids.
[P]Technicians who become Droid Techs gain access to a wealth of abilites that make them better at creating, repairing and directing droids. On the edges of society, droids often constitute much of the labor force due to their low cost - and for the same reason, these droids are often poorly maintained. A Droid Tech can keep droids functional and organized better than anyone else, whether this means meticulously performing upgrades and customizations on a trusted droid partner or keeping a team of pit droids working at maximum efficiency. Far from official factories and even from well-stocked garages where replacement parts can be found, a Droid Tech can be incredibly valuable.
[P]Droid Techs recieve [B]Computers, Cool, Mechanics[b] and [B] Leadership[b] as bonus career skills. If this is the character's starting specialization, the Droid Tech may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]Some Droid Techs are not satisified to merely maintain mechanical beings, but actually want to create new, unique droids with unprecedented abilities and features. Custom-built droids are not as common asstandard models, but they are not especially rare, either. The most skilled Droid Techs can bring extremely complex creations to life, building droids that perform a single task with mechanical percision or versatile models capable of handling any situation the galaxy throws at them. The deep philisophical and ethical ramifications of creating sentient being for a purpose weigh heavily on the minds of a few, of course, but most citizens of the galaxy do not dwell too long on such matters.
[P]In addition to having abilities that facilitate building and repairing droids, Droid Techs are gifted with a knack for convincing droids to actually do things for them. While some droids are well mannered and helpful, others can be ill-tempered, capricious, or even downright cruel - but also too useful to dispense with entirely. Getting difficult droids to work toward the group's common good can be quite a task, but a skilled Droid Tech is better equipped for this task than anyone else. To this end, in addition to benefitting from a high Intellect, Droid Techs might also find a high Presence characteristic and ranks in the Leadership skill useful. These have the added benefit of making it easier to deal with organic beings - though some Droid Techs prefer to avoid dealing with organics entirely.</Description>
  <Source Page="30">Special Modifications</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>COMP</Key>
    <Key>COOL</Key>
    <Key>LEAD</Key>
    <Key>MECH</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>MACHMEND</Key>
        <Key>HIDD</Key>
        <Key>SPKBIN</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>DEFTMAKER</Key>
        <Key>EYEDET</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>SPKBIN</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>SPKBINSUP</Key>
        <Key>SPKBINIMP</Key>
        <Key>HIDD</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>REDUNSYS</Key>
        <Key>MACHMEND</Key>
        <Key>SPKBIN</Key>
        <Key>DEFTMAKER</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>EYEDET</Key>
        <Key>REROUTEPROC</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>MACHMEND</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>