<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Specialization>
  <Key>ENFORCER</Key>
  <Name>Enforcer</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Enforcer - Ruthless Thugs[h4]
Enforcers know that achieving results does not always require violence—sometimes the threat of it is enough. Unlike other Hired Guns, Enforcers focus on social interactions as much as combat. They can handle themselves in a fight, to be sure, but prefer to accomplish their objectives through savvy, intimidation, blackmail, and straightforward threats. If they need to fight, however, they can brawl with the best.

[P]Enforcers receive [B]Brawl, Coercion, Knowledge (Underworld),[b] and [B]Streetwise[b] as additional career skills. If this is the character's starting specialization, he may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each, without spending experience. While most Hired Guns focus almost exclusively on combat, Enforcers have a focus in intimidation and both learned and instinctual criminal knowledge. Although they have access to Brawl and other combat skills, for the most part Enforcers are not mindless thugs, but canny operators well-versed in the ins and outs of the criminal underworld. When it comes to navigating this world, few are as knowledgeable or adept as Enforcers. Even when visiting a new planet, Enforcers adapt quickly, picking up instinctively on subtle cues and local slang.

[P]In most criminal organizations, Enforcers fill the dual role of hired muscle and the "face" of a criminal organization. The Enforcer brings a criminal syndicate's message to the streets, then ensures that message is followed (and punishes those who stray). Enforcers should have no trouble finding work, whether on the uncivilized worlds of the Outer Rim or in the shady underworlds of the Core planets. Enforcers are a natural fit for organized crime syndicates, where they collect debts and ensure everyone shows the proper respect and deference to bosses and leaders. Many Enforcers practice a certain subtlety, avoiding police forces while enforcing the rules of gangs and criminal organizations.

[P]While most Enforcers have a fondness for violence, they also display a degree of self-control. Violence is a tool in the Enforcer's arsenal, and not an end in itself. Unlike some Hired Gun characters, an Enforcer is more likely to try words before violence, though these words may be laced with venom and the threat of imminent violence. However, an Enforcer must always be ready to fight.

[P]In a group, Enforcers can fulfill much the same combat role as other Hired Guns, but can also take the lead in negotiations and social interactions. With their Knowledge (Underworld) and Streetwise skills, Enforcers can act as guides when the group delves into the criminal underworld, a realm as dangerous for the unprepared as any natural environment. A savvy Enforcer can actually help the group to avoid unnecessary fights by knowing what to say during tense negotiations with dangerous criminals. Enforcers are more likely to take on a social interaction role than some other Hired Guns, since their skills can be put to use negotiating jobs, finding work, and managing social encounters.</Description>
  <Source Page="26">Dangerous Covenants</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>BRAWL</Key>
    <Key>COERC</Key>
    <Key>UND</Key>
    <Key>SW</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>INTIM</Key>
        <Key>FEARSOME</Key>
        <Key>STRSMART</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>1</Index>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>DURA</Key>
        <Key>STUNBL</Key>
        <Key>NATENF</Key>
        <Key>TALKTALK</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>2</Index>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>INTIM</Key>
        <Key>DEFSTA</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>LOOM</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>3</Index>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SECWIND</Key>
        <Key>STRSMART</Key>
        <Key>WALKWALK</Key>
        <Key>INTIM</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>4</Index>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>FEARSOME</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>BLA</Key>
        <Key>FEARSOME</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>