<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>MARTIALARTIST</Key>
  <Name>Martial Artist</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Martial Artist[h4]
From the Kage Warriors of Quarzite to the enforcers of the Black Sun, organizations and cultures across the galaxy have developed their own unique hand-to-hand combat styles to use their species' phyiology to greatest effect. Over decades, centuries, and millenia, these combat forms become more than mere means of inflicting violence; generations of practitioners work to make them into art fomrs, philosphies, and ways of life. A desire to practice self-defense can become a belief in the value of self-betterment and the innate potential of others, though not all ideologies develop along such lines. More than a few Bounty Hunters have picked up techniques from martial arts styles across  the galaxy to help their hunts. Some are shinging ecamples of their school's philosophies and traditions, but others are disgraced students, or have never even trained formally, earning their skills through hard experience on the battlefield.
[P]In addition to the Bounty Hunter's eight career skills, the Martial Artist recieves [B]Athletics[b], [B]Brawl[b], [B]Coordination[b], and [B]Discipline[b] as bonus career skills. If this is the character's starting specialization, the Martial Artist may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]A Martial Artist benefits first and foremost from a high Brawn rating to empower the Brawl skill. However, Willpower is an extremely useful secondary charactistic, as it not only gives the Martial Artist the higher strain threshold needed to activate the specialization's many talents that use strain as a resource, but also the ability to face intimidating foes up close without flinching. Further, talents like Mind Over Matter benefit from a higher Willpower, and let the Martial Artist fight even longer without becoming exhausted. Finally, the  Martial Artist benefits greatly from investing in the Coordination skill, as talents like Martial Grace and Coordination Dodge let the Martial Artist supplement raw strength with finesse both offensively and defensively.
[P]Unlike characters from most other specializations built around close-quarters combat, Martial Artists does not need a weapon to fight competently. Martial Artists generally value precision over brute strength and strive to execute efficient unarmed strikes. By wasting as little energy as possible, they can deliver extremely forceul blows even when unarmed. This is reflected in talents like Precision Strike, which lets Martial Artists exhaust and weaken foes as they see fit rather than by chance. Martial Artists also seek to leverage their enemies' strength against them in battle with talents like Overbalance, which allows them to throw foes off-balance after they attack. Martial Artists also have access to Parry to mitigate damage, and can even use Parry when unarmed.
[P]This unique combination of precise offense and controlled defense allows Martial Artists to contend with some of the toughest fighters in the galaxy. Of course, not every battle is worth fighting, and a trained Martial Artist knows to assess not only the enemy but also the situation before deciding whether to join the fray. Many schools of martial arts teach the idea that fights are to be avoided, and that the ideal way to win a battle is to avoid having it in the  first place. Unsurprisingly, this attitude is less prevelent amonst Bounty Hunters who wield martial arts as their profession demands a certain amount of violence, but some still apply these over-arching principles to a certain degree.</Description>
  <Source Page="28">No Disintegrations</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>ATHL</Key>
    <Key>BRAWL</Key>
    <Key>COORD</Key>
    <Key>DISC</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>IRONBODY</Key>
        <Key>PARRY</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>PRECSTR</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
        <Direction />
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>PARRY</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>MARTIALGRACE</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>UNARMPARRY</Key>
        <Key>GRAPPLE</Key>
        <Key>IRONBODY</Key>
        <Key>PRECSTRIMP</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>OVERBAL</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>MINDMAT</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>COORDODGE</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>NATBRAW</Key>
        <Key>PRECSTRSUP</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>