<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>RACER</Key>
  <Name>Racer</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Racer - Eyes to the Future[h4]
Racers race. Whether by landspeeder, airspeeder, starship, or on foot, the Racer speeds forward to be the first, and the fastest. However, the Force grants not only extra sensory insight about the race, but also guides Racers to think about what the race means.
[P]Racers recieve [B]Cool[b], [B]Coordination[b], [B]Piloting (Planetary)[b] and [B]Piloting (Space)[b] as additional career skills. Characters who select this as their starting specialization may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]For these characters, racing is less about speed and more about knowing their position in time and space. Racers don't ask how to get somewhere, they intuit their arrival at their destinations. In many ways, they  push to understand the future in relation to the positioning of self. The Force, racing forward in time, in its own way, has carved a path that Racers must follow.
[P]With the Force, physical obstacle aren't obstacles per se. They represent perceptual shadows on the fabric of space time. Racers use the Force to peer into these shadows, seeing not only what exists in the shadow, but also when such interactions exist in the shadow. If they don't exist in the shadow at all, Racers avoid them. They were either never supposed to be there or their life possibly ended before then. If Racers know they don't exist at some point in a  potential future, then they can pick a future in which they do.
[P]As their skills develop, this perception extends from their own relative position to those of other living beings. Racers become predictive not only about their own place in space-time, but also about other beings' places relative to them. This allows Racers an eerie ability to be at the right place at the right time to intercept an individual. Catching a bounty just before the target escapes or rescuing a person in need at just the right time is an incredible benefit to the community. In the wrong hands, this talent can be terrifying, as dark side Force users employ it to talk their target stalking and harassing with a looming presence at every turn.
[P]Obviously, Racers must have a calm demeanor and steady hands, even if the adrenaline rush and excitement of a race would shake the steeliest nerves. Anger can push them to excessive aggression, and fear can lead to hesitation at the wrong moment. Mistakes cost lives, not just for Racers' lives but also those of other pilots, audience members, pit crew and innocent bystanders. Many Racers claim to attain a paradoxical stillness in the middle of a race, achieving a transcendental oneness with vehicle, speed, and self. At this point, the Force flows naturally through them. However, ordinary, practiced skill in piloting a starship or speeder is a must, even Racers can't rely on the Force alone.
[P]Podracing is the first obvious practical application for this specialization. The Racer specialization also can be useful with everything from racing on foot to racing starships. For  Racers, notions of time, space and position become almost meaningless. Racers can be twelve parsecs away from a target but close to interception with a fast hyperdrive, while those on foot may be only a yard away but separated by a high, impssable durasteel wall. Which one of these Racers is closer to the goal?</Description>
  <Source Page="26">Endless Vigil</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>COOL</Key>
    <Key>COORD</Key>
    <Key>PILOTPL</Key>
    <Key>PILOTSP</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>SKILLJOCK</Key>
        <Key>CONDITIONED</Key>
        <Key>SHORTCUT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction />
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SHORTCUT</Key>
        <Key>FULLTH</Key>
        <Key>SHORTCUT</Key>
        <Key>CONDITIONED</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SKILLJOCK</Key>
        <Key>FULLTHIMP</Key>
        <Key>FREERUN</Key>
        <Key>FREERUNIMP</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>FULLTHSUP</Key>
        <Key>FORCERAT</Key>
        <Key>BETTERLUCK</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SUPHUMAN</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>SHORTCUTIMP</Key>
        <Key>INTUITEVA</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>