<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>REPNAVYOFF</Key>
  <Name>Republic Navy Officer</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Republic Navy Officer[h4]
Waging war against the Confederacy or Independent Systems requires the coordination the brightest military minds within the Republic. The clone army is an effective fighting force on the ground, but it is only as effective as the tactical leadership that commands and supports it from orbit. Drawn from the experienced commanders of Republic worlds' various system defense fleets, the naval Officers of the Republic serve as the Grand Army's frontline strategic leadership amid the raging conflict. Even the Jedi rely on the judgment of the officers they fight beside, as they lack the experience necessary to conduct large-scale naval actions or organize troop deployments.

[H4]MILITARY BRILLIANCE[h4]

[P]Victory is a moving target, which makes the task of a Republic Navy Officer immensely difficult. While the Separatists have been building and training their commanders in secret for years, the Republic leadership was largely unprepared for the sudden onset of open conflict.

[P]The Jedi and the Senate are not experienced at waging war, so they have been forced to draw their officers from the isolated defense fleets scattered throughout the Republic, resulting in a  diverse group of military commanders with wildly different skills, training, approaches, and experiences.

[P]Yet, one thing the officers of the Republic Navy share is an excellent tactical and strategic sense. They are as capable of outmaneuvering a single dangerous warship as they are organizing the defense fleet of an entire star system. Having had to outwit pirates often before the war, officers know the spacelanes of the galaxy and can operate amid dangerous obstacles that would slag less experienced navigators.

[P]To represent their training in tactical combat and command, a Republic Navy Officer receives [B]Astrogation, Discipline, Knowledge (Warfare),[b] and [B]Leadership[b] as additional career skills. Regardless of their unique background, a Republic Navy Officer understands war and knows what must be done to achieve victory.

[P]Beyond their military expertise, a naval officer must be a capable leader. Even a brilliant strategy is useless if the spacers carrying it out don't have faith in their ship or fleet, and a talented officer inspires that faith. Whether captaining a single vessel or coordinating the assault of an entire armada, a Republic Navy Officer is a symbol to the crews they command. Clone troopers rely on the ships of the Navy to travel between worlds and reach the battlefield, and the best officers ensure not only victory in orbital battles, but pave the way for a successful ground strike.

[P]In addition to inspiring the clones and other crew who serve under them, many Republic Navy Officers work closely with a Jedi general. Although a non-Jedi officer is officially outranked by their Jedi colleague, the officer's military experience often ensures they serve more as a mentor than a subordinate, and naval strategies are frequently developed by the two working in concert. The Jedi tend to be more at home directing ground engagements or leading starfighter dogfights, leaving the command of the orbital or interplanetary forces to their trusted naval commanders.</Description>
  <Source Page="31">Rise of the Separatists</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>ASTRO</Key>
    <Key>DISC</Key>
    <Key>LEAD</Key>
    <Key>WARF</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>COM</Key>
        <Key>COMMPRES</Key>
        <Key>GALMAP</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction />
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>COM</Key>
        <Key>COMMPRES</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>KNOWSCH</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>ORDSAT</Key>
        <Key>STNERV</Key>
        <Key>CONF</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>FIREREADY</Key>
        <Key>ONORDER</Key>
        <Key>GALMAP</Key>
        <Key>HYPASSAULT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>NATLEAD</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>CAREPLAN</Key>
        <Key>OUTMAN</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
  <Universal>true</Universal>
</Specialization>