<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>SAPPER</Key>
  <Name>Sapper</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Sapper - To Construct and Destroy[h4]
Sappers have a versatile role in the Alliance. These personnel are responsible not only for building encampments, installations, landing areas, and more to support the war against the Empire, but also for seeking out and destroying many of the same that the enemy possesses. This means these combat Engineers must combine stealth, survival skills, and situational awareness to find suitable locations and analyze defensive possibilities, as well as using the same skills to probe for enemy structural weaknesses that can be exploited with suitable explosives.
[P]Sappers receive [B]Athletics, Knowledge (Warfare), Mechanics,[b] and [B]Survival[b] as additional career skills. Characters who select this as their starting specialization may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]Once Sappers find a good location for construction, they must deal with the logistical demands of supplies. Construction efforts mean they have three bosses that will never agree: the environment, the laws of physics, and their commander. Sappers prioritize each differently, and that decision can make or break a construction project. As with most support jobs, when Sappers do an excellent job, no one notices. Alliance soldiers don' t give a second thought to a warm bunk and good lighting in a base, for example, or pilots to a spacious and smooth-floored hangar. If these aren't present, however, Sappers get the blame (and also the overnight repair duties).
[P]Sappers do see battle, perhaps more so than any other support personnel save medics. Command sends Sappers to sneak up to enemy fortifications to find weaknesses and entry points. This work often requires a hands-on inspection of the enemy base, looking for cracks in walls, exposed power lines or sewage pipes, or unattended guard rotations and resupply schedules. A scouting mission requires stealth or a cover identity, and Sappers must avoid capture or death from guards or automated security systems while successfully mapping the enemy's weak points.
[P]Sappers who survive initial scouting missions must then infiltrate enemy sites to set explosive charges, carefully cut away security grids, or perform another act of sabotage, all while avoiding being killed by blaster fire or a mistimed explosive charge. Even if capture or death is unavoidable, Sappers must press on, as the lives of many of their comrades depend on their sacrifice.
[P]After all that, Sappers who survive may still have to pick up a blaster and join the rest of the soldiers in storming the fortification. Perhaps the operation went off without a hitch, and the Alliance has provided evac to carry Sapper teams back to safety. Many refuse to retreat. They can still carry a weapon, and every body counts in battle. In the end, Sappers risk their lives three times over.</Description>
  <Source Page="26">Fully Operational</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>ATHL</Key>
    <Key>MECH</Key>
    <Key>SURV</Key>
    <Key>WARF</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>CONSTSPEC</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>DURA</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>KNOWSCH</Key>
        <Key>CONT</Key>
        <Key>CONSTSPEC</Key>
        <Key>PWRBLST</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>DURA</Key>
        <Key>IMPDEF</Key>
        <Key>PWRBLST</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>UTIL</Key>
        <Key>STRONG</Key>
        <Key>IMPDET</Key>
        <Key>MASGREN</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>WEAKFOUND</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>IMPPOS</Key>
        <Key>MASTDEMO</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>