<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>SENTRY</Key>
  <Name>Sentry</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Sentry - Hunting The Hunters[h4]
Despite the grand legends of the Jedi and their sweeping battles in half-forgotten wars, neighborhoods still need day-to-day protection. Padawans may have dreamt of striking down an evil general or forginf alliances between powerful armies, but  when they became Sentries, they patrolled the streets streets, city blocks, and alleyways to help the overlooked, the common people. These foot soldiers gained none of the glory of their peers, and their thankless tasks have not been preserved in Jedi myths, but their work has benefited countless lives throughout the years.
[P]Sentries gain access to the additional career skills of [B]Coordination[b], [B]Lightsaber[b], [B]Stealth[b] and [B]Vigilance[b]. Characters who select this as ther starting specialization may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]Although both have a lightsaber-focused specialization, Sentries and Shien Experts differ considerably. Whereas Shien Experts approach life and combat as tactical exercises, Sentries concentrate on the immediate and the personal. They reach their targets through speed or subterfuge, stay aware of potential threats, and strike sure and quick.
[P]Sentries are concerned with the present; a crim commited is a violation too far and stopped too late. While other Sentinels concern themselves on the bigger picture, Sentries pick up the pieces in the moment. They catch those who slip through the cracks and are forgotten, and stop those who break through safeguards to do irreparble damage. To Sentries, the details are the real picture, and allowing one person to suffer in order to promote justice is no justice at all.
[P]Perhpas the most personally engaged of the Sentinel speicalists, Sentries defend individuals, whether a specific person they are charged with protecting or a random person walking down the street. During the days of the Jedi Order, Sentries were accused of being too attached to the singular, becoming too emotionally involved with people and losing sight of larger tasks. However, the sentries remained steadfast, channeling grief, anger, and love into pushing themselves to their limits to save their charges, and finding strength in their personal attachments.
[P]Despite their efforts—or perhaps becuase of them—Sentries don't have a glowing repuation for purity. They revel in their repuation, utilizing fear and surpise against their opponents. Sentries can only maintain this reputation among their adversaties if their communites fear them as well. They must become the monster who the monsters fear.
[P]The Force guides Sentries to be in the right place at the right time to prevent violence. They move unseen, somtimes on rooftops to get a higher perspective, sometimes in the shadows to get an up-close point of view. Their senses expand as Sentries search for an oppurtunity, an opening, to get the jump on evil.
[P]Once engaged in combat, their priorities change. After slipping out of the shadows or dropping down from above, sentries operate visibly and engourage their enemies to target them. Sentries want to be the most intimidating and to be the most dangerous-looking so that their enemies will fear them and fight them rather than their charges. Their talents lie not in ending a fight quickly or attacking directly though. Sentries work best when surprising opponents, removing them one by one and giving the rest a chane to run away or surrender in this way. This lets Sentries use the negative emotions of fear and anger to disorient their opponents.</Description>
  <Source Page="28">Endless Vigil</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>COORD</Key>
    <Key>LTSABER</Key>
    <Key>STEAL</Key>
    <Key>VIGIL</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>REFLECT</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>CONDITIONED</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>UNCANREAC</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>REFLECT</Key>
        <Key>UNCANREAC</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SLEIGHTMIND</Key>
        <Key>SABERTHROWIMP</Key>
        <Key>SABERTHROW</Key>
        <Key>IMPOSFALL</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>DODGE</Key>
        <Key>FEARSHAD</Key>
        <Key>CONSTVIGIL</Key>
        <Key>SLEIGHTMIND</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>FORCERAT</Key>
        <Key>REFLECTIMP</Key>
        <Key>DODGE</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>