<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>WARDEN</Key>
  <Name>Warden</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Warden - The Daunting Defender[h4]
Whether they wield the power of the Force consciously or not, Wardens know that they have been gifted with power. But more importantly, they know that they must wield this might to perform a necessary duty, subduing those who would abuse that same power to harm the Warden's friends and allies. While Guardians of all stripes might be driven by a desire to create a fairer world, the concept of justice is especially important to Wardens. The job of punishing the wicked is frequently a thankless one, especially in the era of the Empire, when the ruling regime is so deeply corrupt. Many Wardens see this burden as inevitable; after all, it is their role to make sure evil is stripped of the means to threaten their chosen allies, not to be loved for these efforts.
[P]The Warden is unique among Guardian specializations in being focused specifically on weakening enemies rather than just bolstering allies. In some ways, this specialization is the mirror image of the Aggressor. Both wield fear as a weapon, but the Warden uses dread to weaken foes' strikes rather than make them more vulnerable to attacks, and relies on counterattacking instead of striking first. What a Warden lacks in raw toughness as compared to a Protector or Armorer, this unique Guardian makes up for with the ability to control foes options by restricting their movement, inflicting strain upon them and intimidating them into submission.
[P]To assist in their task of identifying and subduing threats to their allies, Wardens have [B]Brawl, Coercion, Discipline and Knowledge (Underworld)[b] as additional career skills. If this is the characters stating specialization, he may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]Wardens are suited to taking major roles on and off the battlefield, thanks to their specialization's focus on Coercion. While using intimidation as a primary social tool can have consequences for the character's morality, many unnecessary fights can be avoided if potential foes are too afraid to draw weapons against a Warden. In battle, Wardens shine in close quarters, where foes must approach to attack and thus suffer the consequences of engaging such frightening enemies. Wardens do what is needed to give their allies the best chance of survival in a harsh galaxy, and if this includes some unsavory tasks, so be it.
</Description>
  <Source Page="26">Keeping the Peace</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>BRAWL</Key>
    <Key>COERC</Key>
    <Key>DISC</Key>
    <Key>UND</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>INTIM</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>PRECSTR</Key>
        <Key>CONF</Key>
        <Key>SCATH</Key>
        <Key>BADCOP</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SENSEADV</Key>
        <Key>CONF</Key>
        <Key>FEARSOME</Key>
        <Key>NOESC</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>OVERBAL</Key>
        <Key>BALEGAZE</Key>
        <Key>BADCOP</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRAPPLE</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>FORCERAT</Key>
        <Key>FEARSOME</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
  <Universal>false</Universal>
</Specialization>