<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>WARLEADER</Key>
  <Name>Warleader</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Warleader - The Shrewd Leader[h4]
Not all Guardians solve their problems through feats of prowess with the lightsaber alone. The mind can be a deadlier weapon still, and a little foresight can do as much to win a battle as the greatest feat of heroism. The Warleader possesses a number of tricks and abilities that help to carry the day in battle, and more importantly, to keep friends and allies alive to fight another day.
[P]Warleaders are calculating fighters who rely more on mental acuity and guile tan on raw combat strength. While Warleaders are capable combatants in their own right, thanks to their ranged combat skills, their greatest edge comes when they have comrades in arms to guide in battle. Unlike Peacekeepers, Warleaders do not focus on inspiring others; while individual Warleaders might indeed be charismatic, their friends trust them with their lives not because of rousing speeches, but because of their reliability in the field.
[P]Warleaders might not protect their allies by deftly deflecting blaster shots with  lightsaber or heroically taking blows meant for them, but their guidance can keep comrades safe just the same. Warleaders acquire [B]Leadership, Perception, Ranged (Light) and Survival[b] as additional career skills, all of which assist them in negotiation on the battlefield and guiding their allies across it. If this is the character's starting specialization, he may chose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]Whether through formal military training, practical combat experience or simply having keen minds, PC's who take on this specialization are well-equipped to handle matters of strategy and tactics. Warleaders often have an intuitive grasp of the field of combat thanks to their connection to the Force, and combine this with shrewd tactics to concoct and execute forward-thinking plans that seem almost prescient to their foes. Cover is an especially valuable resource for Warleaders. They can use it not only to grant their comrades additional defensive benefits, but also to gain the edge over enemies by guiding allies to strike them from unexpected angles.
[P]Trust is the foundation of any Warleader's command. More often than not in [B]Force and Destiny[b], a party of Player Characters consists of a group of equals pursuing a common goal rather than a formally structured organization. Even if one PC is nominally in charge, that person might or might not be the Warleader. When battle breaks out, however, the Warleader keeps friends out of the line of fire, exposes weaknesses in enemy plans, and comes up with cunning strategies  that catch foes off guard.
[P]Outside of battle, the Warleader's acute problem-solving skills can also be very useful, as can the character's foresight. Regardless of the situation, the Warleader can look at challenges from an angle others might have neglected. In doing so, the Warleader can help lead the group to victory through unexpected solutions.</Description>
  <Source Page="28">Keeping the Peace</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>LEAD</Key>
    <Key>PERC</Key>
    <Key>RANGLT</Key>
    <Key>SURV</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>PRIMEPOS</Key>
        <Key>SUPPRFIRE</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>UNCANSENS</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>CAREPLAN</Key>
        <Key>SENSDANG</Key>
        <Key>SWIFT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SUPPRFIRE</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>UNCANSENS</Key>
        <Key>PRESSHOT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>COORDASS</Key>
        <Key>PRIMEPOS</Key>
        <Key>BLINDSPOT</Key>
        <Key>FOREWARN</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>CLEVERSOLN</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>FORCERAT</Key>
        <Key>PROPAIM</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
  <Universal>false</Universal>
</Specialization>