<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>ARMORER</Key>
  <Name>Armorer</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Armorer - The Smith[h4]
Armorers are defined by their ability to survive through a combination of ingenuity and stubbornness. While Protectors draw directly on the Force to avoid harm and Soresu Defenders use lightsabers to deflect incoming strikes, Armorers build a better defense, reinforcing solidly built equipment with the inestimable power of the Force.
[P]Armorers gain [B]Knowledge (Outer Rim), Lightsaber, Mechanics,  and Resilience[b] as additional career skills. These skills help Armorers in getting the tools they need for the job, maintaining and using those implements efficiently, and surviving to do it all again. If this is the character's starting specialization, he may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]Armorers wield a number of talents that enhance their own armor and defenses, letting them survive hits that would fell most of their allies. They are extremely skilled craftspeople, and not only can build and modify their own gear proficiently, but can also use the Force to bolster their handiwork. With sufficient training, Armorers can imbue their armor with the power of the Force, allowing it to repel blows from lightsabers.
[P]Thanks to their sturdy defenses, Armorers often favor close-quarters combat, trusting their protection to see them through to melee range. Though lightsabers are practically legendary in this era of oppression, some Armorers manage to acquire the kyber crystals necessary to forge these weapons. The most skilled Armorers can even use their innate knowledge of the Force to unlock unseen potential in more mundane items, bringing out qualities that others have overlooked. This mystical ability, combined with an Armorer's natural resourcefulness, means that catching an Armorer unarmed and unready grants only a minimal advantage.
[P]Though they certainly benefit from having a fully stocked machine shop available, Armorers can also do most of their work on the battlefield, scrounging and retrofitting the supplies they need. This flexibility can be a substantial advantage in [B]Force and Destiny[b], for the Empire hounds every step that Force users take, and they must be able to adapt to shifting circumstances and surroundings. If a vessel needs repairing behind enemy lines or a hull breach must be sealed during a firefight, an Armorer is often the best sentient being for the job.
[P]Outside of combat, Armorers can be extremely helpful to their allies. In addition to possessing considerable skill at modifying equipment, they can repair vehicles and other machines that the group needs kept in working order. While Artisans have the edge in refined skill with technology and the deep research into matters involving machines, Armorers can get the job done, and do it under enemy fire.</Description>
  <Source Page="24">Keeping the Peace</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>LTSABER</Key>
    <Key>MECH</Key>
    <Key>OUT</Key>
    <Key>RESIL</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>GEARHD</Key>
        <Key>INVENT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SABERTHROW</Key>
        <Key>ARM</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>GEARHD</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>ARMIMP</Key>
        <Key>INVENT</Key>
        <Key>MENTTOOLS</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>COMPTECH</Key>
        <Key>TINK</Key>
        <Key>FALLAVAL</Key>
        <Key>ARMSUP</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Index>0</Index>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>FORCERAT</Key>
        <Key>IMBUEITEM</Key>
        <Key>REINITEM</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>false</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>false</Left>
          <Right>false</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>false</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
  <Universal>false</Universal>
</Specialization>