<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>CLONEPIL</Key>
  <Name>Clone Pilot</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Clone Pilot[h4]
Interplanetary conflict inevitably brings battles to the upper atmosphere and the void of space. Capital ships play a prominent role in these battles, but large wings of starfighters are a vital part of every conflict. These specialized ships exploit their smaller profile and variations in armament to avoid detection while occupying a variety of roles. Military transports deploy from capital ships—often through active war zones in the company of starfighter screens—to deliver troops and equipment to a planet’s surface, where clones can engage the enemy.

[P]Every Clone Soldier has the rudimentary knowledge required to pilot repulsorlift vehicles, walkers, and starfighters. However, basic skills alone are inadequate for success in a combat environment. To address this, some Clone Soldiers receive additional training in the Clone Pilot specialization and are inducted into the Republic Navy branch of the Grand Army of the Republic.

[P]Clone Pilots receive [B]Gunnery, Mechanics, Piloting (Planetary),[b] and [B]Piloting (Space)[b] as additional career skills. Characters who select this as their starting specialization may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience. A degree or familiarity with these skills is vital for any Clone Soldier to survive as a starfighter pilot. While any battlefield is profoundly dangerous, the vacuum of space adds significant risks that are not present during typical planetary conflicts. Additional training mitigates some of those dangers but can never completely eliminate them.

[P]Clone Pilots serve as members or a squadron under the command of a Clone Officer, who has also mastered the skills of a pilot. A squadron is typically assigned a particular type of craft, although this can change based on mission requirements. Clone Pilots are sometimes reassigned to other squadrons in which they are expected to fly other craft. Consequently, their training includes exposure to a range of starfighters, speeders, and walkers. Typical starfighter assignments include the Republic Z-95 Headhunter starfighter, the V-19 Torrent starfighter, and the ARC-170 starfighter. Those Clone Pilots assigned to transport duty typically fly Low Altitude Assault Transports (LAATs) or [I]Nu[i]-class attack shuttles. Collectively, these spacecraft represent the core of the Republic Navy's smaller craft.

[P]Some Clone Pilots are assigned to operate vehicles that work more closely with ground units. These include AT-RT and AT-TE walkers, and BARC speeders, among others. Notably, these craft are not normally under the oversight of the Republic Navy branch of the GAR. As such, Clone Pilots assigned to them do not fall under the oversight of the naval chain of command, leaving them far less likely to pilot starfighters.
</Description>
  <Source Page="22">Rise of the Separatists</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>GUNN</Key>
    <Key>MECH</Key>
    <Key>PILOTPL</Key>
    <Key>PILOTSP</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>LETSRIDE</Key>
        <Key>FIRESUP</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>HIGHGTRAIN</Key>
        <Key>CLANKILL</Key>
        <Key>HIGHGTRAIN</Key>
        <Key>SKILLJOCK</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>ASSAULTDR</Key>
        <Key>TRICK</Key>
        <Key>FULLTH</Key>
        <Key>BARREL</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>FIRESUP</Key>
        <Key>NATOP</Key>
        <Key>BARRELIMP</Key>
        <Key>BARRELSUP</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>MISSCRIT</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
        <Key>MASPIL</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>