<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>CYBERTECH</Key>
  <Name>Cyber Tech</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Cyber Tech - Self-Improvement At Any Cost [h4]
Many people think of the body as a machine. After all, it can fulfill complex functions, must be maintained, and wears down over time. When pieces of the body fail or need to be repaired, cyberneticists can help resore funtion and improve the quality of patients' lives. While Cyber Techs focus thier craft entirely on replacing the lost or damaged body parts of  patients, others seen no reason not to upgrade and modify bodies as they would other tools.
[P]The Cyber Tech specialization gives a Technician a way to explore the realm of medicine, using technical and biological know how to craft and maintain cybernetics, as well as to integrate them into living bodies. Given this ability to skillfully alter their bodies with cybernetics, most Cyber Techs perform at lease some upgrades on themselves. The degree and subtlety of an individual's Cyber Tech's upgrades tend to depend on the individual's culture, species and personal beliefs. Within some cultures, extensive cybernetic augmentation is considered unusual or even taboo.
[P]In addition to the Technician's eight career skills, the Cyber Tech receives [B]Athletics, Cybernetics, Mechanics, Medicine[b] and [B]Vigilance[b] as bonus career skills. If this is the  character's starting specialization, the Cyber Tech may choose two of these skills and gain one free rank in each without spending starting experience.
[P]Despite the advantages of cybernetics, which many Cyber Tech are quick to point out, most humans and members of many other species tend not to seek out substantial enhancment unless absolutely necessary. Replacing a lost limb with a cybernetic one is common sense, but for most, the prospect of lopping off a healthy limb to replace it with a stronger one is another matter entirely. Still, among most sentient species with the necessary technology, there are those who have reasons for wanting to surpass flesh.
[P]Other groups and individuals hold no such qualms about removing flesh, bones and organs to replace them with what Cyber Techs see as undoubtably superior components. Ganks, for instance, are a species known for their heavy use of cybernetic augmentation: completely unmodified Gank are very rare. Droids, of course have a special relationship with artificial limbs, and most droids desire periodic part replacements for maintenance.
[P]A Cyber Tech can take on extra cybernetics and can improve augmentations far beyond their normal capacities. Further, a Cyber Tech can assist comrades with medical care and by replacing body parts with cybernetics, though most beings only accept this help after losing a body part - no matter how fervently the Cyber Tech speaks to the virtues of replacing squishy unreliable flesh and organs with cold, sturdy steel.</Description>
  <Source Page="28">Special Modifications</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>ATHL</Key>
    <Key>MECH</Key>
    <Key>MED</Key>
    <Key>VIGIL</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>CYBERNETICIST</Key>
        <Key>MOREMACH</Key>
        <Key>ENGREDUN</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>EYEDET</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
        <Key>ENERGTRANS</Key>
        <Key>CYBERNETICIST</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>OVERCHARGE</Key>
        <Key>MOREMACH</Key>
        <Key>DURA</Key>
        <Key>SURG</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>OVERCHARGEIMP</Key>
        <Key>UTIL</Key>
        <Key>MOREMACH</Key>
        <Key>SURG</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>MOREMACH</Key>
        <Key>DURA</Key>
        <Key>OVERCHARGESUP</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>