<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>NAVIGATOR</Key>
  <Name>Navigator</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Navigator - Guiding to Safety[h4]
Seekers are often at the forefront of exploration, pushing back the edges of the unknown across planets and systens throughout the galaxy. Most view the mission itself as more important than the plotting needed to undertake it, and determining its best method and route unimportant when compared to what awaits at the destination. Others, though, see these as perhaps at least as important, and certainly more personally rewarding. Navigators represent those Seekers who devote themselves fully to these aspects from charting hyperspace passages or plotting overland routes. No matter the enviornment, none can match Navigators when they set about deciding a course. When Navigators use the Force their abilities might even appear more reliant on fantastic luck than skill to the uninitiated.
[P]Navigators are often excellent pilots as well, but these Seekers are generally more interested in the best way for their vehicle to arrive safely an expeditiously than in its firepower or maneuverability. Some of these individuals may have spent their enitre lives in space, moving from ship to ship or working one specific area filled with hazardous asteroids or nests of black holes. Most travel extensively, regardless of their origins, always seeking out new uncharted regions in need of their abilites.
[P]Navigators recieve [B]Astrogation[b], [B]Knowledge (Outer Rim)[b], [B]Perception[b] and [B]Survival[b] as additional career skills, representing their skills at locating and mapping out pathways, both planetary and stellar. Characters who select this as their starting specialization may choose two of these skills and gin one free rank in each without spending starting experience. The addition of Astrogation allows Navigators to truly excel in outer space, where they can help ensure the group arrives speedily and accurately to distant star systems.
[P]Navigators are also excellent on planets, charting routes over sea, land, and air, as well as even orbital voyages. Their skills are especially critical on uncharted worlds, but they are  also valuable in urban settings, which can be as unfathomable as any dense jungle or endless steppe. When the PCs need to find the fastest, safest, or least conspicuous way to reach their destination, Navigators are whome they turn to invaluable in chases, whether the PCs are trying to run down their quarry or escape pusuit, Navigators can give a group the edge it needs by locating the most efficient route.
[P]Navigators are often driven to find such routes on their own, and might become irritated when inferior passages are used. Not resting until the best path is discovered and followed, they soon become bored when success is achieved, as there is no challenge in following an established route. For some Navigators, this is a never-ending quest, and they are always seeking to shave just one light year from a hyperspace lane, or an hour from a city crossing, somethingn that can always happen as they become more proficient with the Forc. The Force can also allow them to offer guidance of a less tactical and more spiritual nature at times as well, something that can also aid the PCs in their adventures.</Description>
  <Source Page="28">Savage Spirits</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>ASTRO</Key>
    <Key>OUT</Key>
    <Key>PERC</Key>
    <Key>SURV</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>STUDPLOT</Key>
        <Key>EXTRACK</Key>
        <Key>SHORTCUT</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GALMAP</Key>
        <Key>SHORTCUTIMP</Key>
        <Key>PLANMAP</Key>
        <Key>PREEMAVOID</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SHORTCUT</Key>
        <Key>SWIFT</Key>
        <Key>UNCANSENS</Key>
        <Key>TOUGH</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GALMAP</Key>
        <Key>HOLNAV</Key>
        <Key>FORCERAT</Key>
        <Key>PLANMAP</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>ONEUNI</Key>
        <Key>INTUITNAV</Key>
        <Key>MASSTAR</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>