<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Specialization xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Key>PROPHET</Key>
  <Name>Prophet</Name>
  <Description>[H4]Prophet - A Cantor for a Choir[h4]
The Jedi Order's proselytizing ebbed and flowed, much as the Force did throughout the Old Republic. Understanding of the Force couldn't be pressured upon a student without causing resentment and anger, which promises a fall toward the dark side. So for Prophets, they proselytized not to convert, but to offer a voice of hope and an opportunity to learn about the power of the Force.
[P]Now, with the Jedi Order destroyed and the Galactic Republic shattered, Prophets carry a fervor not seen before in the history of the galaxy. To them, their knowledge of the light side of the Force reflects the struggle against the dark. If the Galactic Empire is the shadow blotting out the stars, then Prophets are single points of light, hoping to ignite a candle here and there to light up the sky.
[P]Prophets gain the following additional career skills: [B]Charm, Coercion, Deception,[b] and [B]Leadership[b]. Characters who start with this specialization first get one rank in two of these skills without spending experience.
[P]Like Advisors, this specialization directly interacts with people, granting them insight and counsel when needed. Unlike Advisors, Prophets address the crowd, not the individual. Their message has to reach as many ears as possible, in the hope that their ideas or warnings catch fire. Prophets influence communities, cities, or even planets if given a medium and a message.
[P]The medium comes in a variety of forms: a sermon on a soapbox or an altar, a HoloNet posting or recording, flyers or tracts passed from hand to claw, or even images on a poster, painting, or pirate transmission. It doesn't matter what medium, only the passion and truth of the message.
[P]The message might be filtered through a religious lens, but not always. Prophets are keyed into the Cosmic Force more keenly, and images of the future provide wisdom, guidance, and, for followers, an identity. Since Prophets are only mortal, they can only try to interpret with mortal concepts and metaphors. They then have to translate that message into simple language, further diluting the content. The next person's limited understanding then further alters that message. The real question is whether this constant alteration by verbal or visual transmission distorts the message or enhances it just as the Force intended.
[P]Prophets who use their abilities for evil or selfish ends have an easier time now during the Galactic Civil War. Those suffering from the Empire's rule want a voice of hope to give them a reason to live on, and as long as the message doesn't violate Imperial restrictions on religion or political sedition, Prophets can enjoy a safe (and profitable) career. Even on planets free from the Empire, other sources of oppression (slavery, Hutt influence, corporate interests, and the like) may drive people to a religious charlatan, especially one who can produce miracles.
[P]Even well-meaning Prophets should be wary, since it is much too easy for them to insert their own desires, needs, or fears into their visions, distorting them into their own ends, manipulating their followers into believing their own egos.</Description>
  <Source Page="30">Unlimited Power</Source>
  <Custom>DescOnly</Custom>
  <CareerSkills>
    <Key>CHARM</Key>
    <Key>COERC</Key>
    <Key>DECEP</Key>
    <Key>LEAD</Key>
  </CareerSkills>
  <TalentRows>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>5</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>OVERWAURA</Key>
        <Key>RAPREC</Key>
        <Key>CONGENIAL</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction />
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>10</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>SCATH</Key>
        <Key>PLAUSDEN</Key>
        <Key>INSPRHET</Key>
        <Key>RAPREC</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>15</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>RAPREC</Key>
        <Key>OVERWAURA</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>TWISTWORD</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>20</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>FEARSOME</Key>
        <Key>GRIT</Key>
        <Key>INSPRHETIMP</Key>
        <Key>CONGENIAL</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Down>true</Down>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
    <TalentRow>
      <Cost>25</Cost>
      <Talents>
        <Key>OVERWAURAIMP</Key>
        <Key>FORCERAT</Key>
        <Key>FONTPOW</Key>
        <Key>DEDI</Key>
      </Talents>
      <Directions>
        <Direction>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
          <Right>true</Right>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Left>true</Left>
        </Direction>
        <Direction>
          <Up>true</Up>
        </Direction>
      </Directions>
    </TalentRow>
  </TalentRows>
</Specialization>